<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="el|en|it|hy|cs|et|az|es|ru|nl|pt|tr|li|lt|pl|bg|uk|hu|bs|fi|he|ka|nn|sr|sv|sk|ku"><quote id="0" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"Understand this, I mean to arrive at the truth. The truth, however ugly in itself, is always curious and beautiful to seekers after it."</quote><quote id="1" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"Crime is terribly revealing. Try and vary your methods as you will, your tastes, your habits, your attitude of mind, and your soul is revealed by your actions."</quote><quote id="2" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"I have given them life instead of death, freedom instead of the cords of superstition, beauty and truth instead of corruption and exploitation." The old bad days are over for them, the Light of the Aton has risen, and they can dwell in peace and harmony freed from the shadow of fear and oppression.</quote><quote id="3" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">An archaeologist is the best husband any woman can have; the older she gets, the more interested he is in her.</quote><quote id="4" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">Oh dear, I never realized what a terrible lot of explaining one has to do in a murder!</quote><quote id="5" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">I specialize in murders of quiet, domestic interest.</quote><quote id="6" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">It is ridiculous to set a detective story in New York City. New York City is itself a detective story.</quote><quote id="7" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">I have a certain experience of the way people tell lies.</quote><quote id="8" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">The intense interest aroused in the public by what was known at the time as "The Styles Case" has now somewhat subsided. Nevertheless, in view of the world-wide notoriety which attended it, I have been asked, both by my friend Poirot and the family themselves, to write an account of the whole story. This, we trust, will effectually silence the sensational rumours which still persist.</quote><quote id="9" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">Every murderer is probably somebody’s old friend.</quote><quote id="10" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"I am not keeping back facts. Every fact that I know is in your possession. You can draw your own deductions from them."</quote><quote id="11" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"This affair must all be unravelled from within." He tapped his forehead. "These little grey cells. It is 'up to them' — as you say over here."</quote><quote id="12" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"I did not deceive you, mon ami. At most, I permitted you to deceive yourself."</quote><quote id="13" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"&lt;i&gt;Eh bien&lt;/i&gt;, Mademoiselle, all through my life I have observed one thing — 'All one wants one gets!' Who knows?" His face screwed itself up comically. "You may get more than you bargain for." </quote><quote id="14" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">I do not argue with obstinate men. I act in spite of them.</quote><quote id="15" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">“You have been to the Riviera before, Georges?” said Poirot to his valet the following morning. 
George was an intensely English, rather wooden-faced individual. 
“Yes, sir. I was here two years ago when I was in the service of Lord Edward Frampton.” 
“And to-day,” murmured his master, “you are here with Hercule Poirot. How one mounts in the world!”</quote><quote id="16" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">Men are foolish, are they not, Mademoiselle? To eat, to drink, to breathe the good air, it is a very pleasant thing, Mademoiselle. One is foolish to leave all that simply because one has no money — or because the heart aches. &lt;i&gt;L´amour&lt;/i&gt;, it causes many fatalities, does it not?</quote><quote id="17" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">I was wrong about that young man of yours. A man when he is making up to anybody can be cordial and gallant and full of little attentions and altogether charming. But when a man is really in love he can't help looking like a sheep. Now, whenever that young man looked at you he looked like a sheep. I take back all I said this morning. It is genuine.</quote><quote id="18" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"I saw a particular personage and I threatened him — yes, Mademoiselle, I, Hercule Poirot, threatened him."
"With the police?"
"No," said Poirot drily, "With the Press — a much more deadly weapon."</quote><quote id="19" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"Life is like a train Mademoiselle. It goes on. And it is a good thing that that is so."
"Why?"
"Because the train gets to its journey's end at last, and there is a proverb about that in your language, Mademoiselle."
"'Journeys end in lovers meeting'" Lenox laughed. "That is not going to be true for me."
"Yes — yes, it is true. You are young, younger than you yourself know. Trust the train Mademoiselle, for it is &lt;i&gt;le bon  Dieu&lt;/i&gt; who drives it."</quote><quote id="20" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"I like to inquire into everything. Hercule Poirot is a good dog." The good dog follows the scent, and if, regrettably, there is no scent to follow, he noses around — seeking always something that is not very nice.</quote><quote id="21" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"The impossible could not have happened, therefore the impossible must be possible in spite of appearances."</quote><quote id="22" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"Exactly! It is absurd — improbable — it cannot be. So I myself have said. And yet, my friend, "there it is!" one cannot escape from the facts."</quote><quote id="23" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">I don't pretend to be an author or to know anything about writing. I'm doing this simply because Dr Reilly asked me to, and somehow when Dr Reilly asks you to do a thing you don't like to refuse.</quote><quote id="24" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"That was the worst of Dr Reilly. You never knew whether he was joking or not. He always said things in the same slow melancholy way — but half the time there was a twinkle underneath it."</quote><quote id="25" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"Believe me, nurse, the difficulty of beginning will be nothing to the difficulty of knowing how to stop." At least that's the way it is with me when I have to make a speech. Someone's got to catch hold of my coat-tails and pull me down by main force.</quote><quote id="26" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"God bless my soul, woman, the more personal you are the better! This is a story of human beings — not dummies! Be personal — be prejudiced — be catty — be anything you please! Write the thing your own way. We can always prune out the bits that are libellous afterwards! "</quote><quote id="27" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">I don't think I shall ever forget my first sight of Hercule Poirot. Of course, I got used to him later on, but to begin with it was a shock, and I think everyone else must have felt the same! I don't know what I'd imagined — something like Sherlock Holmes — [...] Of course, I knew he was a foreigner, but I hadn't expected him to be "quite" as foreign as he was, if you know what I mean. When you saw him you just wanted to laugh! He was like something on the stage or at the pictures. [...] He looked like a hairdresser in a comic play!</quote><quote id="28" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">i felt that the murderer was in the room. Sitting with us-listening. "one of us"</quote><quote id="29" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">Because, Renisenb, it is so easy and it costs so little labour to write down ten bushels of barley, or a hundred head of cattle, or ten fields of spelt - and the thing that is written will come to seem like the real thing, and so the writer and the scribe will come to despise the man who ploughs the fields and reaps the barley and raises the cattle - but all the same the fields and the cattle are &lt;i&gt;real&lt;/i&gt; - they are not just marks of inks on papyrus. And when all the records and all the papyrus rolls are destroyed and the scribes are scattered, the men who toil and reap will go on, and Egypt will still live.</quote><quote id="30" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"You know that in all tombs there is always a false door?"
Renisenb stared. "Yes, of course."
"Well, people are like that too. They create a false door - to deceive. If they are conscious of weakness, of inefficiency, they make an imposing door of self-assertion, of bluster, of overwhelming authority - and, after a time, they get to believe in it themselves. They think, and everybody thinks, that they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; like that. But behind that door, Renisenb, is a bare rock ... And so when reality comes and touches them with the feather of truth - their true self reasserts itself."</quote><quote id="31" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"It is the kind of thing that happens to you when you are stupid," said Esa. "Things go entirely differently from the way you planned them."</quote><quote id="32" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">I must have a talk with you, David, and learn all the new ideas. As far as I can see, one must hate everybody but at the same time give them free medical attention and a lot of extra education, poor things! All those helpless little children herded into schoolhouses every day—and cod liver oil forced down babies’ throats whether they like it or not—such nasty-smelling stuff.</quote><quote id="33" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">John, forgive me... for what I can't help doing.</quote><quote id="34" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">And if you cast down an idol, there's nothing left. </quote><quote id="35" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">What any woman saw in some particular man was beyond the comprehension of the average intelligent male. It just was so. A woman who could be intelligent about everything else in the world could be a complete fool when it came to some particular man. </quote><quote id="36" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">Any medical man who predicts exactly when a patient will die, or exactly how long he will live, is bound to make a fool of himself. The human factor is always incalculable. The weak have often unexpected powers of resistance, the strong sometimes succumb.</quote><quote id="37" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">There were to be no short cuts to the truth. Instead he would have to adopt a longer, but a reasonably sure method. There would have to be conversation. Much conversation. "For in the long run, either through a lie, or through truth, people were bound to give themselves away..."</quote><quote id="38" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">How averse human beings were ever to admit ignorance!</quote><quote id="39" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">Men always tell such silly lies.</quote><quote id="40" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">It shows you, Madame, the dangers of conversation. It is a profound belief of mine that if you can induce a person to talk to you for long enough, on any subject whatever, sooner or later they will give themselves away.</quote><quote id="41" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"I can imagine anything! That's the trouble with me. I can imagine things now — this minute. I could even make them sound all right, but of course none of them would be true."</quote><quote id="42" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">It would be difficult Bland thought, to forget Hercule Poirot, and this not entirely for complimentary reasons.</quote><quote id="43" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">Who is there who has not felt a sudden startled pang at reliving an old experience or feeling an old emotion?</quote><quote id="44" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">This, Hastings, will be my last case. It will be, too, my most interesting case — and my most interesting criminal.</quote><quote id="45" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"I have no more now to say. I do not know, Hastings, if what I have done is justified or not justified. No — I do not know. I do not believe that a man should take the law into his own hands...  But on the other hand, I "am" the law! "As a young man in the Belgian police force I shot down a desperate criminal who sat on a roof and fired at people below." In a state of emergency martial law is proclaimed."</quote><quote id="46" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"I have always been so sure — too sure... But now I am very humble and I say like a little child: "I do not know..." "~ Hercule Poirot</quote><quote id="47" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"I don't think necessity is the mother of invention — invention, in my opinion, arises directly from idleness, possibly also from laziness. To save oneself trouble."</quote><quote id="48" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">The best time to plan a book is while you are doing the dishes.</quote><quote id="49" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">[http://www.agathachristie.com/ Official Agatha Christie site]</quote><quote id="50" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">[http://www.kirjasto.sci.fi/christie.htm Brief biography] at Kirjasto (Pegasos)</quote><quote id="51" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"[http://www.gutenberg.net/etext/863 The Mysterious Affair at Styles]" at Project Gutenberg</quote><quote id="52" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">"[http://www.gutenberg.net/etext/1155 The Secret Adversary]" at Project Gutenberg</quote><quote id="53" author="Agatha Christie" cats="1970s deaths|Detective fiction authors|English novelists" ref="">[http://samvak.tripod.com/christie.html A review of Christie's works]</quote></quotes>