<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="el|eo|en|af|it|cs|et|gl|es|ru|az|pt|tr|li|lt|pl|bg|de|hu|fa|bs|fi|ja|he|sk|uk|sl"><quote id="0" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Mark how my fame rings out from zone to zone:
A thousand critics shouting: "He's unknown!""</quote><quote id="1" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">The fact that boys are allowed to exist at all is evidence of remarkable Christian forbearance among men--were it not for a mawkish humanitarianism, coupled with imperfect digestive powers, we should devour our young, as Nature intended.</quote><quote id="2" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">Peyton Fahrquhar was dead; his body, with a broken neck, swung gently from side to side beneath the timbers of the Owl Creek bridge.</quote><quote id="3" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">True, more than a half of the green graves in the Grafton cemetery are marked "Unknown," and sometimes it occurs that one thinks of the contradiction involved in "honoring the memory" of him of whom no memory remains to honor; but the attempt seems to do no great harm to the living, even to the logical.</quote><quote id="4" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">This is a simple story of a battle; such a tale as may be told by a soldier who is no writer to a reader who is no soldier. </quote><quote id="5" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">An army's bravest men are its cowards. The death which they would not meet at the hands of the enemy they will meet at the hands of their officers, with never a flinching.</quote><quote id="6" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">Hidden in hollows and behind clumps of rank brambles were large tents, dimly lighted with candles, but looking comfortable. The kind of comfort they supplied was indicated by pairs of men entering and reappearing, bearing litters; by low moans from within and by long rows of dead with covered faces outside. These tents were constantly receiving the wounded, yet were never full; they were continually ejecting the dead, yet were never empty. It was as if the helpless had been carried in and murdered, that they might not hamper those whose business it was to fall to-morrow. </quote><quote id="7" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">I suppose the country lying between Corinth and Pittsburg Landing could boast a few inhabitants other than alligators. What manner of people they were it is impossible to say, inasmuch as the fighting dispersed, or possibly exterminated them; perhaps in merely classing them as non-saurian I shall describe them with sufficient particularity and at the same time avert from myself the natural suspicion attaching to a writer who points out to persons who do not know him the peculiarities of persons whom he does not know. "One thing, however, I hope I may without offense affirm of these swamp-dwellers--they were pious. To what deity their veneration was given--whether, like the Egyptians, they worshiped the crocodile, or, like other Americans, adored themselves, I do not presume to guess." But whoever, or whatever, may have been the divinity whose ends they shaped, unto Him, or It, they had builded a temple. This humble edifice, centrally situated in the heart of a solitude, and conveniently accessible to the supersylvan crow, had been christened Shiloh Chapel, whence the name of the battle.</quote><quote id="8" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">Riven and torn with cannon-shot, the trunks of the trees protruded bunches of splinters like hands, the fingers above the wound interlacing with those below.</quote><quote id="9" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Absent," "adj." Peculiarly exposed to the tooth of detraction; vilifed; hopelessly in the wrong; superseded in the consideration and affection of another.&lt;p&gt;</quote><quote id="10" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">To men a man is but a mind. Who cares 
What face he carries or what form he wears? 
But woman's body is the woman. O, 
Stay thou, my sweetheart, and do never go, 
But heed the warning words the sage hath said: 
A woman absent is a woman dead.</quote><quote id="11" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Abstainer", "n." A weak person who yields to the temptation of denying himself a pleasure. A total abstainer is one who abstains from everything but abstention, and especially from inactivity in the affairs of others.</quote><quote id="12" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Absurdity", "n." A statement or belief manifestly inconsistent with one's own opinion.</quote><quote id="13" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Accord", "n." Harmony.</quote><quote id="14" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Accordion", "n." An instrument in harmony with the sentiments of an assassin.</quote><quote id="15" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Acquaintance", "n." A person whom we know well enough to borrow from, but not well enough to lend to. A degree of friendship called slight when its object is poor or obscure, and intimate when he is rich or famous</quote><quote id="16" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Admiration", "n. "Our polite recognition of another's resemblance to ourselves.</quote><quote id="17" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Advice", "n." The smallest current coin.</quote><quote id="18" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Alone", "adj." In bad company.</quote><quote id="19" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Apologize", "v." To lay the foundation for a future offense.</quote><quote id="20" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Bacchus", "n." A convenient deity invented by the ancients as an excuse for getting drunk.</quote><quote id="21" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Back", "n." That part of your friend which it is your privilege to contemplate in your adversity.</quote><quote id="22" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Barometer", "n." An ingenious instrument which indicates what kind of weather we are having.</quote><quote id="23" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Birth", "n." The first and direst of all disasters.</quote><quote id="24" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Bore", "n." A person who talks when you wish him to listen.</quote><quote id="25" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Boundary", "n."  In political geography, an imaginary line between two nations, separating the imaginary rights of one from the imaginary rights of the other.</quote><quote id="26" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Brain", "n." An apparatus with which we think that we think... In our civilization, and under our republican form of government, intelligence is so highly honored that it is rewarded by exemption from the cares of office.</quote><quote id="27" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Bride", "n." A woman with a fine prospect of happiness behind her.</quote><quote id="28" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Cabbage", "n." A familiar kitchen-garden vegetable about as large and wise as a man's head.</quote><quote id="29" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Callous", "adj." Gifted with great fortitude to bear the evils afflicting another.</quote><quote id="30" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Cannon", "n." An instrument employed in the rectification of national boundaries.</quote><quote id="31" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Cartesian", adj.  Relating to Descartes, a famous philosopher, author of the celebrated dictum, "Cogito ergo sum" -- whereby he was pleased to suppose he demonstrated the reality of human existence.  The dictum might be improved, however, thus: "Cogito cogito ergo cogito sum" -- "I think that I think, therefore I think that I am;" as close an approach to certainty as any philosopher has yet made.</quote><quote id="32" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Cat", "n." A soft, indestructible automaton provided by nature to be kicked when things go wrong in the domestic circle.</quote><quote id="33" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Christian", "n." One who believes that the New Testament is a divinely inspired book admirably suited to the spiritual needs of his neighbor. One who follows the teachings of Christ so long as they are not inconsistent with a life of sin.</quote><quote id="34" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Circus", "n." A place where horses, ponies and elephants are permitted to see men, women and children acting the fool.</quote><quote id="35" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Clarionet", "n." An instrument of torture operated by a person with cotton in his ears. There are two instruments that are worse than a clarionet -- two clarionets.</quote><quote id="36" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Congratulation", "n." The civility of envy.</quote><quote id="37" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Conservative", "n." A statesman enamored of existing evils, as opposed to a Liberal, who wants to replace them with others.</quote><quote id="38" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Corporation", "n." An ingenious device for obtaining individual profit without individual responsibility.</quote><quote id="39" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Cynic", "n." A blackguard whose faulty vision sees things as they are, not as they ought to be. Hence the custom among the Scythians of plucking out a cynic's eyes to improve his vision.</quote><quote id="40" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Dawn", "n." The time when men of reason go to bed. Certain old men prefer to rise at about that time, taking a cold bath and a long walk with an empty stomach, and otherwise mortifying the flesh. </quote><quote id="41" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Defenceless", "adj." Unable to attack.</quote><quote id="42" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Dictionary", "n." A malevolent literary device for cramping the growth of a language and making it hard and inelastic. This dictionary, however, is a most useful work.</quote><quote id="43" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Diplomacy", n.  The patriotic art of lying for one's country.</quote><quote id="44" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Education", "n." That which discloses to the wise and disguises from the foolish their lack of understanding.</quote><quote id="45" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Egotist", "n." A person of low taste, more interested in himself than in me.</quote><quote id="46" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Electricity", "n." The cause of all natural phenomena not known to be caused by something else. It is the same thing as lightning, and its famous attempt to strike Dr. Franklin is one of the most picturesque incidents in that great and good man's career.</quote><quote id="47" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Erudition", "n." Dust shaken out of a book into an empty skull. </quote><quote id="48" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Faith", "n." Belief without evidence in what is told by one who speaks without knowledge, of things without parallel.</quote><quote id="49" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Freebooter", "n." A conqueror in a small way of business, whose annexations lack of the sanctifying merit of magnitude. </quote><quote id="50" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Freemasons", "n." An order with secret rites, grotesque ceremonies and fantastic costumes, which, originating in the reign of Charles II, among working artisans of London, has been joined successively by the dead of past centuries in unbroken retrogression until now it embraces all the generations of man on the hither side of Cyrus, Thothmes, and Buddha. Its emblems and symbols have been found in the Catacombs of Paris and Rome, on the stones of the Parthenon and the Chinese Great Wall, among the temples of Karnak and Palmyra and in the Egyptian Pyramids — always by a Freemason.</quote><quote id="51" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Friendless", "adj." Having no favors to bestow. Destitute of fortune. Addicted to utterance of truth and common sense.</quote><quote id="52" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Generous", "adj." Originally this word meant noble by birth and was rightly applied to a great multitude of persons. It now means noble by nature and is taking a bit of a rest.</quote><quote id="53" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Genealogy", "n." An account of one's descent from an ancestor who did not particularly care to trace his own.</quote><quote id="54" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Happiness", "n." An agreeable sensation arising from contemplating the misery of another.</quote><quote id="55" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Heaven", "n." A place where the wicked cease from troubling you with talk of their personal affairs, and the good listen with attention while you expound your own.</quote><quote id="56" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Helpmate", "n." A wife, or bitter half.</quote><quote id="57" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Hers", "pron." His.</quote><quote id="58" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Idiot", "n." A member of a large and powerful tribe whose influence in human affairs has always been dominant and controlling. The Idiot's activity is not confined to any special field of thought or action, but "pervades and regulates the whole." He has the last word in everything; his decision is unappealable. He sets the fashions and opinion of taste, dictates the limitations of speech and circumscribes conduct with a dead-line.</quote><quote id="59" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Incompossible", "adj." Unable to exist if something else exists. Two things are incompossible when the world of being has scope enough for one of them, but not enough for both — as Walt Whitman's poetry and God's mercy to man. </quote><quote id="60" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Infancy", "n." The period of our lives when, according to Wordsworth, 'Heaven lies about us.' The world begins lying about us pretty soon afterward.</quote><quote id="61" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"In'ards", "n. pl." The stomach, heart, soul, and other bowels.</quote><quote id="62" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Insurrection", "n." An unsuccessful revolution.  Disaffection's failure to substitute misrule for bad government.</quote><quote id="63" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Justice", "n." A commodity which in a more or less adulterated condition the State sells to the citizen as a reward for his allegiance, taxes and personal service.</quote><quote id="64" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Kilt", "n." A costume sometimes worn by Scotchmen  in America and Americans in Scotland.</quote><quote id="65" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Land", "n." A part of the earth's surface, considered as property. The theory that land is property subject to private ownership and control is the foundation of modern society, and is eminently worthy of the superstructure. Carried to its logical conclusion, it means that some have the right to prevent others from living; for the right to own implies the right exclusively to occupy; and in fact laws of trespass are enacted wherever property in land is recognized. It follows that if the whole area of terra firma is owned by A, B and C, there will be no place for D, E, F and G to be born, or, born as trespassers, to exist.</quote><quote id="66" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Laughter", "n." An interior convulsion, producing a distortion of the features and accompanied by inarticulate noises. It is infectious and, though intermittent, incurable.</quote><quote id="67" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Learning", "n." The kind of ignorance distinguishing the studious.</quote><quote id="68" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Liberty", "n." One of imagination's most precious possessions.</quote><quote id="69" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Logic", "n." The art of thinking and reasoning in strict accordance with the limitations and incapacities of the human misunderstanding.</quote><quote id="70" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Love", "n." A temporary insanity curable by marriage or by removal of the patient from the influences under which he incurred the disorder. This disease is prevalent only among civilized races living under artificial conditions; barbarous nations breathing pure air and eating simple food enjoy immunity from its ravages. It is sometimes fatal, but more frequently to the physician than to the patient.</quote><quote id="71" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Mad", "adj." Affected with a high degree of intellectual independence; not conforming to standards of thought, speech, and action derived by the conformants from study of themselves; at odds with the majority; in short, unusual. It is noteworthy that persons are pronounced mad by officials destitute of evidence that they themselves are sane.</quote><quote id="72" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Marriage", "n." The state or condition of a community consisting of a master, a mistress and two slaves, making in all, two.</quote><quote id="73" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Mayonnaise", "n." One of the sauces that serve the French in place of a state religion.</quote><quote id="74" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Monday", "n." In Christian countries, the day after the baseball game.</quote><quote id="75" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Neighbor", "n." One whom we are commanded to love as ourselves, and who does all he knows how to make us disobedient.</quote><quote id="76" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Non-combatant", "n." A dead Quaker.</quote><quote id="77" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Ocean", "n." A body of water occupying about two-thirds of a world made for man — who has no gills.</quote><quote id="78" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Once", "adj". Enough.</quote><quote id="79" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Opportunity", "n." A favorable occasion for grasping a disappointment.</quote><quote id="80" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Opposition", "n." In politics the party that prevents the Government from running amok by hamstringing it.</quote><quote id="81" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Optimist", "n." A proponent of the doctrine that black is white.</quote><quote id="82" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Past", "n." That part of Eternity with some small fraction of which we have a slight and regrettable acquaintance. A moving line called the Present parts it from an imaginary period known as the Future. These two grand divisions of Eternity, of which the one is continually effacing the other, are entirely unlike. The one is dark with sorrow and disappointment, the other bright with prosperity and joy. The Past is the region of sobs, the Future is the realm of song. In the one crouches Memory, clad in sackcloth and ashes, mumbling penitential prayer; in the sunshine of the other Hope flies with a free wing, beckoning to temples of success and bowers of ease. Yet the Past is the Future of yesterday, the Future is the Past of to-morrow. They are one--the knowledge and the dream.</quote><quote id="83" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Patience", "n." A minor form of despair, disguised as a virtue.</quote><quote id="84" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Philosophy", "n." A route of many roads leading from nowhere to nothing.</quote><quote id="85" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Pig", "n". An animal ("Porcus omnivorus") closely allied to the human race by the splendor and vivacity of its appetite, which, however, is inferior in scope, for it sticks at pig.</quote><quote id="86" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Politeness" , "n." The most acceptable hypocrisy. </quote><quote id="87" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Politics", "n." A strife of interests masquerading as a contest of principles. The conduct of public affairs for private advantage.</quote><quote id="88" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Positive", "adj." Mistaken at the top of one's voice.</quote><quote id="89" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Pray", "v." To ask that the laws of the universe be annulled in behalf of a single petitioner confessedly unworthy.</quote><quote id="90" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Prejudice", "n". A vagrant opinion without visible means of support.</quote><quote id="91" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Quotation", "n." The act of repeating erroneously the words of another. The words erroneously repeated.</quote><quote id="92" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Rational", "adj." Devoid of all delusions save those of observation, experience and reflection.</quote><quote id="93" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Religion", "n." A daughter of Hope and Fear, explaining to Ignorance the nature of the Unknowable.</quote><quote id="94" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Resign", "v." To renounce an honor for an advantage. To renounce an advantage for a greater advantage.</quote><quote id="95" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Revelation", "n." A famous book in which St. John the Divine concealed all that he knew. The revealing is done by the commentators, who know nothing.</quote><quote id="96" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Road", "n." A strip of land along which one may pass from where it is too tiresome to be to where it is futile to go.</quote><quote id="97" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Sabbath", "n." A weekly festival having its origin in the fact that God made the world in six days and was arrested on the seventh.</quote><quote id="98" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Scriptures", "n." The sacred books of our holy religion, as distinguished from the false and profane writings on which all other faiths are based.</quote><quote id="99" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Selfish", "adj." Devoid of consideration for the selfishness of others.</quote><quote id="100" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Success", "n." The one unpardonable sin against one's fellows.</quote><quote id="101" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Twice", "adv." Once too often.</quote><quote id="102" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Un-American", "adj." Wicked, intolerable, heathenish.</quote><quote id="103" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Virtues", "n. pl." Certain abstentions.</quote><quote id="104" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Vote", "v." The instrument and symbol of a freeman's power to make a fool of himself and a wreck of his country.</quote><quote id="105" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"White", "adj." and "n." Black.</quote><quote id="106" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Witch", "n." (1) An ugly and repulsive old woman, in a wicked league with the devil. (2) A beautiful and attractive young woman, in wickedness a league beyond the devil.</quote><quote id="107" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Year", "n." A period of three hundred and sixty-five disappointments.</quote><quote id="108" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Youth", "n." The Period of Possibility, when Archimedes finds a fulcrum, Cassandra has a following and seven cities compete for the honor of endowing a living Homer.</quote><quote id="109" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Zeal", "n." A certain nervous disorder afflicting the young and inexperienced. A passion that goeth before a sprawl.</quote><quote id="110" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"Zeus", "n". The chief of Grecian gods, adored by the Romans as Jupiter and by the modern Americans as God, Gold, Mob and Dog. Some explorers who have touched upon the shores of America, and one who professes to have penetrated a considerable distance to the interior, have thought that these four names stand for as many distinct deities, but in his monumental work on Surviving Faiths, Frumpp insists that the natives are monotheists, each having no other god than himself, whom he worships under many sacred names.</quote><quote id="111" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">Woman would be more charming if one could fall into her arms without falling into her hands.</quote><quote id="112" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">You are not permitted to kill a woman who has wronged you, but nothing forbids you to reflect that she is growing older every minute. You are avenged 1440 times a day.</quote><quote id="113" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">Self-denial is indulgence of a propensity to forego.</quote><quote id="114" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">To Dogmatism the Spirit of Inquiry is the same as the Spirit of Evil.</quote><quote id="115" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">There was never a genius who was not thought a fool until he disclosed himself; whereas he is a fool then only.</quote><quote id="116" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">Strive not for singularity in dress; Fools have the more and men of sense the less. To look original is not worth while, But be in mind a little out of style.</quote><quote id="117" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">To be comic is merely to be playful, but wit is a serious matter. To laugh at it is to confess that you do not understand.</quote><quote id="118" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">If you would be accounted great by your contemporaries, be not too much greater than they.</quote><quote id="119" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">O proud philanthropist, your hope is vain To get by giving what you lost by gain.</quote><quote id="120" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">"There's no free will," says the philosopher; "To hang is most unjust."
"There is no free will," assents the officer; "We hang because we must."</quote><quote id="121" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">The game of discontent has its rules, and he who disregards them cheats. It is not permitted to you to wish to add another's advantages or possessions to your own; you are permitted only to wish to be another.</quote><quote id="122" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">If you want to read a perfect book there is only one way: write it.</quote><quote id="123" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">When lost in a forest go always down hill. When lost in a philosophy or doctrine go upward.</quote><quote id="124" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">We submit to the majority because we have to. But we are not compelled to call our attitude of subjection a posture of respect.</quote><quote id="125" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">A popular author is one who writes what the people think. Genius invites them to think something else.</quote><quote id="126" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">The virtues chose Modesty to be their queen.
"I did not know that I was a virtue," she said. "Why did you not choose Innocence?"
"Because of her ignorance," they replied. "She knows nothing but that she is a virtue."</quote><quote id="127" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">The only distinction that democracies reward is a high degree of conformity.</quote><quote id="128" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">Slang is the speech of him who robs the literary garbage carts on their way to the dumps.</quote><quote id="129" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">The palmist looks at the wrinkles made by closing the hand and says they signify character. The philosopher reads character by what the hand most loves to close upon.</quote><quote id="130" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">The money-getter who pleads his love of work has a lame defense, for love of work at money-getting is a lower taste than love of money.</quote><quote id="131" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">A man is the sum of his ancestors; to reform him you must begin with a dead ape and work downward through a million graves. He is like the lower end of a suspended chain; you can sway him slightly to the right or the left, but remove your hand and he falls into line with the other links.</quote><quote id="132" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">He who thinks with difficulty believes with alacrity.</quote><quote id="133" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">Along the road of life are many pleasure resorts, but think not that by tarrying in them you will take more days to the journey. The day of your arrival is already recorded.</quote><quote id="134" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">The most offensive egotist is he that fears to say "I" and "me." "It will probably rain "—that is dogmatic. "I think it will rain"—that is natural and modest. Montaigne is the most delightful of essayists because so great is his humility that he does not think it important that we see not Montaigne. He so forgets himself that he employs no artifice to make us forget him.</quote><quote id="135" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">Convictions are variable; to be always consistent is to be sometimes dishonest.</quote><quote id="136" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">The most intolerant advocate is he who is trying to convince himself.</quote><quote id="137" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">The poor man's price of admittance to the favor of the rich is his self-respect.</quote><quote id="138" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">All are lunatics, but he who can analyze his delusion is called a philosopher.</quote><quote id="139" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">Slang is a foul pool at which every dunce fills his bucket, and then sets up as a fountain.</quote><quote id="140" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">Happiness is lost by criticizing it; sorrow by accepting it.</quote><quote id="141" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">When prosperous the fool trembles for the evil that is to come; in adversity the philosopher smiles for the good that he has had.</quote><quote id="142" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">Age, with his eyes in the back of his head, thinks it wisdom to see the bogs through which he has floundered.</quote><quote id="143" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">Wisdom is known only by contrasting it with folly; by shadow only we perceive that all visible objects are not flat. Yet Philanthropos would abolish evil!</quote><quote id="144" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">To the eye of failure success is an accident.</quote><quote id="145" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">While you have a future do not live too much in contemplation of your past: unless you are content to walk backward the mirror is a poor guide.</quote><quote id="146" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">[http://donswaim.com/ The Ambrose Bierce Site]</quote><quote id="147" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">[http://www.gutenberg.org/browse/authors/b#a206 Bierce] at Project Gutenberg</quote><quote id="148" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">[http://www.biercephile.com The Ambrose Bierce Appreciation Society]</quote><quote id="149" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">[http://www.ambrosebierce.org The Ambrose Bierce Project]</quote><quote id="150" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">[http://ojinaga.com/bierce/ "Ambrose Bierce, 'the Old Gringo': Fact, Fiction and Fantasy"]</quote><quote id="151" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">[http://www.rjgeib.com/thoughts/bierce/ambrose-bierce.html One of Bierce's last letters]</quote><quote id="152" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">[http://atheisme.free.fr/Biographies/Bierce_e.htm Biography and quotes of Ambrose Bierce]</quote><quote id="153" author="Ambrose Bierce" cats="1910s deaths|Aphorists|Californians|Fantasy authors|Horror authors|Humorists|Indianans|Journalists|Ohioans|Political authors" ref="">[http://bitterbierce.blogspot.com Waking Ambrose: Contemporary Adjustments of the Devil's Dictionary]</quote></quotes>