<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="ru|ka|bg|zh|pt|tr|it|lt|en|pl|bs|es|he"><quote id="0" author="Audrey Hepburn" cats="1990s deaths|Actors|Belgians" ref="">"I am more than ever awed and overwhelmed by the monumental talents it was my great, great privilege to work for and with." There is therefore no way I can thank you for this beautiful award without thanking all of them, because it is they who helped and honed, triggered and taught, pushed and pulled, dressed and photographed — and with endless patience and kindness and gentleness, guided and nurtured a totally unknown, insecure, inexperienced, skinny broad into a marketable commodity. "I am proud to have been in a business that gives pleasure, creates beauty, and awakens our conscience, arouses compassion, and perhaps most importantly, gives millions a respite from our so violent world." Thank you, Screen Actors Guild and friends, for this huge honor — and for giving me this unique opportunity to express my deepest gratitude and love to all of those who have given me a career that has brought me nothing but happiness.</quote><quote id="1" author="Audrey Hepburn" cats="1990s deaths|Actors|Belgians" ref="">"Living is like tearing through a museum." Not until later do you really start absorbing what you saw, thinking about it, looking it up in a book, and remembering — because you can't take it all in at once.</quote><quote id="2" author="Audrey Hepburn" cats="1990s deaths|Actors|Belgians" ref="">I can testify to what UNICEF means to children, because I was among those who received food and medical relief right after World War II, "I have a long-lasting gratitude and trust for what UNICEF does."</quote><quote id="3" author="Audrey Hepburn" cats="1990s deaths|Actors|Belgians" ref="">Success is like reaching an important birthday and finding you're exactly the same.</quote><quote id="4" author="Audrey Hepburn" cats="1990s deaths|Actors|Belgians" ref="">I'm half-Irish, half-Dutch, and I was born in Belgium. If I was a dog, I'd be in a hell of a mess!</quote><quote id="5" author="Audrey Hepburn" cats="1990s deaths|Actors|Belgians" ref="">"You have to look at yourself objectively. Analyze yourself like an instrument. You have to be absolutely frank with yourself. Face your handicaps, don't try to hide them. Instead, develop something else."</quote><quote id="6" author="Audrey Hepburn" cats="1990s deaths|Actors|Belgians" ref="">I can take long walks, as I understand Greta Garbo does, and no one interferes with my thoughts and tranquility. Come to think of it, the other day I was on Fifth Avenue in New York and I saw a woman who could very well have been Garbo; I was a bit tempted to go up to her, but then I thought, "My God, practice what you preach! If it is her, you'll be intruding — just the thing you don't like yourself."</quote><quote id="7" author="Audrey Hepburn" cats="1990s deaths|Actors|Belgians" ref="">As a child, I was taught that it was bad manners to bring attention to yourself, and to never, ever make a spectacle of yourself ... All of which I've earned a living doing.</quote><quote id="8" author="Audrey Hepburn" cats="1990s deaths|Actors|Belgians" ref="">I never think of myself as an icon. What is in other people's minds is not in my mind. I just do my thing.</quote><quote id="9" author="Audrey Hepburn" cats="1990s deaths|Actors|Belgians" ref="">People associate me with a time when movies were pleasant, when women wore pretty dresses in films and you heard beautiful music. "I always love it when people write me and say "I was having a rotten time, and I walked into a cinema and saw one of your movies, and it made such a difference.""</quote><quote id="10" author="Audrey Hepburn" cats="1990s deaths|Actors|Belgians" ref="">"I love people who make me laugh. I honestly think it's the thing I like most, to laugh. It cures a multitude of ills. It's probably the most important thing in a person."</quote></quotes>