<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="el|en|af|ca|it|cs|gl|es|ru|az|nl|pt|tr|lt|pl|bg|uk|de|da|fa|bs|fi|he|ko|sk|ku|sl"><quote id="0" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Coningsby" (1844)</quote><quote id="1" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Sybil, or The Two Nations" (1845).</quote><quote id="2" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">To govern men, you must either excel them in their accomplishments, or despise them. </quote><quote id="3" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"I am a Conservative to preserve all that is good in our constitution, a Radical to remove all that is bad." I seek to preserve property and to respect order, and I equally decry the appeal to the passions of the many or the prejudices of the few</quote><quote id="4" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Yes, I am a Jew, and when the ancestors of the right honorable gentleman were brutal savages in an unknown island, mine were priests in the temple of Solomon."</quote><quote id="5" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"I will sit down now, but the time will come when you will hear me."</quote><quote id="6" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Free trade is not a principle; it is an expedient.</quote><quote id="7" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">That dense population in extreme distress inhabited an island where there was an established church which was not their church; and a territorial aristocracy, the richest of whom lived in distant capitals. Thus they had a starving population, an absentee aristocracy, and an alien Church, and, in addition, the weakest executive in the world. That was the Irish question.</quote><quote id="8" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The noble lord in this case, as in so many others, first destroys his opponent, and then destroys his own position afterwards. The noble lord is the Prince Rupert of parliamentary discussion: his charge is resistless, but when he returns from the pursuit he always finds his camp in the possession of the enemy.</quote><quote id="9" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">It is knowledge that influences and equalises the social condition of man; that gives to all, however different their political position, passions which are in common, and enjoyments which are universal.</quote><quote id="10" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">London owes everything to its press: it owes as much to its press as it does to its being the seat of government and the law.</quote><quote id="11" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The press is not only free, it is powerful. That power is ours. It is the proudest that man can enjoy. It was not granted by monarchs, it was not gained for us by aristocracies ; but it sprang from the people, and, with an immortal instinct, it has always worked for the people.</quote><quote id="12" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The right hon. Gentleman caught the Whigs bathing, and walked away with their clothes. He has left them in the full enjoyment of their liberal position, and he is himself a strict conservative of their garments.</quote><quote id="13" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">For myself, I care not what may be the result. Dissolve, if you please, the Parliament you have betrayed, and appeal to the people, who, I believe, mistrust you. For me there remains this at least—the opportunity of expressing thus publicly my belief that a Conservative Government is an Organised Hypocrisy.</quote><quote id="14" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Protection is not a principle, but an expedient.</quote><quote id="15" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Sir, it is very easy to complain of party Government, and there may be persons capable of forming an opinion on this subject who may entertain a deep objection to that Government, and know to what that objection leads. But there are others who shrug their shoulders, and talk in a slipshod style on this head, who, perhaps, are not exactly aware of what the objections lead to. These persons should understand, that if they object to party Government, they do, in fact, object to nothing more nor less than Parliamentary Government. "A popular assembly without parties--500 isolated individuals--cannot stand five years against a Minister with an organized Government without becoming a servile Senate."</quote><quote id="16" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">[http://hansard.millbanksystems.com/commons/1845/apr/11/maynooth-college Speech] in the House of Commons (11 April 1845).</quote><quote id="17" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Something has risen up in this country as fatal in the political world as it has been in the landed world of Ireland—we have a great Parliamentary middleman. It is well known what a middleman is; he is a man who bamboozles one party, and plunders the other, till, having obtained a position to which he is not entitled, he cries out, "Let us have 566 no party questions, but fixity of tenure." </quote><quote id="18" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">That is the fourth course, which in future I trust the right hon. Gentleman (Sir R. Peel) will not forget. The right hon. Gentleman tells us to go back to precedents; with him a great measure is always founded on a small precedent. He traces the steam-engine always back to the tea-kettle. His precedents are generally tea-kettle precedents.</quote><quote id="19" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Sir, very few people reach posterity. Who amongst us may arrive at that destination I presume not to vaticinate. Posterity is a most limited assembly. Those gentlemen who reach posterity are not much more numerous than the planets.</quote><quote id="20" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">He is so vain that he wants to figure in history as the settler of all the great questions; but a Parliamentary constitution is not favorable to such ambitions; things must be done by parties, not by persons using parties as tools.</quote><quote id="21" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">I entirely differ with the Government as to the value of precedents. In this case, as in others, precedents are not mere dusty phrases, which do not substantially affect the question before us. "A precedent embalms a principle."</quote><quote id="22" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">My objection to Liberalism is this--that it is the introduction into the practical business of life of the highest kind--namely, politics--of philosophical ideas instead of political principles.</quote><quote id="23" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The hon. Gentleman has said, in a most extraordinary manner, that our security for peace at the present day is the desire of nations to keep at home. There is a great difference between nationality and race. "Nationality is the principle of political independence. Race is the principle of physical analogy," and you have at this moment the principle of race--not at all of nationality--adopted by Germany, the very country to which the hon. Member for the West Riding referred.</quote><quote id="24" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">You cannot choose between party government and Parliamentary government. I say, you can have no Parliamentary government if you have no party government; and, therefore, when Gentlemen denounce party government, they strike at that scheme of government which, in my opinion, has made this country great, and which I hope will keep it great.</quote><quote id="25" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">But this principle of race is unfortunately one of the reasons why I fear war may always exist; because race implies difference, difference implies superiority, and superiority leads to predominance.</quote><quote id="26" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">But he has left us the legacy of heroes--the memory of his great name, and the inspiration of his great example.</quote><quote id="27" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">I remember—the interruption of the hon. Gentleman reminds me of the words of a great writer, who said that "Grace was beauty in action." "Sir, I say that justice is truth in action. Truth should animate an opposition, and I hope it does animate this opposition.;"</quote><quote id="28" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Yes! I know what I have to face. I have to face a coalition. The combination may be successful. A coalition has before this been successful. But coalitions, although successful, have always found this, that their triumph has been brief. This too I know, that England does not love coalitions.</quote><quote id="29" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">But existing society has chosen to persecute this race which should furnish its choice allies, and what have been the consequences?
They may be traced in the List outbreak of the destructive principle in Europe. An insurrection takes place against tradition and aristocracy, against religion and property. Destruction of the Semitic principle, extirpation of the Jewish religion, whether in the Mosaic or in the Christian form, the natural equality of man and the abrogation of property, are proclaimed by the secret societies who form provisional governments, and men of Jewish race are found at the head of every one of them. "The people of God coöperate with atheists; the most skilful accumulators of property ally themselves with communists; the peculiar and chosen race touch the hand of all the scum and low castes of Europe! And all this because they wish to destroy that ungrateful Christendom which owes to them even its name, and whose tyranny they can no longer endure."</quote><quote id="30" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">This is the third time that, in the course of six years, during which I have had the lead of the Opposition in the House of Commons, I have stormed the Treasury Benches: twice, fruitlessly, the third time with a tin kettle to my tail which rendered the race hopeless.  You cannot, therefore, be surprised, that I am a little wearied of these barren victories, which like Alma, Inkerman, and Balaclava, may be glorious but are certainly nothing more.</quote><quote id="31" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Finality, Sir, is not the language of politics.</quote><quote id="32" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">This shows how much easier it is to be critical than to be correct.</quote><quote id="33" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">He seems to think that posterity is a pack-horse, always ready to be loaded.</quote><quote id="34" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Colonies do not cease to be colonies because they are independent.</quote><quote id="35" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">At present the peace of the world has been preserved, not by statesmen, but by capitalists.</quote><quote id="36" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Never take anything for granted.</quote><quote id="37" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The characteristic of the present age is craving credulity.</quote><quote id="38" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">What is the question now placed before society with the glib assurance which to me is most astonishing? That question is this: Is man an ape or an angel? "I, my lord, I am on the side of the angels." I repudiate with indignation and abhorrence those new fangled theories.</quote><quote id="39" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"There are rare instances when the sympathy of a nation approaches those tenderer feelings which are generally supposed to be peculiar to the individual, and to be the happy privilege of private life, and this is one." Under any circumstances we should have bewailed the catastrophe at Washington; under any circumstances we should have shuddered at the means by which it was accomplished. But in the character of the victim, and even in the accessories of his last moments, there is something so homely and innocent, that it takes the question, as it were, out of all the pomp of history and the ceremonial of diplomacy; it touches the heart of nations, and appeals to the domestic sentiment of mankind. 
Whatever the various and varying opinions in this House, and in the country generally, on the policy of the late President of the United States, all must agree that in one of the severest trials which ever tested the moral qualities of man he fulfilled his duty with simplicity and strength. …When such crimes are perpetrated the public mind is apt to fall into gloom and perplexity, for it is ignorant alike of the causes and the consequences of such deeds. But it is one of our duties to reassure them under unreasoning panic and despondency. "Assassination has never changed the history of the world." I will not refer to the remote past, though an accident has made the most memorable instance of antiquity at this moment fresh in the minds and memory of all around me. But even the costly sacrifice of a Caesar did not propitiate the inexorable destiny of his country.</quote><quote id="40" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">In the character of the victim [Lincoln], and even in the accessories of his last moments, there is something so homely and innocent that it takes the question, as it were, out of all the pomp of history and the ceremonial of diplomacy—it touches the heart of nations and appeals to the domestic sentiment of mankind.</quote><quote id="41" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Ignorance never settles a question.</quote><quote id="42" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Individualities may form communities, but it is institutions alone that can create a nation.</quote><quote id="43" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">For what is the Tory party unless it represents national feeling? If it does not represent national feeling, Toryism is nothing. It does not depend upon hereditary coteries of exclusive nobles. It does not attempt power by attracting to itself the spurious force which may accidentally arise from advocating cosmopolitan principles or talking cosmopolitan jargon. The Tory party is nothing unless it represent and uphold the institutions of the country.</quote><quote id="44" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">In a progressive country change is constant;… change … is inevitable.</quote><quote id="45" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">I see before me the statue of a celebrated minister, who said that confidence was a plant of slow growth. But I believe, however gradual may be the growth of confidence, that of credit requires still more time to arrive at maturity.</quote><quote id="46" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">In a progressive country change is constant; and the great question is not whether you should resist change which is inevitable, but whether that change should be carried out in deference to the manners, the customs, the laws and the traditions of a people, or whether it should be carried out in deference to abstract principles, and arbitrary and general doctrines.</quote><quote id="47" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Yes, I have climbed to the top of the greasy pole.</quote><quote id="48" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">This is to be observed of the Bishop of London, that, though apparently of a spirit somewhat austere, there is in his idiosyncrasy a strange fund of enthusiasm, a quality which ought never to be possessed by an Archbishop of Canterbury, or a Prime Minister of England. The Bishop of London sympathies with everything that is earnest; but what is earnest is not always true; on the contrary error is often more earnest than truth.</quote><quote id="49" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">There can be no economy where there is no efficiency.</quote><quote id="50" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">I think the author who speaks about his own books is almost as bad as a mother who talks about her own children.</quote><quote id="51" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">That is an apology, not an explanation; and apologies only account for that which they do not alter.</quote><quote id="52" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Increased means and increased leisure are the two civilizers of man."</quote><quote id="53" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">You behold a range of exhausted volcanoes. Not a flame flickers on a single pallid crest.</quote><quote id="54" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Gentl, I am a party man. "I believe that, without party, Parliamentary government is impossible". I look upon Parliamentary government as the noblest government in the world, and certainly the one most suited to England.</quote><quote id="55" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Gentlemen, the Tory party, unless it is a national party, is nothing.</quote><quote id="56" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The most distinguishing feature, or, at least, one of the most distinguishing features, of the great change effected in 1832 was that those who effected it at once abolished all the franchises as ancient as those of the Baronage of England; and, while they abolished them, they offered and proposed no substitute. The discontent upon the subject of representation which afterwards more or less pervaded our society dates from that period, and that discontent, all will admit, has ceased. It was terminated by the Act of Parliamentary Reform of 1867-8. That act was founded on a confidence that the great body of the people of this country were "Conservative". I use the word in its purest and loftiest sense. I mean that the people of England, and especially the working classes of England, are proud of belonging to a great country, and wish to maintain its greatness&amp;mdash;that they are proud of belonging to an Imperial country, and are resolved to maintain, if they can, the empire of England&amp;mdash;that they believe, on the whole, that the greatness and the empire of England are to be attributed to the ancient institutions of this country...There are people who may be, or who at least affect to be, working men, and who, no doubt, have a certain influence with a certain portion of the metropolitan working class, who talk Jacobinism...I say with confidence that the great body of the working class of England utterly repudiate such sentiments. They have no sympathy with them. They are English to the core. They repudiate cosmopolitan principles. They adhere to national principles. They are for maintaining the greatness of the kingdom and the empire, and they are proud of being subjects of our Sovereign and members of such an Empire. Well, then, as regards the political institutions of this country, the maintenance of which is one of the chief tenets of the Tory party, so far as I can read public opinion, the feeling of the nation is in accordance with the Tory party.</quote><quote id="57" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"The secret of success is constancy to purpose."</quote><quote id="58" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">A University should be a place of light, of liberty, and of learning.</quote><quote id="59" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">You have despoiled Churches. You have threatened every corporation and endowment in the country. You have examined into everybody's affairs. You have criticized every profession and vexed every trade. No one is certain of his property, and nobody knows what duties he may have to perform tomorrow. This is the policy of confiscation as compared with that of concurrent endowment.</quote><quote id="60" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">For nearly five years the present Ministers have harassed every trade, worried every profession, and assailed or menaced every class, institution, and species of property in the country. Occasionally they have varied this state of civil warfare by perpetrating some job which outraged public opinion, or by stumbling into mistakes which have been always discreditable, and sometimes ruinous. All this they call a policy, and seem quite proud of it; but the country has, I think, made up its mind to close this career of plundering and blundering.</quote><quote id="61" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">An author who speaks about his own books is almost as bad as a mother who talks about her own children.</quote><quote id="62" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">King Louis Philippe once said to me that he attributed the great success of the British nation in political life to their talking politics after dinner.</quote><quote id="63" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">I have always felt that the best security for civilisation is the dwelling, and that upon properly appointed and becoming dwellings depends more than anything else the improvement of mankind. Such dwellings are the nursery of all domestic virtues, and without a becoming home the exercise of those virtues is impossible.</quote><quote id="64" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Upon the education of the people of this country the fate of this country depends.</quote><quote id="65" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">I am dead: dead, but in the Elysian fields.</quote><quote id="66" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The danger at such a moment is that designing politicians may take advantage of such sublime sentiments and may apply them for the furtherance of their sinister ends. I do not think there is any language which can denounce too strongly conduct of this description. He who at such a moment would avail himself of such a commanding sentiment in order to obtain his own individual ends, suggesting a course which he may know to be injurious to the interests of the country, and not favourable to the welfare of mankind, is a man whose conduct no language can too strongly condemn. He outrages the principle of patriotism, which is the soul of free communities. He does more&amp;mdash;he influences in the most injurious manner the common welfare of humanity. Such conduct, if it be pursued by any man at this moment, ought to be indignantly reprobated by the people of England; for, in the general havoc and ruin which it may bring about, it may, I think, be fairly described as worse than any of those Bulgarian atrocities which now occupy attention.</quote><quote id="67" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">What I see in the amendment is not an assertion of great principles, which no man honours more than myself. What is at the bottom of it is rather that principle of peace at any price which a certain party in this country upholds. It is that dangerous dogma which I believe animates the ranks before me at this moment, although many of them may be unconscious of it. That deleterious doctrine haunts the people of this country in every form. Sometimes it is a committee; sometimes it is a letter; sometimes it is an amendment to the Address; sometimes it is a proposition to stop the supplies. That doctrine has done more mischief than any I can well recall that have been afloat this century. It has occasioned more wars than the most ruthless conquerors. It has disturbed and nearly destroyed that political equilibrium so necessary to the liberties of nations and the welfare of the world. It has dimmed occasionally for a moment even the majesty of England. And, my lords, to-night you have an opportunity, which I trust you will not lose, of branding these opinions, these deleterious dogmas, with the reprobation of the Peers of England.</quote><quote id="68" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">It has been said that the people of this country are deeply interested in the humanitarian and philanthropic considerations involved in [the Eastern Question]. All must appreciate such feelings. But I am mistaken if there be not a yet deeper sentiment on the part of the people of this country, one with which I cannot doubt your lordships will ever sympathise, and that is&amp;mdash;the determination to maintain the Empire of England.</quote><quote id="69" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The health of the people is really the foundation upon which all their happiness and all their powers as a state depend.</quote><quote id="70" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">What, then, was that policy? It was a policy of conditional neutrality. Under the circumstances of the case we did not believe that it was for the honour or interest of England or Turkey that we should take any part in the impending contest; but while we enforced the neutrality which we prepared to observe, we declared at the same time that that neutrality must cease if British interests were assailed or menaced. Cosmopolitan critics, men who are the friends of every country save their own, have denounced this policy as a selfish policy. My Lord Mayor, it is as selfish as patriotism.</quote><quote id="71" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">We have brought a peace, and we trust we have brought a peace with honour, and I trust that that will now be followed by the prosperity of the country.</quote><quote id="72" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Lord Salisbury and myself have brought you back peace, but a peace, I hope, with honour which may satisfy our Sovereign, and tend to the welfare of the country.</quote><quote id="73" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Which do you believe most likely to enter an insane convention, a body of English gentlemen honoured by the favour of their Sovereign and the confidence of their fellow-subjects, managing your affairs for five years, I hope with prudence, and not altogether without success, or "a sophistical rhetorician, inebriated with the exuberance of his own verbosity, and gifted with an egotistical imagination that can at all times command an interminable and inconsistent series of arguments to malign an opponent and to glorify himself"?</quote><quote id="74" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">A series of congratulatory regrets.</quote><quote id="75" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The harebrained chatter of irresponsible frivolity.</quote><quote id="76" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Why, I say, that to tax the community for the advantage of a class is not protection; it is plunder, and I entirely disclaim it; but I ask you to protect the rights and interests of labour generally in the first place, by allowing no free imports from countries which meet you with countervailing duties; and, in the second place, with respect to agricultural produce, to compensate the soil for the burdens from which other classes are free by an equivalent duty. This is my view of what is called "protection."</quote><quote id="77" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">It is the initial letters of the four points of the compass that make the word "news," and he must understand that news is that which collies from the North, East, West and South, and if it comes from only one point of the compass, then it is a class publication, and not news.</quote><quote id="78" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Time is precious, but truth is more precious than time.</quote><quote id="79" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Nobody is forgotten, when it is convenient to remember him.</quote><quote id="80" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Without publicity there can be no public spirit, and without public spirit every nation must decay.</quote><quote id="81" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">A sophistical rhetorician, inebriated with the exuberance of his own verbosity, and gifted with an egotistical imagination that who can at all times command an interminable and inconsistent series of arguments to malign an opponent and glorify himself.</quote><quote id="82" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">A very remarkable people the Zulus: they defeat our generals, they convert our bishops, they have settled the fate of a great European dynasty.</quote><quote id="83" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">No one, I think, can deny that the depression of the agricultural interest is excessive. Though I can recall periods of suffering, none of them have ever equalled the present in its instances. Let us consider the principle causes of this distress. My noble friend who has addressed you has very properly touched upon the subject and upon the effect of the continuous bad harvests in this country...It is, however, true that at that time the loss and suffering were not recognized as they were in the old days, when the system of protection existed, because the price of the food of the people was not immediately affected by a bad harvest, and it was not till the repetition of the misfortune on two occasions that the diminution of the wealth of the country began to be severely felt by the people generally. The remarkable feature of the present agricultural depression is this&amp;mdash;that the agricultural interest is suffering from a succession of bad harvest, accompanied, for the first time, by extremely low prices. That is a remarkable circumstance that has never before occurred&amp;mdash;a combination that has never before been encountered. In old days, when we had a bad harvest we had also the somewhat dismal compensation of higher prices; but now, when the harvests are bad the prices are lower rather than higher...nor is it open to doubt that foreign competition has exercised a most injurious influence on the agricultural interests of the country. The country, however, was perfectly warned that if we made a great revolution in our industrial system, that was one of the consequences that would accrue. I may mention that the great result of the returns we possess is this, that the immense importations of foreign agricultural produce have been vastly in excess of what the increased demands of our population actually require, and that is why the low prices are maintained...That is to a great degree the cause of this depression.</quote><quote id="84" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">It cannot be denied that a state of great national prosperity is quite consistent and compatible with legislation in favour of the protection of native industry. That proposition, years ago, was denied; but with the experience we have had of France and the United States of America&amp;mdash;the two most flourishing communities probably in existence&amp;mdash;it is now incontestable. Well, my lords, many years ago&amp;mdash;nearly 40&amp;mdash;this country, which no one can say for a moment did not flourish with the old system of protection, deemed it necessary to revise the principles upon which its commerce was conducted...The scheme that was adopted was this&amp;mdash;that we were to fight hostile tariffs with free imports. I was among those who looked upon that policy with fear. I believed it to be one very perilous. ...reciprocity is barter. I always understood that barter was the last effort of civilization that it was exactly that state of human exchange that separated civilization from savagery; and if reciprocity is only barter, I fear that would hardly help us out of our difficulty. My noble friend read some extracts from the speeches of those who had the misfortune to be in Parliament at that time, and he honoured me by reading an extract from the speech I then made in the other House of Parliament. That was a speech in favour of reciprocity, and indicated the means by which reciprocity could be obtained. That is to say&amp;mdash;I do not want to enter into the discussion whether the principle was right or wrong, but it was acknowledged in public life, favoured and pursued by many statesmen who conceived that by the negotiation of a treaty of commerce, by reciprocal exchange and the lowering of duties, the products of the two negotiating countries would find a freer access and consumption in the two countries than they formerly possessed. But when he taunts me with his quotation of some musty phrases of mine 40 years ago, I must remind him that we had elements then on which treaties of reciprocity could be negotiated. At that time, although the great changes of Sir Robert Peel had taken place, there were 168 articles in the tariff which were materials by which you could have negotiated, if that was a wise and desirable policy, commercial treaties of reciprocity. What is the number you now have in the tariff? Twenty-two. Those who talk of negotiating treaties of reciprocity...have they the materials for negotiating treaties of reciprocity? You have lost the opportunity. I do not want to enter into the argument at the present moment; but England cannot pursue that policy.</quote><quote id="85" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">In assuming that peace will be maintained, I assume also that no Great Power would shrink from its responsibilities. If there be a country, for example, one of the most extensive and wealthiest of empires in the world&amp;mdash;if that country, from a perverse interpretation of its insular geographical position, turns an indifferent ear to the feelings and the fortunes of Continental Europe, such a course would, I believe, only end in its becoming an object of general plunder. So long as the power and advice of England are felt in the councils of Europe, peace, I believe, will be maintained, and maintained for a long period. Without their presence, war, as has happened before, and too frequently of late, seems to me to be inevitable. I speak on this subject with confidence to the citizens of London, because I know that they are men who are not ashamed of the Empire which their ancestors created; because I know that they are not ashamed of the noblest of human sentiments, now decried by philosophers&amp;mdash;the sentiment of patriotism; because I know they will not be beguiled into believing that in maintaining their Empire they may forfeit their liberties. One of the greatest of Romans, when asked what were his politics, replied, "Imperium et Libertas". That would not make a bad programme for a British Ministry. It is one from which Her Majesty's advisers do not shrink.</quote><quote id="86" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">I don't wish to go down to posterity talking bad grammar.</quote><quote id="87" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">You will find as you grow older that courage is the rarest of all qualities to be found in public men.</quote><quote id="88" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Miss Sands told me that Queen Victoria, who was latterly "éprise" with Disraeli, one day asked him what was his real religion. "Madam," he replied, ""I am the blank page between the Old Testament and the New."" </quote><quote id="89" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">We are the children of the gods, and are never more the slaves of circumstance than when we deem ourselves their masters. What may next happen in the dazzling farce of life, the Fates only know.</quote><quote id="90" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Be amusing: never tell unkind stories; above all, never tell long ones. "</quote><quote id="91" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">He told Lord Esher that, in talking with the Queen, he observed a simple rule: "I never deny; I never contradict; I sometimes forget."</quote><quote id="92" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">If Gladstone fell into the Thames, that would be a misfortune; and if anybody pulled him out, that, I suppose, would be a calamity.</quote><quote id="93" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">No man is regular in his attendance at the House of Commons until he is married.</quote><quote id="94" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">He has not a single redeeming defect.</quote><quote id="95" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Where knowledge ends, religion begins.</quote><quote id="96" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">I suppose, to use our national motto, something will turn up.</quote><quote id="97" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"What is care?" asked the Princess, with a smile.
"It is a god", replied the Physician, "invisible, but omnipotent. It steals the bloom from the cheek and lightness from the pulse — it takes away the appetite, and turns the hair grey".</quote><quote id="98" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">I am prepared for the worst, but hope for the best.</quote><quote id="99" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Despair is the conclusion of fools.</quote><quote id="100" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Success is the child of audacity.</quote><quote id="101" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Though lions to their enemies they were lambs to their friends.</quote><quote id="102" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Next to knowing when to seize an opportunity, the most important thing in life is to know when to forego an advantage.</quote><quote id="103" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Courage is fire, and bullying is smoke.</quote><quote id="104" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The fool wonders, the wise man asks.</quote><quote id="105" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Manners are easy," said Coningsby, "and life is hard."</quote><quote id="106" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"So you see, my dear Coningsby, that the world is governed by very different personages from what is imagined by those who are not behind the scenes." (Sidonia speaking)</quote><quote id="107" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The microcosm of a public school.</quote><quote id="108" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The Services in war time are fit only for desperadoes but, in peace, are fit only for fools.</quote><quote id="109" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Beware of endeavouring to become a great man in a hurry. One such attempt in ten thousand may succeed: these are fearful odds.</quote><quote id="110" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">I hate definitions.</quote><quote id="111" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Fear makes us feel our humanity.</quote><quote id="112" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">There is no act of treachery or meanness of which a political party is not capable; for in politics there is no honour.</quote><quote id="113" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Experience is the child of Thought, and Thought is the child of Action. We can not learn men from books.</quote><quote id="114" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Variety is the mother of Enjoyment.</quote><quote id="115" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">There is moderation even in excess.</quote><quote id="116" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">In polit nothing is contemptible.</quote><quote id="117" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">" Man is not the creature of circumstances, circumstances are the creatures of men. We are free agents, and man is more powerful than matter."</quote><quote id="118" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"I repeat that all power is a trust; that we are accountable for its exercise; that from the people, and for the people all springs, and all must exist."</quote><quote id="119" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Grief is the agony of an instant; the indulgence of Grief the blunder of a life.</quote><quote id="120" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">A man's fate is his own temper.</quote><quote id="121" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">A consistent man believes in Destiny — a capricious man in Chance.</quote><quote id="122" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Like all great travellers I have seen more than I remember, and remember more than I have seen.</quote><quote id="123" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The disappointment of manhood succeeds to the delusion of youth: let us hope that the heritage of old age is not despair.</quote><quote id="124" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Every man has a right to be conceited until he is successful.</quote><quote id="125" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">A "dark" horse, which had never been thought of, and which the careless St. James had never even observed in the list, rushed past the grandstand in sweeping triumph.</quote><quote id="126" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Then there was a maiden speech, so inaudible, that it was doubted whether, after all, the young orator really did lose his virginity.</quote><quote id="127" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">We are indeed a nation of shopkeepers.</quote><quote id="128" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">It destroys one's nerves to be amiable every day to the same human being.</quote><quote id="129" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The age of chivalry is past. Bores have succeeded to dragons.</quote><quote id="130" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Teach us that wealth is not elegance; that profusion is not magnificence; and that splendour is not beauty. Teach us that taste is a talisman which can do greater wonders than the millions of the loanmonger. Teach us that to vie is not to rival, and to imitate not to invent. Teach us that pretension is a bore. Teach us that wit is excessively good-natured, and, like champagne, not only sparkles, but is sweet. Teach us the vulgarity of malignity. Teach us that envy spoils our complexions, and that anxiety destroys our figure.</quote><quote id="131" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Something unpleasant is coming when men are anxious to tell the truth."</quote><quote id="132" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">If a man be gloomy, let him keep to himself. No one has a right to go croaking about society, or, what is worse, looking as if he stifled grief.</quote><quote id="133" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">A man may speak very well in the House of Commons, and fail very completely in the House of Lords. There are two distinct styles requisite: I intend, in the course of my career, if I have time, to give a specimen of both.</quote><quote id="134" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Nature is more powerful than education; time will develop everything.</quote><quote id="135" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Never apologize for showing feeling. When you do so, you apologize for truth.</quote><quote id="136" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">With words we govern men.</quote><quote id="137" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Read no history: nothing but biography, for that is life without theory. "</quote><quote id="138" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Amusement to an observing mind is study.</quote><quote id="139" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The sense of existence is the greatest happiness.</quote><quote id="140" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Patience is a necessary ingredient of genius.</quote><quote id="141" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The practice of politics in the East may be defined by one word: dissimulation.</quote><quote id="142" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">All is mystery; but he is a slave who will not struggle to penetrate the dark veil.</quote><quote id="143" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">When men are pure, laws are useless; when men are corrupt, laws are broken.</quote><quote id="144" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Debt is the prolific mother of folly and of crime.</quote><quote id="145" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">What we anticipate seldom occurs; what we least expected generally happens.</quote><quote id="146" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The magic of first love is our ignorance that it can ever end.</quote><quote id="147" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Nature has given us two ears but only one mouth.</quote><quote id="148" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Time is the great physician.</quote><quote id="149" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Man is not a rational animal.  He is only truly good or great when he acts from passion.</quote><quote id="150" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Nature has given us two ears but only one mouth.</quote><quote id="151" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"I rather like bad wine," said Mr. Mountchesney; "one gets so bored with good wine."</quote><quote id="152" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">To be conscious that you are ignorant is a great step to knowledge.</quote><quote id="153" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Is it what you call civilization that makes England flourish? Is it the universal development of the faculties of man that has rendered an island, almost unknown to the ancients, the arbiter of the world? Clearly not. It is the inhabitants that have done this. It is an affair of race.… All is race, there is no other truth.</quote><quote id="154" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Duty cannot exist without faith.</quote><quote id="155" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">A majority is always the best repartee.</quote><quote id="156" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">There is no index of character so sure as the voice.</quote><quote id="157" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Duty cannot exist without faith.</quote><quote id="158" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">That fatal drollery called a representative government.</quote><quote id="159" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The view of Jerusalem is the history of the world; it is more, it is the history of earth and of heaven.</quote><quote id="160" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">He was fresh and full of faith that "something would turn up." </quote><quote id="161" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">When little is done, little is said; silence is the mother of truth.</quote><quote id="162" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Everything comes if a man will only wait.</quote><quote id="163" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">We moralise among ruins.</quote><quote id="164" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">London is a modern Babylon.</quote><quote id="165" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">We should never lose an occasion. Opportunity is more powerful even than conquerors and prophets.</quote><quote id="166" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Our morals differ in different counties, in different towns, in different streets, even in different Acts of Parliament. What is moral in London is immoral in Montacute; what is crime among the multitude is only vice among the few.</quote><quote id="167" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">London is a roost for every bird.</quote><quote id="168" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"The world is weary of statesmen whom democracy has degraded into politicians."</quote><quote id="169" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The pursuit of science leads only to the insoluble.</quote><quote id="170" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">When a man fell into his anecdotage, it was a sign for him to retire.</quote><quote id="171" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Books are fatal: they are the curse of the human race. Nine- tenths of existing books are nonsense, and the clever books are the refutation of that nonsense. The greatest misfortune that ever befell man was the invention of printing.</quote><quote id="172" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">I have always thought that every woman should marry, and no man.</quote><quote id="173" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"You know who critics are?— the men who have failed in literature and art. "</quote><quote id="174" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">""My idea of an agreeable person," said Hugo Bohun, "is a person who agrees with me.""</quote><quote id="175" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Had it not been for you, I should have remained what I was when we first met, a prejudiced, narrow-minded being, with contracted sympathies and false knowledge, wasting my life on obsolete trifles, and utterly insensible to the privilege of living in this wondrous age of change and progress.</quote><quote id="176" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Action may not always bring happiness but there is no happiness without action.</quote><quote id="177" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Nothing is going on, but everybody is afraid of something.</quote><quote id="178" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Desperation is sometimes as powerful an inspirer as genius".</quote><quote id="179" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">His Christianity was muscular.</quote><quote id="180" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"But they deserve their wealth," he added, "nobody grudges it to them. I declare when I was eating that truffle, I felt a glow about my heart that, if it were not indigestion, I think must have been gratitude; though that is an article I had not believed in.</quote><quote id="181" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">I have brought myself, by long meditation, to the conviction that a human being with a settled purpose must accomplish it, and that nothing can resist a will that will stake even existence for its fulfilment.</quote><quote id="182" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The more you are talked about the less powerful you are.</quote><quote id="183" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">As a general rule the most successful man in life is the man who has the best information.</quote><quote id="184" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">An insular country, subject to fogs, and with a powerful middle class, requires grave statesmen.</quote><quote id="185" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The Athanasian Creed is the most splendid ecclesiastical lyric ever poured forth by the genius of man.</quote><quote id="186" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">There is no education like adversity.</quote><quote id="187" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Without tact you can learn nothing.</quote><quote id="188" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">As for our majority... one is enough.</quote><quote id="189" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The world is a wheel, and it will all come round right.</quote><quote id="190" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Real politics are the possession and distribution of power.</quote><quote id="191" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">""As for that," said Waldenshare, "sensible men are all of the same religion." 
"Pray, what is that?" inquired the Prince. 
"Sensible men never tell.""</quote><quote id="192" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">There is no gambling like politics.</quote><quote id="193" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">If you are not very clever, you should be conciliatory.</quote><quote id="194" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The sweet simplicity of the three per cents.</quote><quote id="195" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Characters do not change. Opinions alter, but characters are only developed."</quote><quote id="196" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">w:Charles Cavendish Fulke Greville|Charles Greville was the most conceited person with whom I have ever been brought in contact, though I have read Cicero and known Edward Bulwer-Lytton|Bulwer-Lytton.</quote><quote id="197" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Cleanliness and order are not matters of instinct; they are matters of education, and like most great things, you must cultivate a taste for them.</quote><quote id="198" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Great countries are those that produce great people."</quote><quote id="199" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Great services are not cancelled by one act or by one single error."</quote><quote id="200" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">His shortcoming is his long staying.</quote><quote id="201" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">I must follow the people. Am I not their leader?</quote><quote id="202" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Life is too short to be small."</quote><quote id="203" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Many thanks: I shall lose no time in reading it.</quote><quote id="204" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"Moderation is the centre wherein all philosophies, both human and divine, meet."</quote><quote id="205" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">Never complain and never explain.</quote><quote id="206" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">On the education of the people of this country the fate of the country depends.</quote><quote id="207" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"One secret of success in life is for a man to be ready for his opportunity when it comes."</quote><quote id="208" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The best way to become acquainted with a subject is to write a book about it.</quote><quote id="209" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The governments of the present day have to deal not merely with other governments, with emperors, kings and ministers, but also with the secret societies which have everywhere their unscrupulous agents, and can at the last moment upset all the governments' plans.</quote><quote id="210" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">"The greatest good you can do for another is not just share your riches, but to reveal to him his own."</quote><quote id="211" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The most dangerous strategy is to jump a chasm in two leaps.</quote><quote id="212" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The palace is not safe when the cottage is not happy.</quote><quote id="213" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The right honourable gentleman is reminiscent of a poker. The only difference is that a poker gives off the occasional signs of warmth. (On Robert Peel).</quote><quote id="214" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The very phrase 'foreign affairs' makes an Englishman convinced that I am about to treat of subjects with which he has no concern.</quote><quote id="215" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">The worst atrocity in Bulgaria is Gladstone's pamphlet on the subject.</quote><quote id="216" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">When I want to read a novel, I write one.</quote><quote id="217" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">You have heard me accused me of being a flatterer.  It is true.  I am a flatterer.  I have found it useful.  Everyone likes flattery; and when you come to Royalty you should lay it on with a trowel.</quote><quote id="218" author="Benjamin Disraeli" cats="British Jews|British Prime Ministers|English novelists|Essayists" ref="">["On his deathbed, after hearing that Queen Victoria wanted to visit him."] What's the use? She would only want me to take a message to dear Albert.</quote></quotes>