<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="eo|en|nl|pt|af|ca|de|it|hu|uk|cs|pl"><quote id="0" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">It is characteristic of the unlearned that they are forever proposing something which is old, and because it has recently come to their own attention, supposing it to be new.</quote><quote id="1" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">Workmen’s compensation, hours and conditions of labor are cold consolations, if there be no employment.</quote><quote id="2" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">There is no right to strike against the public safety by anybody, anywhere, any time.</quote><quote id="3" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">Parties do not maintain themselves. They are maintained by effort. The government is not self-existent. It is maintained by the effort of those who believe in it. The people of America believe in American institutions, the American form of government and the American method of transacting business.</quote><quote id="4" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">There are racial considerations too grave to be brushed aside for any sentimental reasons. Biological laws tell us that certain divergent people will not mix or blend. The Nordics propagate themselves successfully. With other races, the outcome shows deterioration on both sides. Quality of mind and body suggests that observance of ethnic law is as great a necessity to a nation as immigration law.</quote><quote id="5" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">To live under the American Constitution is the greatest political privilege that was ever accorded to the human race.</quote><quote id="6" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">The Constitution is the sole source and guaranty of national freedom.</quote><quote id="7" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">I believe in the American Constitution. I favor the American system of individual enterprise, and I am opposed to any general extension of government ownership, and control. I believe not only in advocating economy in public expenditure, but in its practical application and actual accomplishment. I believe in a reduction and reform of taxation, and shall continue my efforts in that direction.</quote><quote id="8" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">I favor the policy of economy, not because I wish to save money, but because I wish to save people. &lt;b&gt;The men and women of this country who toil are the ones who bear the cost of the Government. Every dollar that we carelessly waste means that their life will be so much the more meager. &lt;/b&gt;Every dollar that we prudently save means that their life will be so much the more abundant. Economy is idealism in its most practical form.</quote><quote id="9" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">The chief business of the American people is business.</quote><quote id="10" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">What we need is not more Federal government, but better local government.</quote><quote id="11" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">"Governments do not make ideals, but ideals make governments." This is both historically and logically true. "Of course the government can help to sustain ideals and can create institutions through which they can be the better observed, but their source by their very nature is in the people. The people have to bear their own responsibilities. There is no method by which that burden can be shifted to the government. It is not the enactment, but the observance of laws, that creates the character of a nation."</quote><quote id="12" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">If all men are created equal, that is final. If they are endowed with inalienable rights, that is final. If governments derive their just powers from the consent of the governed, that is final.</quote><quote id="13" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">There is far more danger of harm than there is hope of good in any radical changes. </quote><quote id="14" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">We live in an age of science and abounding accumulation of material things. These did not create the Declaration. Our Declaration created them. The things of the spirit come first. Unless we cling to that, all of our material prosperity, overwhelming though it may appear, will turn to a barren scepter in our grasp. If we are to maintain the great heritage bequeathed to us, we must be like minded as the Founders who created. We must not sink into a pagan materialism. We must cultivate the reverence which they had and for the things that are holy. We must follow the spiritual and moral leadership which they showed. We must keep replenished, that they may glow with a more compelling flame, the altar fires before which they worshipped.</quote><quote id="15" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">About the Declaration there is a finality that is exceedingly restful. It is often asserted that the world has made a great deal of progress since 1776 — that we have had new thoughts and new experiences which have given us a great advance of the people of that day and that we may therefore very well discard their conclusions for something more modern. But, that reasoning cannot be applied to the great charter.</quote><quote id="16" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">No advance, no progress can be made beyond these propositions. If anyone wishes to deny their truth or their soundness, the only direction in which he can proceed historically is not forward, but backward toward a time when there was no equality, no rights of the individual, no rule of the people. Those who wish to proceed in that direction cannot lay claim to progress. They are reactionary. Their ideas are not more "modern," but more ancient than those of our Revolutionary ancestors.</quote><quote id="17" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">Mr. Hoover, if you see ten troubles coming down the road, you can be sure that nine will run into the ditch before they reach you and you have to battle with only one of them. </quote><quote id="18" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">I do not choose to run for President in 1928.</quote><quote id="19" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">It was here that I first saw the light of day; here I received my bride, here my dead lie pillowed on the loving breast of our eternal hills.</quote><quote id="20" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">I love Vermont because of her hills and valleys, her scenery and invigorating climate, but most of all because of her indomitable people. They are a race of pioneers who have almost beggared themselves to serve others. If the spirit of liberty should vanish in other parts of the Union, and support of our institutions should languish, it could all be replenished from the generous store held by the people of this brave little state of Vermont.</quote><quote id="21" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">It is not industry, but idleness, that is degrading.</quote><quote id="22" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">In other periods of depression it has always been possible to see some things which were solid and upon which you could base hope, but as I look about, I now see nothing to give ground for hope — nothing of man. But there is still religion, which is the same yesterday, today, and forever. That continues as a solid basis for hope and courage.</quote><quote id="23" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">"I sometimes wish that people would put a little more emphasis on the observance of the law than they do on its enforcement." It is a maxim of our institutions, that the government does not make the people, but the people make the government.</quote><quote id="24" author="Calvin Coolidge" cats="1930s deaths|Autobiographers|United States Presidents" ref="">Nothing in the world can take the place of persistence. Talent will not; nothing is more common than unsuccessful men with talent. Genius will not; unrewarded genius is almost a proverb. Education will not; the world is full of educated derelicts. Persistence and determination alone are omnipotent. The slogan "press on" has solved and always will solve the problems of the human race.</quote></quotes>