<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="el|en|zh|ca|it|hy|cs|et|az|es|ru|nl|nn|no|tr|li|lt|ro|pl|bg|hr|de|hu|fa|bs|da|he|ka|pt|sr|sk|uk|sl"><quote id="0" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Love is not a feeling to pass away
Like the balmy breath of a Summer's day.......
Love is not a passion of earthly mould
As a thirst for honour, or fame, or gold</quote><quote id="1" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"Mr. Augustus Minns was a bachelor, of about forty as he said — of about eight-and-forty as his friends said." He was always exceedingly clean, precise, and tidy: perhaps somewhat priggish, and the most retiring man in the world.</quote><quote id="2" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">There were two classes of created objects which he held in the deepest and most unmingled horror: they were, dogs and children. "He was not unamiable, but he could at any time have viewed the execution of a dog, or the assassination of an infant, with the liveliest satisfaction. Their habits were at variance with his love of order; and his love of order, was as powerful as his love of life."</quote><quote id="3" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">If any one were to ask me what in my opinion was the dullest and most stupid spot on the face of the Earth, I should decidedly say Chelmsford.</quote><quote id="4" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"To conceal anything from those to whom I am attached, is not in my nature. I can never close my lips where I have opened my heart."</quote><quote id="5" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">The bright old day now dawns again; the cry runs through the the land,
In England there shall be dear bread—in Ireland, sword and brand;
And poverty, and ignorance, shall swell the rich and grand,
So, rally round the rulers with the gentle iron hand,
Of the fine old English Tory days;
Hail to the coming time!</quote><quote id="6" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Wherever religion is resorted to as a strong drink, and as an escape from the dull, monotonous round of home, those of its ministers who pepper the highest will be the surest to please. They who strew the Eternal Path with the greatest amount of brimstone, and who most ruthlessly tread down the flowers and leaves that grow by the wayside, will be voted the most righteous; and they who enlarge with the greatest pertinacity on the difficulty of getting into heaven will be considered, by all true believers, certain of going there: though it would be hard to say by what process of reasoning this conclusion is arrived at.</quote><quote id="7" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">I am quite serious when I say that I do not believe there are, on the whole earth besides, so many intensified bores as in these United States. No man can form an adequate idea of the real meaning of the word, without coming here.</quote><quote id="8" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">O let us love our occupations,
Bless the squire and his relations,
Live upon our daily rations,
And always know our proper stations.</quote><quote id="9" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"La difficulté d'écrire l'anglais m'est extrêmement ennuyeuse. Ah, mon Dieu ! si l'on pouvait toujours écrire cette belle langue de France!"</quote><quote id="10" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">It was a good thing to have a couple of thousand people all rigid and frozen together, in the palm of one's hand.</quote><quote id="11" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">(Carmine Crocco) In such a crowd, so numerous and composed of such heterogeneous elements, it might have appeared almost absurd to look for discipline; but perfect discipline there was, for, whatever his other qualities might be, Crocco most undoubtedly was a "ruler of men". His word in that band was law, and the punishment of disaffection was death.</quote><quote id="12" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">I have known a vast quantity of nonsense talked about bad men not looking you in the face.  Don't trust that conventional idea.  Dishonesty will stare honesty out of countenance, any day in the week, if there is anything to be got by it.</quote><quote id="13" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Resisting the slow touch of a frozen finger tracing out my spine.</quote><quote id="14" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">The system here, is rigid, strict, and hopeless solitary confinement... I believe that very few men are capable of estimating the immense amount of torture and agony which this dreadful punishment, prolonged for years, inflicts upon the sufferers... I hold this slow and daily tampering with the mysteries of the brain, to be immeasurably worse than any torture of the body: and because its ghastly signs and tokens are not so palpable to the eye and sense of touch as scars upon the flesh; because its wounds are not upon the surface, and it extorts few cries that human ears can hear; therefore I the more denounce it, as a secret punishment which slumbering humanity is not roused up to stay</quote><quote id="15" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">The dignity of his office is never impaired by the absence of efforts on his part to maintain it.</quote><quote id="16" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">He is not, as he forcibly remarks, ‘one of those fortunate men who, if they were to dive under one side of a barge stark–naked, would come up on the other with a new suit of clothes on, and a ticket for soup in the waistcoat–pocket:’ neither is he one of those, whose spirit has been broken beyond redemption by misfortune and want. He is just one of the careless, good–for–nothing, happy fellows, who float, cork–like, on the surface, for the world to play at hockey with: knocked here, and there, and everywhere: now to the right, then to the left, again up in the air, and anon to the bottom, but always reappearing and bounding with the stream buoyantly and merrily along.</quote><quote id="17" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">I used to sit, think, think, thinking, till I felt as lonesome as a kitten in a wash–house copper with the lid on.</quote><quote id="18" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"The civility which money will purchase, is rarely extended to those who have none."</quote><quote id="19" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Grief never mended no broken bones, and as good people’s wery scarce, what I says is, make the most on ’em.</quote><quote id="20" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"Reflect upon your present blessings — of which every man has many — not on your past misfortunes, of which all men have some."</quote><quote id="21" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Minerva House ... was "a finishing establishment for young ladies," where some twenty girls of the ages from thirteen to nineteen inclusive, acquired a smattering of everything and a knowledge of nothing.</quote><quote id="22" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">What is the odds so long as the fire of soul is kindled at the taper of conwiviality, and the wing of friendship never moults a feather! What is the odds so long as the spirit is expanded by means of rosy wine, and the present moment is the least happiest of our existence!</quote><quote id="23" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">She's the ornament of her sex.</quote><quote id="24" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Fan the sinking flame of hilarity with the wing of friendship; and pass the rosy wine.</quote><quote id="25" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Send forth the child and childish man together, and blush for the pride that libels our own old happy state, and gives its title to an ugly and distorted image.</quote><quote id="26" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">The very dogs were all asleep, and the flies, drunk with moist sugar in the grocer’s shop, forgot their wings and briskness, and baked to death in dusty corners of the window.</quote><quote id="27" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">In mind, she was of a strong and vigorous turn, having from her earliest youth devoted herself with uncommon ardour to the study of the law; not wasting her speculations upon its eagle flights, which are rare, but tracing it attentively through all the slippery and eel-like crawlings in which it commonly pursues its way.</quote><quote id="28" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Under an accumulation of staggerers, no man can be considered a free agent. No man knocks himself down; if his destiny knocks him down, his destiny must pick him up again.</quote><quote id="29" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">It was a maxim with Mr. Brass that the habit of paying compliments kept a man’s tongue oiled without any expense; and that, as that useful member ought never to grow rusty or creak in turning on its hinges in the case of a practitioner of the law, in whom it should be always glib and easy, he lost few opportunities of improving himself by the utterance of handsome speeches and eulogistic expressions.</quote><quote id="30" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">In love of home, the love of country has its rise.</quote><quote id="31" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">That vague kind of penitence which holidays awaken next morning.</quote><quote id="32" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"If there were no bad people, there would be no good lawyers."</quote><quote id="33" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"Did you ever taste beer?" "I had a sip of it once," said the small servant. "Here's a state of things!" cried Mr Swiveller, raising his eyes to the ceiling. "She "never" tasted it — it can't be tasted in a sip!"</quote><quote id="34" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">You will not have forgotten that it was a maxim with Foxey — our revered father, gentlemen — "Always suspect everybody." That's the maxim to go through life with!</quote><quote id="35" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">He’s tough, ma’am,—tough is J. B.; tough and devilish sly.</quote><quote id="36" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"I want to know what it says," he answered, looking steadily in her face. "The sea Floy, what is it that it keeps on saying?"</quote><quote id="37" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"Wal'r, my boy," replied the Captain, "in the Proverbs of Solomon you will find the following words, 'May we never want a friend in need, nor a bottle to give him!' When found, make a note of."</quote><quote id="38" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Cows are my passion.</quote><quote id="39" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">The bearings of this observation lays in the application on it.</quote><quote id="40" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">If you could see my legs when I take my boots off, you'd form some idea of what unrequited affection is.</quote><quote id="41" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">…vices are sometimes only virtues carried to excess!</quote><quote id="42" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Jarndyce and Jarndyce drones on. This scarecrow of a suit, has, in course of time, become so complicated that no man alive knows what it means. The parties to it understand it least; but it has been observed that no two Chancery lawyers can talk about it for five minutes, without coming to total disagreement as to all the premises.</quote><quote id="43" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">This is the Court of Chancery, which has its decaying houses and its blighted lands in every shire, which has its worn-out lunatic in every madhouse and its dead in every churchyard, which has its ruined suitor with his slipshod heels and threadbare dress borrowing and begging through the round of every man's acquaintance, which gives to monied might the means abundantly of wearying out the right, which so exhausts finances, patience, courage, hope, so overthrows the brain and breaks the heart, that there is not an honourable man among its practitioners who would not give--who does not often give--the warning, "Suffer any wrong that can be done you rather than come here!"</quote><quote id="44" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">[T]he evil of it is that it is a world wrapped up in too much jeweller’s cotton and fine wool, and cannot hear the rushing of the larger worlds, and cannot see them as they circle round the sun. It is a deadened world, and its growth is sometimes unhealthy for want of air.</quote><quote id="45" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">He is a gentleman of strict conscience, disdainful of all littleness and meanness and ready on the shortest notice to die any death you may please to mention rather than give occasion for the least impeachment of his integrity.  He is an honourable, obstinate, truthful, high-spirited, intensely prejudiced, perfectly unreasonable man.</quote><quote id="46" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"Oh, dear no, miss," he said. "This is a London particular." I had never heard of such a thing. "A fog, miss," said the young gentleman. "Oh, indeed!" said I.</quote><quote id="47" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">I expect a judgment. Shortly.</quote><quote id="48" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">“She means well,” said Mr Jarndyce, hastily. “The wind’s in the east.” “It was in the north, sir, as we came down,” observed Richard. “My dear Rick,” said Mr Jarndyce, poking the fire, “I’ll take an oath it’s either in the east, or going to be. I am always conscious of an uncomfortable sensation now and then when the wind is blowing in the east.”</quote><quote id="49" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">It is said that the children of the very poor are not brought up, but dragged up.</quote><quote id="50" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">I don’t feel any vulgar gratitude to you. I almost feel as if you ought to be grateful to me, for giving you the opportunity of enjoying the luxury of generosity. I know you like it. For anything I can tell, I may have come into the world expressly for the purpose of increasing your stock of happiness.</quote><quote id="51" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">I only ask to be free. The butterflies are free. Mankind will surely not deny to Harold Skimpole what it concedes to the butterflies!</quote><quote id="52" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Not to put too fine a point upon it.</quote><quote id="53" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">He wos wery good to me, he wos!</quote><quote id="54" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">He had a cane, he had an eye-glass, he had a snuff-box, he had rings, he had wristbands, he had everything but any touch of nature; he was not like youth, he was not like age, he was not like anything in the world but a model of deportment.</quote><quote id="55" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Mr. Chadband is a large yellow man, with a fat smile, and a general appearance of having a good deal of train oil in his system.</quote><quote id="56" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">What is peace? Is it war? No. Is it strife? No. Is it lovely, and gentle, and beautiful, and pleasant, and serene, and joyful? Oh, yes! Therefore, my friends, I wish for peace, upon you and upon yours.</quote><quote id="57" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">You are a human boy, my young friend. A human boy. O glorious to be a human boy!... O running stream of sparkling joy To be a soaring human boy!</quote><quote id="58" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">'Don't you be afraid of hurting the boy,' he says.</quote><quote id="59" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">It’s my old girl that advises. She has the head. But I never own to it before her. Discipline must be maintained.</quote><quote id="60" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">It is a melancholy truth that even great men have their poor relations.</quote><quote id="61" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Never have a Mission, my dear child.</quote><quote id="62" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Take care, while you are young, that you can think in those days, 'I never whitened a hair of her dear head, I never marked a sorrowful line in her face!' For of all the many things that you can think when you are a man, you had better have that by you, Woolwich!</quote><quote id="63" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">The one great principle of the English law is, to make business for itself.</quote><quote id="64" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Dead, your Majesty. Dead, my lords and gentlemen. Dead, Right Reverends and Wrong Reverends of every order. Dead, men and women, born with Heavenly compassion in your hearts. And dying thus around us every day.</quote><quote id="65" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Your sex have such a surprising animosity against one another when you do differ.</quote><quote id="66" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">We are not rich in the bank, but we have always prospered and we have quite enough. I never walk out with my husband but I hear the people bless him. I never lie down at night, but I know that in the course of that day he has alleviated pain and soothed some fellow creature in the time of need. Is not this to be rich?</quote><quote id="67" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Now, what I want is, Facts. Teach these boys and girls nothing but Facts. Facts alone are wanted in life.  Plant nothing else, and root out everything else. You can only form the minds of reasoning animals upon Facts: nothing else will ever be of any service to them. This is the principle on which I bring up my own children, and this is the principle on which I bring up these children. Stick to Facts, sir!</quote><quote id="68" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Oh my friends, the down-trodden operatives of Coketown! Oh my friends and fellow-countrymen, the slaves of an ironhanded and a grinding despotism! Oh my friends and fellow-sufferers, and fellow-workmen, and fellow-men! I tell you that the hour is come, when we must rally round one another as One united power, and crumble into dust the oppressors that too long have battened upon the plunder of our families, upon the sweat of our brows, upon the labour of our hands, upon the strength of our sinews, upon the God-created glorious rights of Humanity, and upon the holy and eternal privileges of Brotherhood!</quote><quote id="69" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">There is a wisdom of the Head, and ... there is a wisdom of the Heart.</quote><quote id="70" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">A prison taint was on everything there. The imprisoned air, the imprisoned light, the imprisoned damps, the imprisoned men, were all deteriorated by confinement. As the captive men were faded and haggard, so the iron was rusty, the stone was slimy, the wood was rotten, the air was faint, the light was dim. Like a well, like a vault, like a tomb, the prison had no knowledge of the brightness outside; and would have kept its polluted atmosphere intact, in one of the spice islands of the Indian Ocean.</quote><quote id="71" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">I am the only child of parents who weighed, measured, and priced everything; for whom what could not be weighed, measured, and priced, had no existence.</quote><quote id="72" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">The Circumlocution Office was (as everybody knows without being told) the most important Department under Government. No public business of any kind could possibly be done at any time without the acquiescence of the Circumlocution Office. Its finger was in the largest public pie, and in the smallest public tart. It was equally impossible to do the plainest right and to undo the plainest wrong without the express authority of the Circumlocution Office.</quote><quote id="73" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Whatever was required to be done, the Circumlocution Office was beforehand with all the public departments in the art of perceiving — HOW NOT TO DO IT.</quote><quote id="74" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">The Barnacles were a very high family, and a very large family.  They were dispersed all over the public offices, and held all sorts of public places.  Either the nation was under a load of obligation to the Barnacles, or the Barnacles were under a load of obligation to the nation.  It was not quite unanimously settled which; the Barnacles having their opinion, the nation theirs.</quote><quote id="75" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">A person who can't pay, gets another person who can't pay, to guarantee that he can pay.  Like a person with two wooden legs getting another person with two wooden legs, to guarantee that he has got two natural legs. It don't make either of them able to do a walking match.</quote><quote id="76" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">I revere the memory of Mr. F. as an estimable man and most indulgent husband, only necessary to mention Asparagus and it appeared or to hint at any little delicate thing to drink and it came like magic in a pint bottle; it was not ecstasy but it was comfort.</quote><quote id="77" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"Papa is a preferable mode of address," observed Mrs General. "Father is rather vulgar, my dear. The word Papa, besides, gives a pretty form to the lips. Papa, potatoes, poultry, prunes, and prism are all very good words for the lips: especially prunes and prism. You will find it serviceable, in the formation of a demeanour, if you sometimes say to yourself in company — on entering a room, for instance — Papa, potatoes, poultry, prunes and prism, prunes and prism.</quote><quote id="78" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Whatever was required to be done, the Circumlocution Office was beforehand with all the public departments in the art of perceiving HOW NOT TO DO IT.</quote><quote id="79" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"Once a gentleman, and always a gentleman."</quote><quote id="80" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Now, I ain't alone, as you may think I am. There's a young man hid with me, in comparison with which young man I am a angel. That young man hears the words I speak. That young man has a secret way pecooliar to himself of getting at a boy, and at his heart, and at his liver. It is in wain for a boy to attempt to hide himself from that young man. A boy may lock his door, may be warm in bed, may tuck himself up, may draw the clothes over his head, may think himself comfortable and safe, but that young man will softly creep and creep his way to him and tear him open.</quote><quote id="81" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Mrs. Joe was a very clean housekeeper, but had an exquisite art of making her cleanliness more uncomfortable and unacceptable than the dirt itself. Cleanliness is next to Godliness, and some people do the same by religion.</quote><quote id="82" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">In the little world in which children have their existence whosoever brings them up, there is nothing so finely perceived and so finely felt, as injustice.  It may be only small injustice that the child can be exposed to; but the child is small, and its world is small, and its rocking-horse stands as many hands high, according to scale, as a big-boned Irish hunter.</quote><quote id="83" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">That was a memorable day to me, for it made great changes in me.  But, it is the same with any life.  Imagine one selected day struck out of it, and think how different it's course would have been.  Pause you who read this, and think for the moment of the long chain of iron or gold, of thorns or flowers, that would never have bound you, but for the formation of the first link on one memorable day.</quote><quote id="84" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">I had been to see "Macbeth" at the theatre a night or two before and she reminded me of the faces rising out of the witches' cauldron.</quote><quote id="85" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">My guiding star always is, Get hold of portable property.</quote><quote id="86" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Throughout life, our worst weaknesses and meannesses are usually committed for the sake of the people we most despise.</quote><quote id="87" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"Pip, dear old chap, life is made of ever so many partings welded together..."</quote><quote id="88" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">All the truth of my position came flashing on me; and its disappointments, dangers, disgraces, consequences of all kinds, rushed in in such a multitude that I was borne down by them and had to struggle for every breath I drew.</quote><quote id="89" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"Take nothing on its looks; take everything on evidence. There's no better rule."</quote><quote id="90" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Compeyson's business was the swindling, hand writing forging, stolen bank-note passing, and such-like.  All sorts of traps as Compeyson could set with his head, and keep his own legs out of and get the profits from and let another man in for, was Compeyson's business.  He'd no more heart than a iron file he was as cold as death, and he had the head of the Devil afore mentioned.</quote><quote id="91" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"You are part of my existence, part of myself. You have been in every line I have ever read, since I first came here, the rough common boys whose poor heart you wounded even then. You have been in every prospect I have ever seen since - on the river, on the sails of the ships, on the marshes, in the clouds, in the light, in the darkness, in the wind, in the woods, in the sea, in the streets. You have been the embodiment of every graceful fancy that my mind has ever become acquainted with. The stones of which the strongest London buildings are made, are not more real, or more impossible to be displaced by your hands, than your presence and influence have been to me, there and everywhere, and will be. Estella, to the last hour of my life, you cannot choose but remain part of my character, part of the little good in me, part of the evil. But, in this separation I associate you only with the good, and I will faithfully hold you to that always, for you must have done me far more good than harm, let me feel now what sharp distress I may. Oh, God bless you, God forgive you!"</quote><quote id="92" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">'suffering has been stronger than all other teaching, and has taught me to understand what your heart used to be. I have been bent and broken, but - I hope - into a better shape.'</quote><quote id="93" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Money and goods are certainly the best of references.</quote><quote id="94" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">Professionally he declines and falls, and as a friend he drops into poetry.</quote><quote id="95" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">I want to be something so much worthier than the doll in the doll's house.</quote><quote id="96" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">I don't care whether I am a Minx or a Sphinx.</quote><quote id="97" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">"And if it's proud to have a heart that never hardens, and a temper that never tires, and a touch that never hurts," Miss Jenny struck in, flushed, "she is proud."</quote><quote id="98" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">That's the state to live and die in!...R-r-rich!</quote><quote id="99" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">We must scrunch or be scrunched.</quote><quote id="100" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">'No one is useless in this world,' retorted the Secretary, 'who lightens the burden of it for any one else.'</quote><quote id="101" author="Charles Dickens" cats="1870s deaths|Activists|English novelists|English people" ref="">'Who will wonder that Barbara had a headache, or that Barbara's mother was disposed to be cross, or that she slightly underrated Astley's, and thought the clown was older than they had taken him to be last night? Kit was not surprised to hear her say so--not he. He had already had a misgiving that the inconstant actors in that dazzling vision had been doing the same thing the night before last, and would do it again that night, and the next, and for weeks and months to come, though he would not be there. Such is the difference between yesterday and today. We are all going to the play, or coming home from it.'</quote></quotes>