<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="bg|tr|it|en|es|fi|az|pl"><quote id="0" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">I have the easiest job in Hollywood, because I get paid to be me.  What's the role?  A milkman?  'Hey, I'm a milkman.  Here's your milk.' 'Cut.  Print.'</quote><quote id="1" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">I play a lot of those parts, and it's a chicken-and-egg thing. I don't know whether you get scary because you play those parts or did you get those parts because you were scary? But I do believe that there's a very close connection to what's scary and what's funny. So I think if you have the ability to do one, you might have the ability to do the other.</quote><quote id="2" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">Well, I don't play heroes obviously. I never played the guy who gets the girl. It might be interesting to do a part where I was a father in a functional family.</quote><quote id="3" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">I won't retire. When you're an actor, you're forced to retire every few months. John Gielgud was 96 when he died, and he was working. It's good to work, whatever it is that keeps you interested. I would like to do that, I would like to keep going. I don't have kids, and I don't have hobbies. I don't particularly like to travel. If you're an actor, you have to travel anyway.</quote><quote id="4" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">I look for good possibilities in movies. I don't look for perfection.</quote><quote id="5" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">I'm not a big fan of other people's punctuation. When I read a script I've got a sort of automatic eraser. I don't see punctuation or capitals or instructions. I want to decide when the sentence is over. Who's to say when a sentence ends and the other one begins? Sometimes it begins in the middle of the next sentence. </quote><quote id="6" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">I believe in saving money. I believe in having a house. I believe in keeping things clean. I believe in exercising. Slow and steady is a very good thing for me. It works for me.</quote><quote id="7" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">Careers are not often as chosen as people think they are. People talk to me about my choices. I don't make choices, hardly. Things happen, and you say yes or no - usually 'yes', because it's always better to do something. What's the choice? Somebody will say, 'Don't do that part, you don't need to do that part.' And I'll say, 'Why not? What am I going to do? Sit around the house? I'd much rather go to work, and see actors, and have fun.</quote><quote id="8" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">I think it's sort of a compliment. Jay Mohr does it in front of me all the time. I've got another friend who does me on his answering machine. When I call him, I hear myself.</quote><quote id="9" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">I have a theory, that there is a terrific link between what is funny and what is scary. I think there is a very close connection between what frightens people and what makes them laugh. Laughter is a kind of nervousness. Animals don't laugh. Smiling is, anthropologists agree, directly linked to the baring of the teeth.</quote><quote id="10" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">I think that my strength as a villain is that the people watching me know that Chris knows that he's in a movie. He's playing. He's having fun. He's going bang, bang. You know, "What's that?"</quote><quote id="11" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">It's a natural aspect of the marketplace. It's always been that way in storytelling. The guy who was good at playing the lover plays the lover, the funny guy gets the comic role. Movies are so expensive, when they put them together they want to have a couple of solid blocks in what they're building. I accept that. In theater, though, I tend to look for other things, I think I tend to be best in comedy. </quote><quote id="12" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">I'm a better actor now than I ever was, I wish I could have hurried that up, but there's no way. Anyway, I always wanted to be around for a long time. Like a European actor, I hope I live a long time and that I'm acting until I finish.</quote><quote id="13" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">I'm very nervous when I work in a film and very relaxed before a live audience. I like theater because it's more of an actor's medium. You can control your performance. In film you depend on the director to watch out for your ass, but in the theater you can take care of yourself. </quote><quote id="14" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">Walken is fascinating because he has a complex and fearless process -- each take is wildly different and he does that until he finds the one that is true perfection.</quote><quote id="15" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">Everybody always wants to work with Christopher Walken. I think he's the most interesting actor working today. His choices are always dangerous, which makes for interesting work. You can watch him eat a bowl of cereal and you'd be riveted because he's just unpredictable.</quote><quote id="16" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">{{imdb name|0000686}}</quote><quote id="17" author="Christopher Walken" cats="American actors|Living people" ref="">{{tv.com person|65260}}</quote></quotes>