<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="bg|pt|it|hu|en|es|cs|pl"><quote id="0" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">This has given me a feeling of confidence, which I might not have had otherwise.</quote><quote id="1" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">I'm lucky enough to have a job that I love, and a relatively down-to-earth life. [http://www.flixster.com/actor/daniel-radcliffe/daniel-radcliffe-quotes]</quote><quote id="2" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">It's not so much that they don't want me to grow up. It's that they're annoyed that I'm growing up adjusted. They'd much rather I was growing up and going wild and crashing cars. [http://www.flixster.com/actor/daniel-radcliffe/daniel-radcliffe-quotes]</quote><quote id="3" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">(on way to relax) “I just like to lock my self in a small room and listen to music and watch films all day!” [http://dan-radcliffe.net/index.php/information/facts-favorites/]</quote><quote id="4" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">What everybody would love to see is me having ditched school and then just going wild. That's what I'm determined not to give them. [http://www.flixster.com/actor/daniel-radcliffe/daniel-radcliffe-quotes]</quote><quote id="5" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">When I go back to school everyone asks a lot of questions. Then, after about a week, when I've answered everything, we get back to normal. I've never been one of the cool people at school, but then again, I don't get the people who are cool. It's not that I don't like them, it's just that they don't interest me.</quote><quote id="6" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">It was very emotional, actually. In the front of the book I wrote something Anton Chekhov wrote to the woman he ended up spending the rest of his life with: "Hello, the last page of my life." Which I thought was very appropriate.</quote><quote id="7" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">I don't understand girls, but I'm slowly learning. [http://www.flixster.com/actor/daniel-radcliffe/daniel-radcliffe-quotes]</quote><quote id="8" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">They are a pretty amazing bunch... some people have been here for 18 hours, which is... unbelievable! I don't think I would ever wait 18 hours on something, not even an organ, that I needed. I don't think I would wait that long, I would be like, oh fine, never mind...</quote><quote id="9" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">...I suppose that the image people have of me is one that's quite talkative, because in interviews and that you can sometimes get nervous, and the thing when you meet people... I tend to be quite chatty just because that's just something I do. But in terms of Maps' character, I'm like him in that I'm perfectly happy in my own company. And I'm probably happiest when I'm being quiet.</quote><quote id="10" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">I'm really happy when I meet a beautiful girl with whom I can have a good conversation. And I can feel attracted to her after a while, but that's not love! It takes time to develop an intense feeling like love. When you start a relationship with someone, it means you have to work hard. Love is a gift that needs to be looked after and cared for.</quote><quote id="11" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">Some people think I’m gay when I meet them, which I think is awesome. It’s always good to keep them guessing. I don’t go on any blogs or chats or anything, but my friends are demons for them, and apparently someone said: ‘Daniel Radcliffe is gay. He’s got a gay face!’ I really don’t know what a gay face is!</quote><quote id="12" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">I would hate to be accused of having got through life just by luck - I think you do create your own destiny. My mum and Dad believe in fate. I see coincidences but not a predestined pattern. If it's just about fate, then you become complacent and expect things to come your way. I like being challenged. Even when you're doing really intense, dramatic scenes that take so much out of you it's still really fun and energizing. Acting makes you feel so alive.</quote><quote id="13" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">Invisibility. That would be so cool just to go anywhere without people seeing you. You could sneak into rock concerts and films and stuff. And I'd like to have Hagrid's three-head dog, because then nobody would try to fight me. I think I'd love to be a wizard in Harry's world, even though you have to face a lot of danger.</quote><quote id="14" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">When I get into trouble at school I'd like to take an invisibility cloak, drape it over me and sneak out the door. Or I'd like to have a 3-headed-dog because then no one would argue with me. [http://www.danradcliffe.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=23&amp;Itemid=28]</quote><quote id="15" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">In the bathtub. My dad came in and said, "Guess who they want to play Harry Potter?" I think I said the name of another actor, because I was sure it wasn't me. Then he said, "No, it's you," and I started to cry with joy. That night, I woke up at 2 in the morning and woke up mom and dad and asked, "Am I dreaming? Will I really play Harry Potter?"</quote><quote id="16" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">I like science and I love gym. Oh, and I like art, but I'm really bad at it. I'm just a terrible drawer. I can't draw a circle. Even with a ruler, I can't draw a straight line.</quote><quote id="17" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">All it takes is for me to be seen chatting up a girl for [tabloids] to, you know, make up some crappy headline about me being a sex rat or whatever they call it.</quote><quote id="18" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">I might like to be an actor, but there are loads of other things I'm interested in as well, like music and writing and sports. I want to keep my options open.</quote><quote id="19" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">Everyone on the set has a mobile phone, and I found by pushing a few buttons, they could be programmed into different languages. I fixed Robbie's (Coltrane) to speak in Turkish.</quote><quote id="20" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">Ron's funnier than Robin Williams. The hard thing is not to laugh when the camera is rolling.</quote><quote id="21" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">I'm the only kid in the world who doesn't want an eighth Harry Potter book.</quote><quote id="22" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">(upon seeing the movie) I'm a bit nervous about whether people will like it, but I've seen it, and I'm sure they will. It's really good - it's quite scary, it's quite emotional. Even I cried and I don't cry easily! I cried at the end credits when my name came up, and I was, like, Oh my God! I can't believe that's my name! I've met so many people since we started filming and it's been wonderful. I've progressed so far and changed so much since the beginning. It's been like a real journey. </quote><quote id="23" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">Fans are really important for me. And if they take pains to write me, it's the minimum that I answer myself.</quote><quote id="24" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">I'm thrilled of the acceptance I get abroad. The people are so hearty, warm and grateful and I feel privileged having seen so many countries and some of the greatest monuments </quote><quote id="25" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">In a way, ... growing up like this with Harry makes it easier to act in each of the films, because I've been through all the stuff that he's going through, like the hormones, relatively recently. So it's quite fresh in my mind. And then I suppose it's been made easier by the fact I've been playing Harry Potter since I was 12. You get to know the character so well that it makes it easier to act in the long run.</quote><quote id="26" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">It's good to be back filming. I just put on my glasses and then I became Harry again. [http://www.associatedcontent.com/article/274090/daniel_radcliffe_quotes_harry_potter.html]</quote><quote id="27" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">I would consider doing any part as long as the script is good and the film has an interesting director. [http://www.flixster.com/actor/daniel-radcliffe/daniel-radcliffe-quotes]</quote><quote id="28" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">Stage is much more intimidating than going before the cameras, because you can really screw up, and can't do a retake. [http://www.flixster.com/actor/daniel-radcliffe/daniel-radcliffe-quotes]</quote><quote id="29" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">Me and Harry (Potter) are not very good with women. I've got better now. But I think any man whoever says he has never had an awkward moment with a girl is a liar. He's either a liar or he's delusional.</quote><quote id="30" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">I once had a friend call me (Harry) by accident. If there's another person in the room called Harry and somebody shouts their name I do respond slightly, which is embarrassing. But no one has ever said it in the throws of passion. That would be the end of that session. Go now! [http://www.movietome.com/people/86509/daniel-radcliffe/trivia.html]</quote><quote id="31" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">I support Fulham because I live two minutes away from the ground, but I'm not a massive football fan. Cricket is the game I'm obsessed with, to be honest, and also despair of. [http://www.movietome.com/people/86509/daniel-radcliffe/trivia.html]</quote><quote id="32" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">(about Math) Too many little numbers on one page! [http://www.movietome.com/people/86509/daniel-radcliffe/trivia.html]</quote><quote id="33" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">When I go back to school everyone asks a lot of questions. Then, after about a week, when I've answered everything, we get back to normal [http://www.movietome.com/people/86509/daniel-radcliffe/trivia.html]</quote><quote id="34" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">After I read a script about three times, it sinks into my head. With Harry Potter, it took about six times because it was a lot bigger. [http://www.associatedcontent.com/article/274090/daniel_radcliffe_quotes_harry_potter.html]</quote><quote id="35" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">(On considering himself as a heartthrob) Personally I can't see it, but if other people can, fine. Cool! [http://www.movietome.com/people/86509/daniel-radcliffe/trivia.html]</quote><quote id="36" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">The one piece of advice I would give to any actor is, if you want to go out on the street without being recognised, without even being looked at, go out with a 6ft 8in beautiful transsexual. No one gives you a second glance. Especially when you're 5ft 5in.</quote><quote id="37" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">There have been people who have tried to exploit me. You get chancers out there who just want to make a quick buck, but as long as you tune into them and who they are ... The best thing I've learned is, if you're going out, never go out alone - you leave yourself vulnerable. If you've got someone else there you trust, they can say, be wary of that person. I probably used to be too trusting of people.</quote><quote id="38" author="Daniel Radcliffe" cats="British Jews|British actors|English people|Living people" ref="">I'm very proud of being Jewish. It means I have a good work ethic, and you get Jewish humour and you're allowed to tell Jewish jokes.</quote></quotes>