<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="bg|is|tr|en|id|es|he"><quote id="0" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">A sense of humor is a measurement of the extent to which we realize that we are trapped in a world almost totally devoid of reason. Laughter is how we express the anxiety we feel at this knowledge.</quote><quote id="1" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">The problem is, when Oprah lost all that weight, her head didn't get any smaller. And so she looks kind of like a person carrying a balloon.</quote><quote id="2" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">But I do think we need to explore the commitment problem, which has caused many women to mistakenly conclude that men, as a group, have the emotional maturity of hamsters . This is not the case. A hamster is MUCH more capable of making a lasting commitment to a woman, especially if she gives it those little food pellets. Whereas a guy, in a relationship, will consume the pellets of companionship, and he will run on the exercise wheel of lust; but as soon as he senses that the door of commitment is about to close and trap him in the wire cage of true intimacy, he'll squirm out, scamper across the kitchen floor of uncertainty and hide under the refrigerator of Non-Readiness.</quote><quote id="3" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">I think Superman should go on the Larry King show and announce that he would come back to life if people in all 50 states wanted him to.</quote><quote id="4" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">As a child, I was more afraid of tetanus shots than, for example, Dracula.</quote><quote id="5" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">It is a scientific fact that your body will not absorb cholesterol if you take it from another person's plate.</quote><quote id="6" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">What, exactly, is the Internet?  Basically it is a global network exchanging digitized data in such a way that any computer, anywhere, that is equipped with a device called a "modem" can make a noise like a duck choking on a kazoo.</quote><quote id="7" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">Of course it’s possible that there really ISN’T any shadow government. The whole thing could be a phony story that was fed to The Washington Post to mislead our enemies. As you recall, Secretary of Defense Donald Rumsfeld recently admitted that the Pentagon had set up an office-officially named "The Office of Disinformation"-that was supposed to put out false statements to the media, thus throwing our enemies off the track. For example, if we were getting ready to attack Iraq, officials of the Office of Disinformation would hold a press conference and state: "Well, we’re certainly not going to attack Iraq!" The news media would report this, and Iraq would relax. France, meanwhile, would surrender.</quote><quote id="8" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">Winter's here, and you feel lousy: You're coughing and sneezing; your muscles ache; your nose is an active mucus volcano. These symptoms -- so familiar at this time of year -- can mean only one thing: Tiny fanged snails are eating your brain.</quote><quote id="9" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">But this should serve as a reminder to brides of the importance of discouraging reception guests from discharging their firearms unless they have a good reason, such as the band vocalist attempting to perform "I Will Always Love You" in the official Whitney Houston Diarrhea of the Vowels version ("And IIIIIIeeeeeIIIIIIIII, will alwaaaaays love yoooooeeeeeeeooooooouuuuueeeeeeeeeoooooo" BANG)</quote><quote id="10" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">The transportation bill had over $5 billion worth of special local projects and favors attached to it, lamprey-like, by various congresspersons. But this is good, because these projects will CREATE JOBS. See, when the GOVERNMENT spends money, it creates jobs; whereas when the money is left in the hands of  TAXPAYERS, God only knows what they do with it. Bake it into pies, probably. Anything to avoid creating jobs.</quote><quote id="11" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">The only really good place to buy lumber is at a store where the lumber has already been cut and attached together in the form of furniture, finished, and put inside boxes.</quote><quote id="12" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">Electricity is actually made up of extremely tiny particles called electrons, that you cannot see with the naked eye unless you have been drinking.</quote><quote id="13" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">Although golf was originally restricted to wealthy, overweight Protestants, today it's open to anybody who owns hideous clothing.</quote><quote id="14" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">The first major president to be elected after the War of 1812 was President Monroe Doctrine, who became famous by developing the policy for which he is named. This policy, which is still in effect today, states that:</quote><quote id="15" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref=""># Other nations are "not allowed" to mess around with the internal affairs of nations in this hemisphere.</quote><quote id="16" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref=""># But we are.</quote><quote id="17" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref=""># Ha-ha-ha.</quote><quote id="18" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">Without question, the greatest invention in the history of mankind is beer. Oh, I grant you that the wheel was also a fine invention, but the wheel does not go nearly as well with pizza.</quote><quote id="19" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">We travel because, no matter how comfortable we are at home, there's a part of us that wants - that "needs" - to see new vistas, take new tours, obtain new traveler's checks, buy new souvenirs, order new entrees, introduce new bacteria into our intestinal tracts, learn new words for "transfusion," and have all the other travel adventures that make us want to french-kiss our doormats when we finally get home.</quote><quote id="20" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">I took an estimated two thousand years of high school French, and when I finally got to France, I discovered that I didn't know one single phrase that was actually useful in a real-life French situation.</quote><quote id="21" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">What Dad means by "see" of course, is "drive past at 67 miles per hour." Dad feels it is a foolish waste of valuable vacation time to get out of the car and actually "go look" at an attraction.</quote><quote id="22" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">During the warm season (August 8 and 9), Maine is a true "vacation paradise," offering visitors a chance to jump into crystal-clear mountain lakes and see if they can get back out again before their bodily tissue is frozen as solid as a supermarket turkey.</quote><quote id="23" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">But Nebraska was not always a bed of roses. When the first settlers arrived, they found a harsh, unforgiving place, a vast treeless expanse of barren, drought-parched soil. And so, summoning up the dynamic pioneer spirit of hope and steely determination, they left. But a few of them remained and built sod houses, which are actually made of dirt. Think about that. You can't "clean" a sod house, because it would be "gone". The early settlers had a hell of a time getting this through to their children. "You kids stop tracking dirt out of the house!" they'd yell.</quote><quote id="24" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">Vermont: See New Hampshire</quote><quote id="25" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">Denmark (also called "Norway") is best known as the original home of the prune Danish as well as the Vikings, who wore hats with horns sticking out of them, and for a very good reason: they were insane.</quote><quote id="26" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">Ha ha! We are just poking a little friendly fun at Germany, which is famous for enjoying a good joke, or as the Germans say, "Sprechnehaltenzoltenfussenmachschnitzerkalbenrollen." Here is just one hilarious example of what we are talking about:</quote><quote id="27" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">The best way to learn Japanese is to be born as a Japanese baby, in Japan, raised by a Japanese family.</quote><quote id="28" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">We need our highest judicial body to stop this childish bickering and get back to debating the kinds of weighty constitutional issues that have absorbed the court in recent years, such as whether a city can legally force an exotic dancer to cover her entire nipple, or just the part that pokes out.</quote><quote id="29" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">Buying the right computer and getting it to work properly is no more complicated than building a nuclear reactor from wristwatch parts in a darkened room using only your teeth.</quote><quote id="30" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">When I purchase a food item at the supermarket, I can be confident that the label will state how much riboflavin is in it. The United States government requires this, and for a good reason, which is: I have no idea. I don't even know what riboflavin "is". I do know I eat a lot of it. For example, I often start the day with a hearty Kellogg's strawberry Pop-Tart, which has, according to the label, a riboflavin rating of 10 percent. I assume this means that 10 percent of the Pop-Tart is riboflavin. Maybe it's the red stuff in the middle. Anyway, I'm hoping riboflavin is a good thing; if it turns out that it's a "bad" thing, like "riboflavin" is the Latin word for "cockroach pus," then I am definitely in trouble.</quote><quote id="31" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">The Constitution of the United States of America, Article V, Section 1: "There shall be a National Anthem containing incomprehensible words and a high note that normal humans cannot hit without risk of hernia."</quote><quote id="32" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">But when it came to eloquence, George &amp;#91;H. W.&amp;#93; Bush was Winston Churchill compared with his vice president, the legendary J. Danforth Quayle. You never knew what Dan was going to say next, and the wonderful thing was, Dan clearly didn't know either. He'd be asked a question, and he'd start talking, and you could see in his eyes that he was thinking, Ohmigod I'm talking and I HAVE NO EARTHLY IDEA WHAT I'M TRYING TO SAY! I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING RIGHT NOW! </quote><quote id="33" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">A lot of people were very upset, especially people in Palm Beach County, who were saying that they had accidentally voted for Pat Buchanan, which was clearly a mistake. Even Pat Buchanan admitted this.</quote><quote id="34" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">:"You'd have to be "nuts" to vote for me!" he declared. "Hell, "I" didn't even vote for me!"</quote><quote id="35" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">[Gary] Hart was clearly the most attractive candidate, the only one with even a remote chance of beating Ronald Reagan, so naturally the Democrats selected: Walter Mondale. When Mondale accepted the nomination, he wooed the voter by informing them...that if they elected him as president, his first move would be to jack up their income taxes. Walter you sweet talker!</quote><quote id="36" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">What was life like in the colonies? Probably the best word to describe it would be "colonial".</quote><quote id="37" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">U.S. News Organizations observe the anniversary of September 11 with investigations about the nation's continuing vulnerability to terrorism. First, the New York "Daily News" reports that two of its reporters carried box cutters, razor knives, and pepper spray on fourteen commercial flights without getting caught. Then ABC News reports that it smuggled fifteen pounds of uranium into New York City. Then Fox News reports that it flew Osama bin Laden to Washington, D.C., and videotaped him touring the White House.</quote><quote id="38" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">In sports, Vijay Singh wins the Masters golf tournament and is awarded the coveted green jacket, which is quickly snatched away by angry Buick executives and given to Tiger Woods.</quote><quote id="39" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">In sports, the U.S. Open is not actually held because it's more efficient just to mail the check to Tiger Woods.</quote><quote id="40" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">Tiger Woods is kidnapped by rival golfers, sedated, handcuffed, placed in a straitjacket, wrapped in chains, and locked inside a trunk, which is then weighted with concrete blocks and dropped into the deepest part of the Pacific Ocean. He easily wins the PGA Championship.</quote><quote id="41" author="Dave Barry" cats="Americans|Authors|Humorists|Living people|Pulitzer Prize winners" ref="">[http://www.davebarry.com/ The &lt;strike&gt;Un&lt;/strike&gt;official Dave Barry Website]</quote></quotes>