<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="ru|bg|sr|it|en|bs|cs|pl"><quote id="0" author="Emir Kusturica" cats="Film directors" ref="">That is a Medieval way of drawing history, in which they do not respect the law and want the rest of the world to respect the law. That's not possible. </quote><quote id="1" author="Emir Kusturica" cats="Film directors" ref="">I just don't get it. The pigeon was already dead, we found it in the road. And no other censor has objected. What is the problem with you, English? You killed millions of Indians and Africans, and yet you go nuts about the circumstances of the death of a single Serbian pigeon. I am touched you hold the lives of Serbian birds so dear, but you are crazy. I will never understand how your minds work.</quote><quote id="2" author="Emir Kusturica" cats="Film directors" ref="">In Serbia a lot of people hate me because they want to westernise, not understanding that the western world is bipolar, with very good things and very bad things. Since they don't have experience of the west, they even believe that a western pile of shit is actually pie.</quote><quote id="3" author="Emir Kusturica" cats="Film directors" ref="">My father was an atheist and he always described himself as a Serb. OK, maybe we were Muslim for 250 years, but we were orthodox before that and deep down we were always Serbs, religion cannot change that. We only became Muslims to survive the Turks.</quote><quote id="4" author="Emir Kusturica" cats="Film directors" ref="">There are always motherfuckers queuing up to pull you down to earth. But we must fly occasionally, we all have to feel that joy or we are nothing.</quote><quote id="5" author="Emir Kusturica" cats="Film directors" ref="">the man stands between life and death. 
 the man thinks...</quote><quote id="6" author="Emir Kusturica" cats="Film directors" ref="">the fish is mute. 
 expressionless. 
" the fish doesn't think, 
 because the fish knows everything. 
 the fish knows everything. "</quote></quotes>