<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="el|eo|en|zh|af|ca|it|hy|cs|et|gl|id|es|ru|az|nl|pt|no|tr|lt|ro|is|pl|fr|bg|uk|hr|de|da|fa|br|bs|fi|hu|ja|he|ka|sr|sq|ko|sv|sk|ar|ku|sl"><quote id="0" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"I am utterly amazed, utterly enchanted! I have a "precursor", and what a precursor!" I hardly knew Spinoza: that I should have turned to him just "now", was inspired by "instinct." Not only is his overtendency like mine—namely to make all knowledge the "most powerful affect" — but in five main points of his doctrine I recognize myself; this most unusual and loneliest thinker is closest to me precisely in these matters: he denies the freedom of the will, teleology, the moral world-order, the unegoistic, and evil. "Even though the divergencies are admittedly tremendous, they are due more to the difference in time, culture, and science." "In summa": my lonesomeness, which, as on very high mountains, often made it hard for me to breathe and make my blood rush out, is now at least a twosomeness. Strange! Incidentally, I am not at all as well as I had hoped. Exceptional weather here too! Eternal change of atmospheric conditions! — that will yet drive me out of Europe! I must have "clear skies for months", else I get nowhere. Already six severe attacks of two or three days each. With affectionate love, Your friend.</quote><quote id="1" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"There are no facts, only interpretations."</quote><quote id="2" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"In Germany there is much complaining about my "eccentricities." But since it is not known where my center is, it won't be easy to find out where or when I have thus far been "eccentric."" That I was a philologist, for example, meant that I was "outside" my center (which fortunately does not mean that I was a poor philologist). Likewise, I now regard my having been a Wagnerian as eccentric. It was a highly dangerous experiment; now that I know it did "not" ruin me, I also know what "significance" it had for me — it was the most severe test of my character.</quote><quote id="3" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"So far no one had had enough courage and intelligence to "reveal" me to my dear Germans." My problems are new, my psychological horizon frighteningly comprehensive, my language bold and clear; there may well be no books written in German which are richer in ideas and more independent than mine.</quote><quote id="4" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">I've seen proof, black on white, that Herr Dr. Förster has not yet severed his connection with the anti-Semitic movement. ... Since then I've had difficulty coming up with any of the tenderness and protectiveness I've so long felt toward you. The separation between us is thereby decided in really the most absurd way. "Have you grasped nothing of the reason why I am in the world?" ... Now it has gone so far that I have to defend myself hand and foot against people who confuse me with these anti-Semitic canaille; after my own sister, my former sister, and after Widemann more recently have given the impetus to this most dire of all confusions. "After I read the name Zarathustra in the anti-Semitic "Correspondence" my forbearance came to an end. I am now in a position of "emergency defense" against your spouse's Party. These accursed anti-Semite deformities "shall not" sully my ideal!!"</quote><quote id="5" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">You have committed one of the greatest stupidities — for yourself and for me! Your association with an anti-Semitic chief expresses a foreignness to my whole way of life which fills me again and again with ire or melancholy. ... "It is a matter of honor with me to be absolutely clean and unequivocal in relation to anti-Semitism, namely, opposed to it, as I am in my writings. I have recently been persecuted with letters and "Anti-Semitic Correspondence Sheets". My disgust with this party (which would like the benefit of my name only too well!) is as pronounced as possible", but the relation to Förster, as well as the aftereffects of my former publisher, the anti-Semitic Schmeitzner, always brings the adherents of this disagreeable party back to the idea that I must belong to them after all. ... "It arouses mistrust against my character, as if publicly I condemned something which I have favored secretly — and that I am unable to do anything against it, that the name of Zarathustra is used in every "Anti-Semitic "Correspondence Sheet", has almost made me sick several times."</quote><quote id="6" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">I have somehow something like "influence" ... In the Anti-Semitic "Correspondence" ... my name is mentioned in almost every issue. "Zarathustra" ... has charmed the anti-Semites; there is a special anti-Semitic interpretation of it that made me laugh very much.</quote><quote id="7" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Mathematics would certainly have not come into existence if one had known from the beginning that there was in nature no exactly straight line, no actual circle, no absolute magnitude."</quote><quote id="8" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"He who fights with monsters should look to it that he himself does not become a monster. And when you gaze long into an abyss the abyss also gazes into you."</quote><quote id="9" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"The surest way to corrupt a youth is to instruct him to hold in higher esteem those who think alike than those who think differently."</quote><quote id="10" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Although the most acute judges of the witches and even the witches themselves, were convinced of the guilt of witchery, the guilt nevertheless was non-existent. It is thus with all guilt.</quote><quote id="11" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Freier Wille ohne Fatum ist ebenso wenig denkbar, wie Geist ohne Reelles, Gutes ohne Böses.</quote><quote id="12" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The modern scientific counterpart to belief in God is the belief in the universe as an organism: this disgusts me. This is to make what is quite rare and extremely derivative, the organic, which we perceive only on the surface of the earth, into something essential, universal, and eternal! This is still an anthropomorphizing of nature!</quote><quote id="13" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Is Wagner a human being at all?  Is he not rather a disease?  He contaminates everything he touches - he has made music sick.</quote><quote id="14" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">To say it once again: today I find it an impossible book — badly written, clumsy and embarrassing, its images frenzied and confused, sentimental, in some places saccharine-sweet to the point of effeminacy, uneven in pace, lacking in any desire for logical purity, so sure of its convictions that it is above any need for proof, and even suspicious of the "propriety" of proof, a book for initiates, 'music' for those who have been baptized in the name of music and who are related from the first by their common and rare experiences of art, a shibboleth for first cousins "in artibus" [in the arts] an arrogant and fanatical book that wished from the start to exclude the "profanum vulgus" [the profane mass] of the 'educated' even more than the 'people'; but a book which, as its impact has shown and continues to show, has a strange knack of seeking out its fellow-revellers and enticing them on to new secret paths and dancing-places.</quote><quote id="15" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">How far I was then from all that resignationism!</quote><quote id="16" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Art is the supreme task and the truly metaphysical activity in this life…"</quote><quote id="17" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Thus the man who is responsive to artistic stimuli reacts to the reality of dreams as does the philosopher to the reality of existence; he observes closely, and he enjoys his observation: for it is out of these images that he interprets life, out of these processes that he trains himself for life." It is not only pleasant and agreeable images that he experiences with such universal understanding: the serious, the gloomy, the sad and the profound, the sudden restraints, the mockeries of chance, fearful expectations, in short the whole 'divine comedy' of life, the Inferno included, passes before him, not only as a shadow-play — for he too lives and suffers through these scenes — and yet also not without that fleeting sense of illusion; and perhaps many, like myself, can remember calling out to themselves in encouragement, amid the perils and terrors of the dream, and with success: 'It is a dream! I want to dream on!' Just as I have often been told of people who have been able to continue one and the same dream over three and more successive nights: facts which clearly show that our innermost being, our common foundation, experiences dreams with profound pleasure and joyful necessity.</quote><quote id="18" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">In these dancers of Saint John and Saint Vitus we can recognize the Bacchic choruses of the Greeks, with their prehistory in Asia Minor, as far back as Babylon and the orgiastic Sacaea. Some people, either through a lack of experience or through obtuseness, turn away with pity or contempt from phenomena such as these as from 'folk diseases', bolstered by a sense of their own sanity; these poor creatures have no idea how blighted and ghostly this 'sanity' of theirs sounds when the glowing life of Dionysiac revellers thunders past them.</quote><quote id="19" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">According to the old story, King Midas had long hunted wise "Silenus", Dionysus' companion, without catching him. When Silenus had finally fallen into his clutches, the king asked him what was the best and most desirable thing of all for mankind. The daemon stood still, stiff and motionless, until at last, forced by the king, he gave a shrill laugh and spoke these words: 'Miserable, ephemeral race, children of hazard and hardship, why do you force me to say what it would be much more fruitful for you not to hear? The best of all things is something entirely outside your grasp: not to be born, not to "be", to be "nothing". But the second-best thing for you — is to die soon.'</quote><quote id="20" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Underneath this reality in which we live and have our being, another and altogether different reality lies concealed...</quote><quote id="21" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Greek tragedy met her death in a different way from all the older sister arts: she died tragically by her own hand, after irresolvable conflicts, while the others died happy and peaceful at an advanced age. If a painless death, leaving behind beautiful progeny, is the sign of a happy natural state, then the endings of the other arts show us the example of just such a happy natural state: they sink slowly, and with their dying eyes they behold their fairer offspring, who lift up their heads in bold impatience. The death of Greek tragedy, on the other hand, left a great void whose effects were felt profoundly, far and wide; as once Greek sailors in Tiberius' time heard the distressing cry 'the god Pan is dead' issuing from a lonely island, now, throughout the Hellenic world, this cry resounded like an agonized lament: 'Tragedy is dead! Poetry itself died with i! Away, away with you, puny, stunted imitators! Away with you to Hades, and eat your fill of the old masters' crumbs!'</quote><quote id="22" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">This context enables us to understand the passionate affection in which the poets of the New Comedy held Euripides; so that we are no longer startled by the desire of Philemon, who wished to be hanged at once so that he might meet Euripides in the underworld, so long as he could be sure that the deceased was still in full possession of his senses.</quote><quote id="23" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">..."aesthetic Socratism", the chief law of which is, more or less: "to be beautiful everything must first be intelligible" — a parallel to the Socratic dictum: "only the one who knows is virtuous."</quote><quote id="24" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">But for Socrates, tragedy did not even seem to "tell what's true", quite apart from the fact that it addresses "those without much wit", not the philosopher: another reason for giving it a wide berth. Like Plato, he numbered it among the flattering arts which represent only the agreeable, not the useful, and therefore required that his disciples abstain most rigidly from such unphilosophical stimuli — with such success that the young tragedian, Plato, burnt his writings in order to become a pupil of Socrates.</quote><quote id="25" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Gotthold Ephraim Lessing|Lessing, the most honest of theoretical men, dared to say that he took greater delight in the quest for truth than in the truth itself.</quote><quote id="26" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"We cannot help but see Socrates as the turning-point, the vortex of world history." For if we imagine that the whole incalculable store of energy used in that global tendency had been used "not" in the service of knowledge but in ways applied to the practical — selfish — goals of individuals and nations, universal wars of destruction and constant migrations of peoples would have enfeebled man's instinctive zest for life to the point where, suicide having become universal, the individual would perhaps feel a vestigial duty as a son to strangle his parents, or as a friend his friend, as the Fiji islanders do: a practical pessimism that could even produce a terrible ethic of genocide through pity, and which is, and always has been, present everywhere in the world where art has not in some form, particularly as religion and science, appeared as a remedy and means of prevention for this breath of pestilence.</quote><quote id="27" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">But what changes come upon the weary desert of our culture, so darkly described, when it is touched by the magic of Dionysus! A storm seizes everything decrepit, rotten, broken, stunted; shrouds it in a whirling red cloud of dust and carries it into the air like a vulture. In vain confusion we seek for all that has vanished; for what we see has risen as if from beneath he earth into the gold light, so full and green, so luxuriantly alive, immeasurable and filled with yearning. Tragedy sits in sublime rapture amidst this abundance of life, suffering and delight, listening to a far-off, melancholy song which tells of the Mothers of Being, whose names are Delusion, Will, Woe 
Yes, my friends, join me in my faith in this Dionysiac life and the rebirth of tragedy. The age of Socratic man is past: crown yourselves with ivy, grasp the thyrsus and do not be amazed if tigers and panthers lie down fawning at your feet. Now dare to be tragic men, for you will be redeemed. You shall join the Dionysiac procession from India to Greece! Gird yourselves for a hard battle, but have faith in the miracles of your god!</quote><quote id="28" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Once upon a time, in some out of the way corner of that universe which is dispersed into numberless twinkling solar systems, there was a star upon which clever beasts invented knowing." That was the most arrogant and mendacious minute of "world history," but nevertheless, it was only a minute. After nature had drawn a few breaths, the star cooled and congealed, and the clever beasts had to die. One might invent such a fable, and yet he still would not have adequately illustrated how miserable, how shadowy and transient, how aimless and arbitrary the human intellect looks within nature. There were eternities during which it did not exist. And when it is all over with the human intellect, nothing will have happened.</quote><quote id="29" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"The pride connected with knowing and sensing lies like a blinding fog over the eyes and senses of men, thus deceiving them concerning the value of existence." For this pride contains within itself the most flattering estimation of the value of knowing. Deception is the most general effect of such pride, but even its most particular effects contain within themselves something of the same deceitful character.</quote><quote id="30" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Deception, flattering, lying, deluding, talking behind the back, putting up a false front, living in borrowed splendor, wearing a mask, hiding behind convention, playing a role for others and for oneself — in short, a continuous fluttering around the solitary flame of vanity — is so much the rule and the law among men that there is almost nothing which is less comprehensible than how an honest and pure drive for truth could have arisen among them. They are deeply immersed in illusions and in dream images; their eyes merely glide over the surface of things and see "forms."</quote><quote id="31" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"What does man actually know about himself?" Is he, indeed, ever able to perceive himself completely, as if laid out in a lighted display case? Does nature not conceal most things from him — even concerning his own body — in order to confine and lock him within a proud, deceptive consciousness, aloof from the coils of the bowels, the rapid flow of the blood stream, and the intricate quivering of the fibers! She threw away the key.</quote><quote id="32" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"The liar is a person who uses the valid designations, the words, in order to make something which is unreal appear to be real." He says, for example, "I am rich," when the proper designation for his condition would be "poor." He misuses fixed conventions by means of arbitrary substitutions or even reversals of names. If he does this in a selfish and moreover harmful manner, society will cease to trust him and will thereby exclude him. "What men avoid by excluding the liar is not so much being defrauded as it is being harmed by means of fraud. Thus, even at this stage, what they hate is basically not deception itself, but rather the unpleasant, hated consequences of certain sorts of deception. It is in a similarly restricted sense that man now wants nothing but truth: he desires the pleasant, life-preserving consequences of truth." He is indifferent toward pure knowledge which has no consequences; toward those truths which are possibly harmful and destructive he is even hostilely inclined.</quote><quote id="33" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Are designations congruent with things? Is language the adequate expression of all realities?" 
It is only by means of forgetfulness that man can ever reach the point of fancying himself to possess a "truth" of the grade just indicated. "If he will not be satisfied with truth in the form of tautology, that is to say, if he will not be content with empty husks, then he will always exchange truths for illusions."</quote><quote id="34" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"The various languages placed side by side show that with words it is never a question of truth, never a question of adequate expression; otherwise, there would not be so many languages." The "thing in itself" (which is precisely what the pure truth, apart from any of its consequences, would be) is likewise something quite incomprehensible to the creator of language and something not in the least worth striving for. "This creator only designates the relations of things to men, and for expressing these relations he lays hold of the boldest metaphors."' To begin with, a nerve stimulus is transferred into an image: first metaphor. The image, in turn, is imitated in a sound: second metaphor. And each time there is a complete overleaping of one sphere, right into the middle of an entirely new and different one.</quote><quote id="35" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"We believe that we know something about the things themselves when we speak of trees, colors, snow, and flowers; and yet we possess nothing but metaphors for things — metaphors which correspond in no way to the original entities."</quote><quote id="36" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Every word instantly becomes a concept precisely insofar as it is not supposed to serve as a reminder of the unique and entirely individual original experience to which it owes its origin; but rather, a word becomes a concept insofar as it simultaneously has to fit countless more or less similar cases — which means, purely and simply, cases which are never equal and thus altogether unequal. "Every concept arises from the equation of unequal things." Just as it is certain that one leaf is never totally the same as another, so it is certain that the concept "leaf" is formed by arbitrarily discarding these individual differences and by forgetting the distinguishing aspects.</quote><quote id="37" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"We obtain the concept, as we do the form, by overlooking what is individual and actual; whereas nature is acquainted with no forms and no concepts, and likewise with no species, but only with an X which remains inaccessible and undefinable for us."</quote><quote id="38" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"What then is truth? A movable host of metaphors, metonymies, and anthropomorphisms: in short, a sum of human relations which have been poetically and rhetorically intensified, transferred, and embellished, and which, after long usage, seem to a people to be fixed, canonical, and binding." Truths are illusions which we have forgotten are illusions — they are metaphors that have become worn out and have been drained of sensuous force, coins which have lost their embossing and are now considered as metal and no longer as coins.</quote><quote id="39" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">We still do not yet know where the drive for truth comes from. For so far we have heard only of the duty which society imposes in order to exist: "to be truthful means to employ the usual metaphors." Thus, to express it morally, this is the duty to lie according to a fixed convention, to lie with the herd and in a manner binding upon everyone. Now man of course forgets that this is the way things stand for him. Thus he lies in the manner indicated, unconsciously and in accordance with habits which are centuries' old; and precisely by means of this unconsciousness and forgetfulness he arrives at his sense of truth.</quote><quote id="40" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The venerability, reliability, and utility of truth is something which a person demonstrates for himself from the contrast with the liar, whom no one trusts and everyone excludes. "As a "rational" being, he now places his behavior under the control of abstractions. He will no longer tolerate being carried away by sudden impressions, by intuitions."</quote><quote id="41" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Everything which distinguishes man from the animals depends upon this ability to volatilize perceptual metaphors in a schema, and thus to dissolve an image into a concept." For something is possible in the realm of these schemata which could never be achieved with the vivid first impressions: the construction of a pyramidal order according to castes and degrees, the creation of a new world of laws, privileges, subordinations, and clearly marked boundaries — a new world, one which now confronts that other vivid world of first impressions as more solid, more universal, better known, and more human than the immediately perceived world, and thus as the regulative and imperative world.</quote><quote id="42" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">One may certainly admire man as a mighty genius of construction, who succeeds in piling an infinitely complicated dome of concepts upon an unstable foundation, and, as it were, on running water. Of course, in order to be supported by such a foundation, his construction must be like one constructed of spiders' webs: delicate enough to be carried along by the waves, strong enough not to be blown apart by every wind.</quote><quote id="43" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">As a genius of construction man raises himself far above the bee in the following way: whereas the bee builds with wax that he gathers from nature, man builds with the far more delicate conceptual material which he first has to manufacture from himself.</quote><quote id="44" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"When someone hides something behind a bush and looks for it again in the same place and finds it there as well, there is not much to praise in such seeking and finding. Yet this is how matters stand regarding seeking and finding "truth" within the realm of reason. If I make up the definition of a mammal, and then, after inspecting a camel, declare "look, a mammal' I have indeed brought a truth to light in this way, but it is a truth of limited value." That is to say, it is a thoroughly anthropomorphic truth which contains not a single point which would be "true in itself" or really and universally valid apart from man. At bottom, what the investigator of such truths is seeking is only the metamorphosis of the world into man.</quote><quote id="45" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Only by forgetting this primitive world of metaphor can one live with any repose, security, and consistency": only by means of the petrification and coagulation of a mass of images which originally streamed from the primal faculty of human imagination like a fiery liquid, only in the invincible faith that this sun, this window, this table is a truth in itself, in short, "only by forgetting that he himself is an artistically creating subject, does man live with any repose, security, and consistency. If but for an instant he could escape from the prison walls of this faith, his "self consciousness" would be immediately destroyed." It is even a difficult thing for him to admit to himself that the insect or the bird perceives an entirely different world from the one that man does, and that the question of which of these perceptions of the world is the more correct one is quite meaningless, for this would have to have been decided previously in accordance with the criterion of the correct perception, which means, in accordance with a criterion which is not available.</quote><quote id="46" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Between two absolutely different spheres, as between subject and object, there is no causality, no correctness, and no expression; there is, at most, an aesthetic relation": I mean, a suggestive transference, a stammering translation into a completely foreign tongue — for which I there is required, in any case, a freely inventive intermediate sphere and mediating force." "Appearance" is a word that contains many temptations, which is why I avoid it as much as possible. For it is not true that the essence of things "appears" in the empirical world." A painter without hands who wished to express in song the picture before his mind would, by means of this substitution of spheres, still reveal more about the essence of things than does the empirical world. "Even the relationship of a nerve stimulus to the generated image is not a necessary one." But when the same image has been generated millions of times and has been handed down for many generations and finally appears on the same occasion every time for all mankind, then it acquires at last the same meaning for men it would have if it were the sole necessary image and if the relationship of the original nerve stimulus to the generated image were a strictly causal one. In the same manner, an eternally repeated dream would certainly be felt and judged to be reality. But "the hardening and congealing of a metaphor guarantees absolutely nothing concerning its necessity and exclusive justification."</quote><quote id="47" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">If each us had a different kind of sense perception — if we could only perceive things now as a bird, now as a worm, now as a plant, or if one of us saw a stimulus as red, another as blue, while a third even heard the same stimulus as a sound — then no one would speak of such a regularity of nature, rather, nature would be grasped only as a creation which is subjective in the highest degree. After all, "what is a law of nature as such for us? We are not acquainted with it in itself, but only with its effects, which means in its relation to other laws of nature — which, in turn, are known to us only as sums of relations. Therefore all these relations always refer again to others and are thoroughly incomprehensible to us in their essence."</quote><quote id="48" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">We produce these representations in and from ourselves with the same necessity with which the spider spins. "If we are forced to comprehend all things only under these forms, then it ceases to be amazing that in all things we actually comprehend nothing but these forms." For they must all bear within themselves the laws of number, and it is precisely number which is most astonishing in things. "All that conformity to law, which impresses us so much in the movement of the stars and in chemical processes, coincides at bottom with those properties which we bring to things." Thus it is we who impress ourselves in this way</quote><quote id="49" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">We have seen how it is originally language which works on the construction of concepts, a labor taken over in later ages by science. Just as the bee simultaneously constructs cells and fills them with honey, so science works unceasingly on this great columbarium of concepts, the graveyard of perceptions.</quote><quote id="50" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Whereas the man of action binds his life to reason and its concepts so that he will not be swept away and lost, the scientific investigator builds his hut right next to the tower of science so that he will be able to work on it and to find shelter for himself beneath those bulwarks which presently exist." And he requires shelter, for there are frightful powers which continuously break in upon him, powers which oppose scientific "truth" with completely different kinds of "truths" which bear on their shields the most varied sorts of emblems.</quote><quote id="51" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"The drive toward the formation of metaphors is the fundamental human drive, which one cannot for a single instant dispense with in thought, for one would thereby dispense with man himself." This drive is not truly vanquished and scarcely subdued by the fact that a regular and rigid new world is constructed as its prison from its own ephemeral products, the concepts. It seeks a new realm and another channel for its activity, and it finds this in myth and in art generally. This drive continually confuses the conceptual categories and cells by bringing forward new transferences, metaphors, and metonymies. "It continually manifests an ardent desire to refashion the world which presents itself to waking man, so that it will be as colorful, irregular, lacking in results and coherence, charming, and eternally new as the world of dreams." Indeed, it is only by means of the rigid and regular web of concepts that the waking man clearly sees that he is awake; and it is precisely because of this that he sometimes thinks that he must be dreaming when this web of concepts is torn by art.</quote><quote id="52" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Because of the way that myth takes it for granted that miracles are always happening, the waking life of a mythically inspired people — the ancient Greeks, for instance — more closely resembles a dream than it does the waking world of a scientifically disenchanted thinker.</quote><quote id="53" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Man has an invincible inclination to allow himself to be deceived and is, as it were, enchanted with happiness when the rhapsodist tells him epic fables as if they were true, or when the actor in the theater acts more royally than any real king." So long as it is able to deceive without injuring, that master of deception, the intellect, is free; it is released from its former slavery and celebrates its Saturnalia. It is never more luxuriant, richer, prouder, more clever and more daring.</quote><quote id="54" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"That immense framework and planking of concepts to which the needy man clings his whole life long in order to preserve himself is nothing but a scaffolding and toy for the most audacious feats of the liberated intellect." And when it smashes this framework to pieces, throws it into confusion, and puts it back together in an ironic fashion, pairing the most alien things and separating the closest, it is demonstrating that it has no need of these makeshifts of indigence and that it will now be guided by intuitions rather than by concepts. "There is no regular path which leads from these intuitions into the land of ghostly schemata, the land of abstractions. There exists no word for these intuitions; when man sees them he grows dumb, or else he speaks only in forbidden metaphors and in unheard — of combinations of concepts." He does this so that by shattering and mocking the old conceptual barriers he may at least correspond creatively to the impression of the powerful present intuition.</quote><quote id="55" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"There are ages in which the rational man and the intuitive man stand side by side, the one in fear of intuition, the other with scorn for abstraction." The latter is just as irrational as the former is inartistic. They both desire to rule over life: the former, by knowing how to meet his principle needs by means of foresight, prudence, and regularity; the latter, by disregarding these needs and, as an "overjoyed hero," counting as real only that life which has been disguised as illusion and beauty.</quote><quote id="56" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"The man who is guided by concepts and abstractions only succeeds by such means in warding off misfortune, without ever gaining any happiness for himself from these abstractions. And while he aims for the greatest possible freedom from pain, the intuitive man, standing in the midst of a culture, already reaps from his intuition a harvest of continually inflowing illumination, cheer, and redemption — in addition to obtaining a defense against misfortune." To be sure, he suffers more intensely, when he suffers; he even suffers more frequently, since he does not understand how to learn from experience and keeps falling over and over again into the same ditch.</quote><quote id="57" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Our destiny exercises its influence over us even when, as yet, we have not learned its nature: it is our future that lays down the law of our today."</quote><quote id="58" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">One must have a good memory to be able to keep the promises one makes.</quote><quote id="59" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"One will rarely err if extreme actions be ascribed to vanity, ordinary actions to habit, and mean actions to fear."</quote><quote id="60" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Every tradition grows ever more venerable — the more remote its origin, the more confused that origin is. The reverence due to it increases from generation to generation. The tradition finally becomes holy and inspires awe.</quote><quote id="61" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Where there is happiness, there is found pleasure in nonsense. The transformation of experience into its opposite, of the suitable into the unsuitable, the obligatory into the optional (but in such a manner that this process produces no injury and is only imagined in jest), is a pleasure; ...</quote><quote id="62" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">We often contradict an opinion for no other reason than that we do not like the tone in which it is expressed.</quote><quote id="63" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Arrogance on the part of the meritorious is even more offensive to us than the arrogance of those without merit: "for merit itself is offensive".</quote><quote id="64" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Unpleasant, even dangerous, qualities can be found in every nation and every individual": it is cruel to demand that the Jew be an exception. In him, these qualities may even be dangerous and revolting to an unusual degree; and perhaps the young stock-exchange Jew is altogether the most disgusting invention of mankind.</quote><quote id="65" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">He who thinks a great deal is not suited to be a party man: he thinks his way through the party and out the other side too soon.</quote><quote id="66" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The advantage of a bad memory is that one can enjoy the same good things for the first time "several" times.</quote><quote id="67" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">No one talks more passionately about his rights than he who in the depths of his soul doubts whether he has any. By enlisting passion on his side he wants to stifle his reason and its doubts: thus he will acquire a good conscience and with it success among his fellow men.</quote><quote id="68" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">If you have hitherto believed that life was one of the highest value and now see yourselves disappointed, do you at once have to reduce it to the lowest possible price?</quote><quote id="69" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"The mother of excess is not joy but joylessness."</quote><quote id="70" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Many a man fails to become a thinker only because his memory is too good.</quote><quote id="71" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The worst readers are those who behave like plundering troops: they take away a few things they can use, dirty and confound the remainder, and revile the whole.</quote><quote id="72" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">A witticism is an epigram on the death of a feeling.</quote><quote id="73" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">A Path to Equality. - A few hours of mountain climbing turn a rascal and a saint into two pretty similar creatures. Fatigue is the shortest way to Equality and Fraternity--and, in the end, Liberty will surrender to Sleep.                           </quote><quote id="74" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">It says nothing against the ripeness of a spirit that it has a few worms.</quote><quote id="75" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">With all great deceivers there is a noteworthy occurrence to which they owe their power. In the actual act of deception... they are overcome by belief in themselves. It is this which then speaks so miraculously and compellingly to those who surround them.</quote><quote id="76" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"In the mountains of truth you will never climb in vain": either you will get up higher today or you will exercise your strength so as to be able to get up higher tomorrow.</quote><quote id="77" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">It is mere illusion and pretty sentiment to expect much from mankind if he forgets how to make war. And yet no means are known which call so much into action as a great war, that rough energy born of the camp, that deep impersonality born of hatred, that conscience born of murder and cold-bloodedness, that fervor born of effort of the annihilation of the enemy, that proud indifference to loss, to one's own existence, to that of one's fellows, to that earthquake-like soul-shaking that a people needs when it is losing its vitality.</quote><quote id="78" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Feinde der Wahrheit. - Überzeugungen sind gefährlichere Feinde der Wahrheit, als Lügen.</quote><quote id="79" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Ziel und Wege. - Viele sind hartnäckig in Bezug auf den einmal eingeschlagenen Weg, Wenige in Bezug auf das Ziel.</quote><quote id="80" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Das Empörende an einer individuellen Lebensart. - Alle sehr individuellen Maassregeln des Lebens bringen die Menschen gegen Den, der sie ergreift, auf; sie fühlen sich durch die aussergewöhnliche Behandlung, welche jener sich angedeihen lässt, erniedrigt, als gewöhnliche Wesen.</quote><quote id="81" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Vorrecht der Grösse. - Es ist das Vorrecht der Grösse, mit geringen Gaben hoch zu beglücken.</quote><quote id="82" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Jeder in Einer Sache überlegen. - In civilisirten Verhältnissen fühlt sich Jeder jedem Anderen in Einer Sache wenigstens überlegen: darauf beruht das allgemeine Wohlwollen, insofern Jeder einer ist, der unter Umständen helfen kann und desshalb sich ohne Scham helfen lassen darf.</quote><quote id="83" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Das Leben als Ertrag des Lebens. - Der Mensch mag sich noch so weit mit seiner Erkenntniss ausrecken, sich selber noch so objectiv vorkommen: zuletzt trägt er doch Nichts davon, als seine eigene Biographie.</quote><quote id="84" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Aus der Erfahrung. - Die Unvernunft einer Sache ist kein Grund gegen ihr Dasein, vielmehr eine Bedingung desselben.</quote><quote id="85" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Gefahr unserer Cultur. - Wir gehören einer Zeit an, deren Cultur in Gefahr ist, an den Mitteln der Cultur zu Grunde zu gehen.</quote><quote id="86" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Die Länge des Tages. - Wenn man viel hineinzustecken hat, so hat ein Tag hundert Taschen.</quote><quote id="87" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Unglück. - Die Auszeichnung, welche im Unglück liegt (als ob es ein Zeichen von Flachheit, Anspruchslosigkeit, Gewöhnlichkeit sei, sich glücklich zu fühlen), ist so gross, dass wenn Jemand Einem sagt: "Aber wie glücklich Sie sind!" man gewöhnlich protestirt.</quote><quote id="88" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Den Andern zum Vorbild. - Wer ein gutes Beispiel geben will, muss seiner Tugend einen Gran Narrheit zusetzen: dann ahmt man nach und erhebt sich zugleich über den Nachgeahmten, - was die Menschen lieben.</quote><quote id="89" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Schatten in der Flamme. - Die Flamme ist sich selber nicht so hell,als den Anderen, denen sie leuchtet: so auch der Weise.</quote><quote id="90" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Eigene Meinungen. - Die erste Meinung, welche uns einfällt, wenn wir plötzlich über eine Sache befragt werden, ist gewöhnlich nicht unsere eigene, sondern nur die landläufige, unserer Kaste, Stellung, Abkunft zugehörige; die eigenen Meinungen schwimmen selten oben auf.</quote><quote id="91" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Lebensalter und Wahrheit. - junge Leute lieben das Interessante und Absonderliche, gleichgültig wie wahr oder falsch es ist. Reifere Geister lieben Das an der Wahrheit, was an ihr interessant und absonderlich ist. Ausgereifte Köpfe endlich lieben die Wahrheit auch in Dem, wo sie schlicht und einfältig erscheint und dem gewöhnlichen Menschen Langeweile macht, weil sie gemerkt haben, dass die Wahrheit das Höchste an Geist, was sie besitzt, mit der Miene der Einfalt zu sagen pflegt.</quote><quote id="92" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Der Gegenwart entfremdet. - Es hat grosse Vortheile, seiner Zeit sich einmal in stärkerem Maasse zu entfremden und gleichsam von ihrem Ufer zurück in den Ocean der vergangenen Weltbetrachtungen getrieben zu werden. Von dort aus nach der Küste zu blickend, überschaut man wohl zum ersten Male ihre gesammte Gestaltung und hat, wenn man sich ihr wieder nähert, den Vortheil, sie besser im Ganzen zu verstehen, als Die, welche sie nie verlassen haben.</quote><quote id="93" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Philosophisch gesinnt sein. - Gewöhnlich strebt man darnach, für alle Lebenslagen und Ereignisse eine Haltung des Gemüthes, eine Gattung von Ansichten zu erwerben, - das nennt man vornehmlich philosophisch gesinnt sein. Aber für die Bereicherung der Erkenntniss mag es höheren Werth haben, nicht in dieser Weise sich zu uniformiren, sondern auf die leise Stimme der verschiedenen Lebenslagen zu hören; diese bringen ihre eigenen Ansichten mit sich. So nimmt man erkennenden Antheil am Leben und Wesen Vieler, indem man sich selber nicht als starres, beständiges, Eines Individuum behandelt.</quote><quote id="94" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Verkehr mit dem höheren Selbst. - Ein jeder hat seinen guten Tag, wo er sein höheres Selbst findet; und die wahre Humanität verlangt, jemanden nur nach diesem Zustande und nicht nach den Werktagen der Unfreiheit und Knechtung zu schätzen. Man soll zum Beispiel einen Maler nach seiner höchsten Vision, die er zu sehen und darzustellen vermochte, taxiren und verehren. Aber die Menschen selber verkehren sehr verschieden mit diesem ihrem höheren Selbst und sind häufig ihre eigenen Schauspieler, insofern sie Das, was sie in jenen Augenblicken sind, später immer wieder nachmachen. Manche leben in Scheu und Demuth vor ihrem Ideale und möchten es verleugnen: sie fürchten ihr höheres Selbst, weil es, wenn es redet, anspruchsvoll redet. Dazu hat es eine geisterhafte Freiheit zu kommen und fortzubleiben wie es will; es wird desswegen häufig eine Gabe der Götter genannt, während eigentlich alles Andere Gabe der Götter (des Zufalls) ist: jenes aber ist der Mensch selber.</quote><quote id="95" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Leben und Erleben. - Sieht man zu, wie Einzelne mit ihren Erlebnissen - ihren unbedeutenden alltäglichen Erlebnissen - umzugehen wissen, so dass diese zu einem Ackerland werden, das dreimal des Jahres Frucht trägt; während Andere - und wie Viele! - durch den Wogenschlag der aufregendsten Schicksale, der mannigfaltigsten Zeit- und Volksströmungen hindurchgetrieben werden und doch immer leicht, immer obenauf, wie Kork, bleiben: so ist man endlich versucht, die Menschheit in eine Minorität (Minimalität) Solcher einzutheilen, welche aus Wenigem Viel zu machen verstehen: und in eine Majorität Derer, welche aus Vielem Wenig zu machen verstehen; ja man trifft auf jene umgekehrten Hexenmeister, welche, anstatt die Welt aus Nichts, aus der Welt ein Nichts schaffen.</quote><quote id="96" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Es ist nicht der Kampf der Meinungen, welcher die Geschichte so gewaltthätig gemacht hat, sondern der Kampf des Glaubens an die Meinungen, das heisst der Ueberzeugungen.</quote><quote id="97" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Wir sind im Wesentlichen noch dieselben Menschen, wie die des Zeitalters der Reformation: wie sollte es auch anders sein? Aber dass wir uns einige Mittel nicht mehr erlauben, um mit ihnen unsrer Meinung zum Siege zu verhelfen, das hebt uns gegen jene Zeit ab und beweist, dass wir einer höhern Cultur angehören. Wer jetzt noch, in der Art der Reformations-Menschen, Meinungen mit Verdächtigungen, mit Wuthausbrüchen bekämpft und niederwirft, verräth deutlich, dass er seine Gegner verbrannt haben würde, falls er in anderen Zeiten gelebt hätte, und dass er zu allen Mitteln der Inquisition seine Zuflucht genommen haben würde, wenn er als Gegner der Reformation gelebt hätte. Diese Inquisition war damals vernünftig, denn sie bedeutete nichts Anderes, als den allgemeinen Belagerungszustand, welcher über den ganzen Bereich der Kirche verhängt werden musste, und der, wie jeder Belagerungszustand, zu den äussersten Mitteln berechtigte, unter der Voraussetzung nämlich (welche wir jetzt nicht mehr mit jenen Menschen theilen), dass man die Wahrheit, in der Kirche, habe, und um jeden Preis mit jedem Opfer zum Heile der Menschheit bewahren müsse. Jetzt aber giebt man Niemandem so leicht mehr zu, dass er die Wahrheit habe: die strengen Methoden der Forschung haben genug Misstrauen und Vorsicht verbreitet, so dass Jeder, welcher gewaltthätig in Wort und Werk Meinungen vertritt, als ein Feind unserer jetzigen Cultur, mindestens als ein zurückgebliebener empfunden wird. In der That: das Pathos, dass man die Wahrheit habe, gilt jetzt sehr wenig im Verhältniss zu jenem freilich milderen und klanglosen Pathos des Wahrheit-Suchens, welches nicht müde wird, umzulernen und neu zu prüfen.</quote><quote id="98" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Who is the most moral man? "First", he who obeys the law most frequently, who ... is continually inventive in creating opportunities for obeying the law. Then, he who obeys it even in the most difficult cases. The most moral man is he who "sacrifices" the most to custom. ... "Self-overcoming is demanded, "not" on account of any useful consequences it may have for the individual, but so that hegemony of custom and tradition shall be made evident."</quote><quote id="99" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Whoever has overthrown an existing law of custom has hitherto always first been accounted a "bad man": but when, as did happen, the law could not afterwards be reinstated and this fact was accepted, the predicate gradually changed: - "history treats almost exclusively of these "bad men" who subsequently became "good men"!"</quote><quote id="100" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"He who is punished is never he who performed the deed. He is always the scapegoat."</quote><quote id="101" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">He who lives as children live — who does not struggle for his bread and does not believe that his actions possess any ultimate significance — remains childlike.</quote><quote id="102" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"It is not enough to prove something, one has also to seduce or elevate people to it." That is why the man of knowledge should learn how to "speak" his wisdom: and often in such a way that it "sounds" like folly!</quote><quote id="103" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">For those who need consolation no means of consolation is so effective as the assertion that in their case no consolation is possible: it implies so great a degree of distinction that they at once hold up their heads again.</quote><quote id="104" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"One has attained to mastery when one neither goes wrong "nor hesitates" in the performance."</quote><quote id="105" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"We are, all of us, growing volcanoes that approach the hour of their eruption; but how near or distant that is, nobody knows — not even God."</quote><quote id="106" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Benefiting and hurting others are ways of exercising one's power upon others; that is all one desires in such cases. One hurts those whom one wants to feel one's power, for pain is a much more efficient means to that end than pleasure; pain always raises the question about its origin while pleasure is inclined to stop with itself without looking back. We benefit and show benevolence to those who are already dependent on us in some way (which means that they are used to thinking of us as causes); we want to increase their power because in that way we increase ours, or we want to show them how advantageous it is to be in our power; that way they will become more satisfied with their condition and more hostile to and willing to fight against the enemies of our power.</quote><quote id="107" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">People who live in an age of corruption are witty and slanderous; they know that there are other kinds of murder than by dagger or assault; they also know that "whatever is "well said" is believed..."</quote><quote id="108" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"The reasons and purposes for habits are always lies that are added only after some people begin to attack these habits and to "ask" for reasons and purposes. At this point the conservatives of all ages are thoroughly dishonest: they add lies."</quote><quote id="109" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Even the most beautiful scenery is no longer assured of our love after we have lived in it for three months, and some distant coast attracts our avarice: "possessions are generally diminished by possession…"</quote><quote id="110" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">A thinker sees his own actions as experiments and questions — as attempts to find out something. Success and failure are for him answers above all.</quote><quote id="111" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Pardon me, my friends, I have ventured to paint my happiness on the wall.</quote><quote id="112" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">But let us not forget this either: "it is enough to create new names and estimations and probabilities in order to create in the long run new "things.""</quote><quote id="113" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Without art we would be nothing but foreground and live entirely in the spell of that perspective which makes what is closest at hand and most vulgar appear as if it were vast, and reality itself."</quote><quote id="114" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Good prose is written only face to face with poetry.</quote><quote id="115" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Art furnishes us with eyes and hands and above all the good conscience to be able to turn ourselves into such a phenomenon.</quote><quote id="116" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Gott ist tot! aber so wie die Art der Menschen ist, wird es vielleicht noch Jahrtausende lang Höhlen geben, in denen man seinen Schatten zeigt. — Und wir — Wir müssen auch noch seinen Schatten besiegen."</quote><quote id="117" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"To what extent can truth endure incorporation? That is the question; that is the experiment."</quote><quote id="118" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Morality is herd instinct in the individual.</quote><quote id="119" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Gott ist tot! Gott bleibt tot! Und wir haben ihn getötet."</quote><quote id="120" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Mystical explanations are considered deep; the truth is, they are not even shallow."</quote><quote id="121" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The Christian resolution to find the world ugly and bad has made the world ugly and bad.</quote><quote id="122" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">What is now decisive against Christianity is our taste, no longer our reasons.</quote><quote id="123" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"To find everything profound — that is an inconvenient trait." It makes one strain one's eyes all the time, and in the end one finds more than one might have wished.</quote><quote id="124" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">We are always in our own company.</quote><quote id="125" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Thoughts are the shadows of our feelings — always darker, emptier, simpler."</quote><quote id="126" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"The most perfidious way of harming a cause consists of defending it deliberately with faulty arguments."</quote><quote id="127" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">We have no dreams at all or interesting ones. We should learn to be awake the same way — not at all or in an interesting manner.</quote><quote id="128" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">New Domestic Animals. I want to have my lion and my eagle about me, that I may always have hints and premonitions concerning the amount of my strength or weakness. Must I look down on them today, and be afraid of them? And will the hour come once more when they will look up to me, and tremble?</quote><quote id="129" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Die Leugner des Zufalls. — 'Kein Sieger glaubt an den Zufall."</quote><quote id="130" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Was sagt dein Gewissen? — 'Du sollst der werden, der du bist.' "</quote><quote id="131" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">What is the seal of liberation? — No longer being ashamed in front of oneself.</quote><quote id="132" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">There is something laughable about the sight of authors who enjoy the rustling folds of long and involved sentences: they are trying to cover up their feet.</quote><quote id="133" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Glaubt es mir! – das Geheimnis, um die größte Fruchtbarkeit und den größten Genuß vom Dasein einzuernten, heißt: gefährlich leben!"</quote><quote id="134" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Everything good, fine or great they do is first of all an argument against the skeptic inside them.</quote><quote id="135" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Perhaps man will rise ever higher as soon as he ceases to flow out into a god.</quote><quote id="136" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Eins ist not. — Seinem Charakter 'Stil geben'."</quote><quote id="137" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"We want to be poets of our life — first of all in the smallest most everyday matters."</quote><quote id="138" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Do you believe then that the sciences would have arisen and grown up if the sorcerers, alchemists, astrologers and witches had not been their forerunners; those who, with their promisings and foreshadowings, had first to create a thirst, a hunger, and a taste for hidden and forbidden powers?</quote><quote id="139" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Whatever has value in our world now does not have value in itself, according to its nature — nature is always value-less, but has been given value at some time, as a present — and it was we who gave and bestowed it."</quote><quote id="140" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">It is true that there are men who, on the approach of severe pain, hear the very opposite call of command, and never appear more proud, more martial, or more happy than when the storm is brewing; indeed, pain itself provides them with their supreme moments! These are the heroic men, the great pain-bringers of mankind: those few and rare ones who need just the same apology as pain generally — and verily, it should not be denied them. They are forces of the greatest importance for preserving and advancing the species, be it only because they are opposed to smug ease, and do not conceal their disgust at this kind of happiness.</quote><quote id="141" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Who can attain to anything great if he does not feel in himself the force and will to inflict great pain? The ability to suffer is a small matter: in that line, weak women and even slaves often attain masterliness. But not to perish from internal distress and doubt when one inflicts great suffering and hears the cry of it — that is great, that belongs to greatness.</quote><quote id="142" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Could one count such dilettantes and old spinsters as that mawkish apostle of virginity, Mainlander, as a genuine German? In the last analysis he probably was a Jew (all Jews become mawkish when they moralize).</quote><quote id="143" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"I would not know what the spirit of a philosopher might wish more to be than a good dancer."</quote><quote id="144" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">We "conserve" nothing; neither do we want to return to any past periods; we are not by any means "liberal"; we do not work for "progress"; we do not need to plug up our ears against the sirens who in the market place sing of the future: their song about "equal rights," "a free society," "no more masters and no servants" has no allure for us.</quote><quote id="145" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">We simply do not consider it desirable that a realm of justice and concord should be established on earth (because it would certainly be the realm of the deepest leveling and "chinoiserie"); "we are delighted with all who love, as we do, danger, war, and adventures, who refuse to compromise, to be captured, reconciled, and castrated"; we count ourselves among conquerors; we think about the necessity for new orders, also for a new slavery — for every strengthening and enhancement of the human type also involves a new kind of enslavement.</quote><quote id="146" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Is it not clear that with all this we are bound to feel ill at ease in an age that likes to claim the distinction of being the most humane, the mildest, and the most righteous age that the sun has ever seen? It is bad enough that precisely when we hear these beautiful words we have the ugliest suspicions. What we find in them is merely an expression — and a masquerade — of a profound weakening, of weariness, of old age, of declining energies. What can it matter to us what tinsel the sick may use to cover up their weakness? Let them parade it as their virtue; after all, there is no doubt that weakness makes one mild, oh so mild, so righteous, so inoffensive, so "humane"!</quote><quote id="147" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Preparatory human beings. — I welcome all signs that a more virile, warlike age is about to begin, which will restore honor to courage above all! For this age shall prepare the way for one yet higher, and it shall gather the strength that this higher age will require some day — the age that will carry heroism into the search for knowledge and that will wage wars for the sake of ideas and their consequences.</quote><quote id="148" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">To this end we now need many preparatory courageous human beings who cannot very well leap out of nothing — any more than out of the sand and slime of present-day civilization and metropolitanism: human beings who know how to be silent, lonely, resolute, and content and constant in invisible activities; human beings who are bent on seeking in all things for what in them must be overcome; human beings distinguished as much by cheerfulness, patience, unpretentiousness, and contempt for all great vanities as by magnanimity in victory and forbearance regarding the small vanities of the vanquished; human beings whose judgment concerning all victors and the share of chance in every victory and fame is sharp and free; human beings with their own festivals, their own working days, and their own periods of mourning, accustomed to command with assurance but instantly ready to obey when that is called for, equally proud, equally serving their own cause in both cases; more endangered human beings, more fruitful human beings, happier beings!</quote><quote id="149" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Du grosses Gestirn! Was wäre dein Glück, wenn du nicht Die hättest, welchen du leuchtest!"</quote><quote id="150" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Ihr habt den Weg vom Wurme zum Menschen gemacht, und Vieles ist in euch noch Wurm. Einst wart ihr Affen, und auch jetzt ist der Mensch mehr Affe, als irgend ein Affe."</quote><quote id="151" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Wahrlich, ein schmutziger Strom ist der Mensch. Man muß schon ein Meer sein, um einen schmutzigen Strom aufnehmen zu können, ohne unrein zu werden."</quote><quote id="152" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Ich sage euch: man muß noch Chaos in sich haben, um einen tanzenden Stern gebären zu können."</quote><quote id="153" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Kein Hirt und Eine Heerde! Jeder will das Gleiche, Jeder ist gleich: wer anders fühlt, geht freiwillig in's Irrenhaus."</quote><quote id="154" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Welches ist der große Drache, den der Geist nicht mehr Herr und Gott heißen mag? "Du-sollst" heißt der große Drache. Aber der Geist des Löwen sagt "ich will". "Du-sollst" liegt ihm am Wege, goldfunkelnd, ein Schuppentier, und auf jeder Schuppe glänzt golden "Du sollst!" Tausendjährige Werte glänzen an diesen Schuppen, und also spricht der mächtigste aller Drachen: "aller Wert der Dinge - der glänzt an mir." "Aller Wert ward schon geschaffen, und aller geschaffene Wert - das bin ich. Wahrlich, es soll kein 'Ich will' mehr geben!" Also spricht der Drache."</quote><quote id="155" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Keine geringe Kunst ist schlafen: es thut schon Noth, den ganzen Tag darauf hin zu wachen."</quote><quote id="156" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">""Leib bin ich und Seele"–so redet das Kind. Und warum sollte man nicht wie die Kinder reden?"</quote><quote id="157" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Es ist mehr Vernunft in deinem Leibe, als in deiner besten Weisheit."</quote><quote id="158" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Und nichts Böses wächst mehr fürderhin aus dir, es sei denn das Böse, das aus dem Kampfe deiner Tugenden wächst. Mein Bruder, wenn du Glück hast, so hast du Eine Tugend und nicht mehr: so gehst du leichter über die Brücke."</quote><quote id="159" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Von allem Geschriebenen liebe ich nur Das, was Einer mit seinem Blute schreibt."</quote><quote id="160" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Es ist immer etwas Wahnsinn in der Liebe. Es ist aber immer auch etwas Vernunft im Wahnsinn."</quote><quote id="161" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Muthig, unbekümmert, spöttisch, gewaltthätig - so will uns die Weisheit: sie ist ein Weib und liebt immer nur einen Kriegsmann."</quote><quote id="162" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Es ist wahr: wir lieben das Leben, nicht, weil wir an's Leben, sondern weil wir an's Lieben gewöhnt sind."</quote><quote id="163" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Ich würde nur an einen Gott glauben, der zu tanzen verstünde."</quote><quote id="164" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Nicht durch Zorn, sondern durch Lachen tötet man</quote><quote id="165" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Ihr seht nach oben, wenn ihr nach Erhebung verlangt. Und ich sehe hinab, weil ich erhoben bin."</quote><quote id="166" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Im Gebirge ist der nächste Weg von Gipfel zu Gipfel: aber dazu musst du lange Beine haben. Sprüche sollen Gipfel sein: und Die, zu denen gesprochen wird, Grosse und Hochwüchsige."</quote><quote id="167" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">""Je mehr er hinauf in die Höhe und Helle will, um so stärker streben seine Wurzeln erdwärts, abwärts, in's Dunkle, Tiefe, — in's Böse.""</quote><quote id="168" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Ihre (Predigern des Todes) Weisheit lautet: "ein Thor, der leben bleibt, aber so sehr sind wir Thoren! Und das eben ist das Thörichtste am Leben!" — "</quote><quote id="169" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Ich weiss um den Hass und Neid eures Herzens. Ihr seid nicht gross genug, um Hass und Neid nicht zu kennen. So seid denn gross genug, euch ihrer nicht zu schämen!"</quote><quote id="170" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Aber der Staat lügt in allen Zungen des Guten und Bösen; und was er auch redet, er lügt—und was er auch hat, gestohlen hat er's."</quote><quote id="171" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Seht sie klettern, diese geschwinden Affen! Sie klettern über einander hinweg und zerren sich also in den Schlamm und die Tiefe. Hin zum Throne wollen sie Alle: ihr Wahnsinn ist es, — als ob das Glück auf dem Throne sässe! Oft sitzt der Schlamm auf dem Thron — und oft auch der Thron auf dem Schlamme. Wahnsinnige sind sie mir Alle und kletternde Affen und Überheisse. Übel riecht mir ihr Götze, das kalte Unthier: übel riechen sie mir alle zusammen, diese Götzendiener."</quote><quote id="172" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Wenn die Macht gnädig wird und herabkommt ins Sichtbare: Schönheit heiße ich solches Herabkommen. Und von niemandem will ich so als von dir gerade Schönheit, du Gewaltiger: deine Güte sei deine letzte Selbst-Überwältigung. Alles Böse traue ich dir zu: darum will ich von dir das Gute. Wahrlich, ich lachte oft der Schwächlinge, welche sich gut glauben, weil sie lahme Tatzen haben!"</quote><quote id="173" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Zweierlei will der echte Mann: Gefahr und Spiel. Deshalb will er das Weib als das gefährlichste Spielzeug."</quote><quote id="174" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Vornehmer ist's, sich Unrecht zu geben als Recht zu behalten, sonderlich wenn man Recht hat. Nur muss man reich genug dazu sein."</quote><quote id="175" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">" Also aber rathe ich euch, meine Freunde: misstraut Allen, in welchen der Trieb, zu strafen, mächtig ist! Das ist Volk schlechter Art und Abkunft; aus ihren Gesichtern blickt der Henker und der Spürhund. Misstraut allen Denen, die viel von ihrer Gerechtigkeit reden! Wahrlich, ihren Seelen fehlt es nicht nur an Honig. Und wenn sie sich selber 'die Guten und Gerechten' nennen, so vergesst nicht, dass ihnen zum Pharisäer Nichts fehlt als — Macht! "</quote><quote id="176" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Und wer von uns Dichtern hätte nicht seinen Wein verfälscht? Manch giftiger Mischmasch geschah in unsern Kellern, manches Unbeschreibliche ward da getan."</quote><quote id="177" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Ach, es gibt so viel Dinge zwischen Himmel und Erde, von denen sich nur die Dichter etwas haben träumen lassen. Und zumal ü b e r dem Himmel: denn alle Götter sind Dichter-Gleichnis, Dichter-Erschleichnis! Wahrlich, immer zieht es uns hinan - nämlich zum Reich der Wolken: auf diese setzen wir unsre bunten Bälge und heißen sie dann Götter und Übermenschen: - Sind sie doch gerade leicht genug für diese Stühle! - alle diese Götter und Übermenschen. Ach, wie bin ich all des Unzulänglichen müde, das durchaus Ereignis sein soll! Ach, wie bin ich der Dichter müde!"</quote><quote id="178" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Höheres als alle Versöhnung muss der Wille wollen, welcher der Wille zur Macht ist".</quote><quote id="179" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Und wer unter Menschen nicht verschmachten will, muß lernen, aus allen Gläsern zu trinken; und wer unter Menschen rein bleiben will, muß verstehn, sich auch mit schmutzigem Wasser zu waschen. Und also sprach ich oft mir zum Troste: "Wohlan! Wohlauf! Altes Herz! Ein Unglück mißriet dir: genieße dies als dein - Glück!""</quote><quote id="180" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Die stillsten Worte sind es, welche den Sturm bringen. Gedanken, die mit Taubenfüßen kommen, lenken die Welt."</quote><quote id="181" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Woher kommen die höchsten Berge? so fragte ich einst. Da lernte ich, daß sie aus dem Meere kommen. Dies Zeugnis ist in ihr Gestein geschrieben und in die Wände ihrer Gipfel. Aus dem Tiefsten muß das Höchste zu seiner Höhe kommen."</quote><quote id="182" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"O meine Brüder, ich weihe und weise euch zu einem neuen Adel: ihr sollt mir Zeuger und Züchter werden und Säemänner der Zukunft, - wahrlich, nicht zu einem Adel, den ihr kaufen könntet gleich den Krämern und mit Krämer-Golde: denn wenig Wert hat alles, was seinen Preis hat. Nicht, woher ihr kommt, mache euch fürderhin eure Ehre, sondern wohin ihr geht! Euer Wille und euer Fuß, der über euch selber hinaus will, — das mache eure neue Ehre!"</quote><quote id="183" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"O meine Brüder, nicht zurück soll euer Adel schauen, sondern h i n a u s ! Vertriebene sollt ihr sein aus allen Vater- und Urväterländern! Eurer Kinder Land sollt ihr lieben: diese Liebe sei euer neuer Adel, — das unentdeckte, im fernsten Meere! Nach ihm heiße ich eure Segel suchen und suchen! An euren Kindern sollt ihr gut machen, daß ihr eurer Väter Kinder seid: alles Vergangene sollt ihr so erlösen! Diese neue Tafel stelle ich über euch!"</quote><quote id="184" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Free "from" what? As if that mattered to Zarathustra! But your eyes should tell me brightly: free "for" what?</quote><quote id="185" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Then will he who goes under bless himself for being one who goes over and beyond; and the sun of his knowledge will stand at high noon for him. 
""Dead are all gods: now we want the overman to live"" — on that great noon, let this be our last will.</quote><quote id="186" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Was fällt, das soll man auch noch stoßen!"</quote><quote id="187" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">There still shines the most important nuance by virtue of which the noble felt themselves to be men of a higher rank. They designate themselves simply by their superiority in power (as "the powerful," "the masters," "the commanders") or by the most clearly visible signs of this superiority, for example, as "the rich," "the possessors" (this is the meaning of 'Arya,' and of corresponding words in Iranian and Slavic).</quote><quote id="188" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">As is well known, the priests are the most evil enemies — but why? Because they are the most impotent. "It is because of their impotence that in them hatred grows to monstrous and uncanny proportions, to the most spiritual and poisonous kind of hatred." The truly great haters in the world history have always been priests; likewise the most ingenious haters: other kinds of spirit hardly come into consideration when compared with the spirit of priestly vengefulness.</quote><quote id="189" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"While every noble morality develops from a triumphant affirmation of itself, slave morality from the outset says No to what is "outside," what is "different," what is "not itself"; and this No is its creative deed."</quote><quote id="190" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Without cruelty there is no festival: thus the longest and most ancient part of human history teaches — and in punishment there is so much that is festive!</quote><quote id="191" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"That every will must consider every other will its equal — would be a principle hostile to life, an agent of the dissolution and destruction of man, an attempt to assassinate the future of man, a sign of weariness, a secret path to nothingness."</quote><quote id="192" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">It is possible to imagine a society flushed with such a sense of power that it could afford to let its offenders go unpunished.</quote><quote id="193" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The broad effects which can be obtained by punishment in man and beast are the increase of fear, the sharpening of the sense of cunning, the mastery of the desires; so it is that punishment tames man, but does not make him "better."</quote><quote id="194" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">All instincts that do not discharge themselves outwardly turn inward — this is what I call the internalization of man: thus it was that man first developed what was later called his "soul."</quote><quote id="195" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The advent of the Christian God, as the maximum god attained so far, was therefore accompanied by the maximum feeling of guilty indebtedness on earth.</quote><quote id="196" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"If a temple is to be erected, a temple must be "destroyed"."</quote><quote id="197" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"The sick are the greatest danger for the healthy; it is not from the strongest that harm comes to the strong, but from the weakest."</quote><quote id="198" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"A strong and well-constituted man digests his experiences (deeds and misdeeds all included) just as he digests his meats, even when he has some tough morsels to swallow."</quote><quote id="199" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">O, what nowadays does science not conceal! How much, at least, it is "meant" to conceal!</quote><quote id="200" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Plato ist langweilig"</quote><quote id="201" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Wie? ist der Mensch nur ein Fehlgriff Gottes? Oder Gott nur ein Fehlgriff des Menschen?"</quote><quote id="202" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">&lt;span id="make-stronger"/&gt;"Was mich nicht umbringt, macht mich stärker."</quote><quote id="203" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Hat man sein warum? des Lebens, so verträgt man sich fast mit jedem wie?"</quote><quote id="204" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Women are considered profound. Why? Because we never fathom their depths. But women aren't even shallow.</quote><quote id="205" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Ohne Musik wäre das Leben ein Irrtum."</quote><quote id="206" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Das Christenthum ist eine Metaphysik des Henkers..."</quote><quote id="207" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Liberalismus: auf deutsch Heerden-Verthierung ..."</quote><quote id="208" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Freedom is the will to be responsible for ourselves. It is to preserve the distance which separates us from other men. To grow more indifferent to hardship, to severity, to privation, and even to life itself.</quote><quote id="209" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Two great European narcotics, alcohol and Christianity.</quote><quote id="210" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Man believes that the world itself is filled with beauty — he "forgets" that it is he who has created it. He alone has bestowed beauty upon the world — alas! only a very human, an all too human, beauty.</quote><quote id="211" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"My conception of freedom. — The value of a thing sometimes does not lie in that which one attains by it, but in what one pays for it — what it costs us." I give an example. "Liberal institutions cease to be liberal as soon as they are attained: later on, there are no worse and no more thorough injurers of freedom than liberal institutions." One knows, indeed, what their ways bring: they undermine the will to power; they level mountain and valley, and call that morality; they make men small, cowardly, and hedonistic ["genüsslich"] — every time it is the herd animal that triumphs with them. Liberalism: in other words, herd-animalization ...</quote><quote id="212" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"It is my ambition to say in ten sentences what everyone else says in a whole book — what everyone else does "not" say in a whole book."</quote><quote id="213" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The doctrine of equality! … But there is no more venomous poison in existence: for it appears to be preached by justice itself, when it is actually the end of justice …" "Equality to the equal; inequality to the unequal" — that would be true justice speaking: and its corollary, "never make the unequal equal"."</quote><quote id="214" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">When one gives up Christian belief one thereby deprives oneself of the "right" to Christian morality. For the latter is absolutely "not" self-evident: one must make this point clear again and again, in spite of English shallowpates.</quote><quote id="215" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"We have already gone beyond whatever we have words for. In all talk there is a grain of contempt."</quote><quote id="216" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">These same institutions produce quite different effects while they are still being fought for; then they really promote freedom in a powerful way. On closer inspection it is war that produces these effects, the war for liberal institutions, which, as a war, permits illiberal instincts to continue. And war educates for freedom. For what is freedom? That one has the will to self-responsibility. That one maintains the distance which separates us. That one becomes more indifferent to difficulties, hardships, privation, even to life itself. That one is prepared to sacrifice human beings for one's cause, not excluding oneself.</quote><quote id="217" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Freedom means that the manly instincts which delight in war and victory dominate over other instincts, for example, over those of "pleasure." The human being who has become free — and how much more the spirit who has become free — spits on the contemptible type of well-being dreamed of by shopkeepers, Christians, cows, females, Englishmen, and other democrats. The free man is a warrior. —</quote><quote id="218" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">How is freedom measured, in individuals as in nations? By the resistance which must be overcome, by the effort ["Mühe"] it costs to remain on top. The highest type of free men should be sought where the highest resistance is constantly overcome: five steps from tyranny, close to the threshold of the danger of servitude. This is true psychologically if by "tyrants" are meant inexorable and dreadful instincts that provoke the maximum of authority and discipline against themselves — most beautiful type: Julius Caesar — ; this is true politically too; one need only go through history. The nations which were worth something, became worth something, never became so under liberal institutions: it was great danger that made something of them that merits respect. "Danger alone acquaints us with our own resources, our virtues, our armor and weapons, our spirit — and forces us to be strong ..."</quote><quote id="219" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">First principle: one must need to be strong — otherwise one will never become strong. — Those large hothouses ["Treibhäuser"] for the strong, for the strongest kind of human being that has ever been, the aristocratic commonwealths of the type of Rome or Venice, understood freedom exactly in the sense in which I understand the word freedom: as something one has and does not have, something one wants, something one conquers ...</quote><quote id="220" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Our institutions are no good any more: on that there is universal agreement. However, it is not their fault but ours. Once we have lost all the instincts out of which institutions grow, we lose institutions altogether because we are no longer good for them.</quote><quote id="221" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Einige werden posthum geboren."</quote><quote id="222" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">What is good? All that heightens the feeling of power in man, the will to power, power itself. What is bad? All that is born of weakness. What is happiness? The feeling that power is growing, that resistance is overcome.</quote><quote id="223" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">In Christianity neither morality nor religion come into contact with reality at any point.</quote><quote id="224" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Hope, in its stronger forms, is a great deal more powerful stimulans to life than any sort of realized joy can ever be." Man must be sustained in suffering by a hope so high that no conflict with actuality can dash it—so high, indeed, that no fulfilment can satisfy it: a hope reaching out beyond this world.</quote><quote id="225" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Love is a state in which a man sees things most decidedly as they are "not".</quote><quote id="226" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">...to the priestly class — decadence is no more than a means to an end. Men of this sort have a vital interest in making mankind sick, and in confusing the values of "good" and "bad," "true" and "false" in a manner that is not only dangerous to life, but also slanders it.</quote><quote id="227" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"The very word "Christianity" is a misunderstanding — in truth, there was only one Christian, and he died on the cross."</quote><quote id="228" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">As an artistic triumph in psychological corruption ... the Gospels, in fact, stand alone ... Here we are among Jews: this is the first thing to be borne in mind if we are not to lose the thread of the matter. This positive genius for conjuring up a delusion of personal "holiness" unmatched anywhere else, either in books or by men; this elevation of fraud in word and attitude to the level of an art — all this is not an accident due to the chance talents of an individual, or to any violation of nature. The thing responsible is "race".</quote><quote id="229" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The whole disaster was only made possible by the fact that there already existed in the world a similar megalomania, allied to this one in race, to wit, "the Jewish".</quote><quote id="230" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">What follows, then? That one had better put on gloves before reading the New Testament. The presence of so much filth makes it very advisable. One would as little choose early Christians for companions as "Polish Jews": not that one need seek out an objection to them — neither has a pleasant smell.</quote><quote id="231" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The God that Paul invented for himself, a God who "reduced to absurdity" "the wisdom of this world" (especially the two great enemies of superstition, philology and medicine), is in truth only an indication of Paul's resolute determination to accomplish that very thing himself: "to give one's own will the name of God, Torah — that is essentially Jewish".</quote><quote id="232" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">God created woman. And boredom did indeed cease from that moment — but many other things ceased as well! Woman was God's "second" mistake.</quote><quote id="233" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Against boredom even gods struggle in vain."</quote><quote id="234" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">That faith makes blessed under certain circumstances, that blessedness does not make of a fixed idea a "true" idea, that faith moves no mountains but "puts" mountains where there are none: a quick walk through a "madhouse" enlightens one sufficiently about this.</quote><quote id="235" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Faith" means not "wanting" to know what is true.</quote><quote id="236" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Whom do I hate most among the rabble of today? The socialist rabble, the chandala apostles, who undermine the instinct, the pleasure, the worker’s sense of satisfaction with his small existence–who make him envious, who teach him revenge. The source of wrong is never unequal rights but the claim of “equal” rights."</quote><quote id="237" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Nihilist und Christ: das reimt sich, das reimt sich nicht bloss."</quote><quote id="238" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Christianity destroyed for us the whole harvest of ancient civilization, and later it also destroyed for us the whole harvest of Mohammedan civilization. The wonderful culture of the Moors in Spain, which was fundamentally nearer to us and appealed more to our senses and tastes than that of Rome and Greece, was trampled down ( — I do not say by what sort of feet — ) Why? Because it had to thank noble and manly instincts for its origin — because it said yes to life, even to the rare and refined luxuriousness of Moorish life! The crusaders later made war on something before which it would have been more fitting for them to have grovelled in the dust — a civilization beside which even that of our nineteenth century seems very poor and very "senile."[...] Intrinsically there should be no more choice between Islam and Christianity than there is between an Arab and a Jew. The decision is already reached; nobody remains at liberty to choose here. Either a man is a Chandala or he is not.... “War to the knife with Rome! Peace and friendship with Islam!”: this was the feeling, this was the act, of that great free spirit, that genius among German emperors, Frederick II.</quote><quote id="239" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">I call Christianity the one great curse, the one great intrinsic depravity, the one great instinct for revenge for which no expedient is sufficiently poisonous, secret, subterranean, petty — I call it the one immortal blemish of mankind.</quote><quote id="240" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Der Mensch der Erkenntniss muss nicht nur seine Feinde lieben, er muss auch seine Freunde hassen können."</quote><quote id="241" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Original: Man büsst es theuer, unsterblich zu sein: man stirbt dafür mehrere Male bei Lebzeiten.</quote><quote id="242" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"Nothing on earth consumes a man more quickly than the passion of resentment."</quote><quote id="243" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"I know my fate. One day my name will be associated with the memory of something tremendous — a crisis without equal on earth, the most profound collision of conscience, a decision that was conjured up against everything that had been believed, demanded, hallowed so far. I am no man, I am dynamite."</quote><quote id="244" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"was ihn nicht umbringt, macht ihn stärker"</quote><quote id="245" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">I am a pure-blooded Polish nobleman, without a single drop of bad blood, certainly not German blood. When I look for my diametric opposite, an immeasurably shabby instinct, I always think of my mother and sister, — it would blaspheme my divinity to think I am related to this sort of "canaille". The way my mother and sister treat me to this very day is a source of unspeakable horror; a real time bomb is at work here, which can tell with unerring certainty the exact moment I can be hurt — in my highest moments, … because at that point I do not have the strength to resist poison worms …</quote><quote id="246" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">All things considered, I could never have survived my youth without Wagnerian music. For I seemed condemned to the society of Germans. If a man wishes to rid himself of a feeling of unbearable oppression, he may have to take to hashish. Well, I had to take to Wagner...</quote><quote id="247" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">"The world is poor for him who has never been sick enough for this 'voluptuousness of hell':</quote><quote id="248" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">To become what one is, one must not have the faintest idea what one is.</quote><quote id="249" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">This is the "antinomy": Insofar as we believe in morality we pass sentence on existence.</quote><quote id="250" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Moralities and religions are the principal means by which one can make whatever one wishes out of man, provided one possesses a superfluity of creative forces and can assert one's will over long periods of time — in the form of legislation and customs.</quote><quote id="251" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">A man as he ought to be: that sounds to us as insipid as "a tree as it ought to be."</quote><quote id="252" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">To those human beings who are of any concern to me I wish suffering, desolation, sickness, ill-treatment, indignities — I wish that they should not remain unfamiliar with profound self-contempt, the torture of self-mistrust, the wretchedness of the vanquished: I have no pity for them, because I wish them the only thing that can prove today whether one is worth anything or not — that one endures.</quote><quote id="253" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The stronger becomes master of the weaker, in so far as the latter cannot assert its degree of independence — here there is no mercy, no forbearance, even less a respect for "laws."</quote><quote id="254" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">Morality is: the mediocre are worth more than the exceptions ... I abhore Christianity with a deadly hatred.</quote><quote id="255" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The states in which we infuse a transfiguration and a fullness into things and poetize about them until they reflect back our fullness and joy in life...three elements principally: sexuality, intoxication and cruelty — all belonging to the oldest festal joys.</quote><quote id="256" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The beautiful exists just as little as the true. In every case it is a question of the conditions of preservation of a certain type of man: thus the herd-man will experience the value feeling of the true in different things than will the overman.</quote><quote id="257" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">A declaration of war on the masses by higher men is needed! ... Everything that makes soft and effeminate, that serves the end of the people or the feminine, works in favor of universal suffrage, i.e. the domination of the inferior men. But we should take reprisal and bring this whole affair to light and the bar of judgment.</quote><quote id="258" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The rights a man arrogates to himself are related to the duties he imposes on himself, to the tasks to which he feels equal. The great majority of men have no right to existence, but are a misfortune to higher men.</quote><quote id="259" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The homogenizing of European man ... requires a justification: it lies in serving a higher sovereign species that stands upon the former which can raise itself to its task only by doing this. Not merely a master race whose sole task is to rule, but a race with its own sphere of life, with an excess of strength ... strong enough to have no need of the tyranny of the virtue-imperative.</quote><quote id="260" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">There is only nobility of birth, only nobility of blood. When one speaks of "aristocrats of the spirit," reasons are usually not lacking for concealing something. As is well known, it is a favorite term among ambitious Jews. For spirit alone does not make noble. Rather, there must be something to ennoble the spirit. What then is required? Blood.</quote><quote id="261" author="Friedrich Nietzsche" cats="1900s deaths|German philosophers" ref="">The possibility has been established for the production of...a master race, the future "masters of the earth"...made to endure for millennia — a higher kind of men who...employ democratic Europe as their most pliant and supple instrument for getting hold of the destinies of the earth.</quote></quotes>