<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="el|en|it|ar|cs|az|es|ru|pt|no|tr|lt|pl|bg|hr|de|br|bs|fi|he|sk|sl"><quote id="0" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">In fact, "the whole machinery of our intelligence, our general ideas and laws, fixed and external objects, principles, persons, and gods, are so many symbolic, algebraic expressions." They stand for experience; experience which we are incapable of retaining and surveying in its multitudinous immediacy. We should flounder hopelessly, like the animals, did we not keep ourselves afloat and direct our course by these intellectual devices. "Theory helps us to bear our ignorance of fact."</quote><quote id="1" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Beauty as we feel it is something indescribable: what it is or what it means can never be said.</quote><quote id="2" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Beauty is a pledge of the possible conformity between the soul and nature, and consequently a ground of faith in the supremacy of the good.</quote><quote id="3" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Even the most inspired verse, which boasts not without a relative justification to be immortal, becomes in the course of ages a scarcely legible hieroglyphic; the language it was written in dies, a learned education and an imaginative effort are requisite to catch even a vestige of its original force. Nothing is so irrevocable as mind.</quote><quote id="4" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">"Happiness is the only sanction of life; where happiness fails, existence remains a mad and lamentable experiment."</quote><quote id="5" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">That life is worth living is the most necessary of assumptions and, were it not assumed, the most impossible of conclusions.</quote><quote id="6" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">"Fanaticism consists in redoubling your efforts when you have forgotten your aim."</quote><quote id="7" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Progress, far from consisting in change, depends on retentiveness. When change is absolute there remains no being to improve and no direction is set for possible improvement: and when experience is not retained, as among savages, infancy is perpetual. "Those who cannot remember the past are condemned to repeat it."</quote><quote id="8" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">"The highest form of vanity is love of fame."</quote><quote id="9" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">The human race, in its intellectual life, is organized like the bees: the masculine soul is a worker, sexually atrophied, and essentially dedicated to impersonal and universal arts; the feminine is a queen, infinitely fertile, omnipresent in its brooding industry, but passive and abounding in intuitions without method and passions without justice.</quote><quote id="10" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">To call war the soil of courage and virtue is like calling debauchery the soil of love.</quote><quote id="11" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">It is not society's fault that most men seem to miss their vocation.  Most men have no vocation.</quote><quote id="12" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Injustice in this world is not something comparative; the wrong is deep, clear, and absolute in each private fate.</quote><quote id="13" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">What renders man an imaginative and moral being is that in society he gives new aims to his life which could not have existed in solitude: the aims of friendship, religion, science, and art.  </quote><quote id="14" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Experience has repeatedly confirmed that well-known maxim of Bacon's that "a little philosophy inclineth a man's mind to atheism, but depth in philosophy bringeth men's minds about to religion."  At the same time, when Bacon penned that sage epigram... he forgot to add that "the God to whom depth in philosophy brings back men's minds is far from being the same from whom a little philosophy estranges them."</quote><quote id="15" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Matters of religion should never be matters of controversy. We neither argue with a lover about his taste, nor condemn him, if we are just, for knowing so human a passion. </quote><quote id="16" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Fashion is something barbarous, for it produces innovation without reason and imitation without benefit.</quote><quote id="17" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Happiness is the only sanction of life; where happiness fails, existence remains a mad and lamentable experiment.</quote><quote id="18" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Art like life should be free, since both are experimental.</quote><quote id="19" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">"History is nothing but assisted and recorded memory." It might almost be said to be no science at all, if memory and faith in memory were not what science necessarily rest on. In order to sift evidence we must rely on some witness, and we must trust experience before we proceed to expand it. "The line between what is known scientifically and what has to be assumed in order to support knowledge is impossible to draw. Memory itself is an internal rumour"; and when to this hearsay within the mind we add the falsified echoes that reach us from others, we have but a shifting and unseizable basis to build upon. The picture we frame of the past changes continually and grows every  day less similar to the original experience which it purports to describe.</quote><quote id="20" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">When Socrates and his two great disciples composed a system of rational ethics they were hardly proposing practical legislation for mankind...They were merely writing an eloquent epitaph for their country.</quote><quote id="21" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Oblivious of Democritus, "the unwilling materialists of our day have generally been awkwardly intellectual and quite incapable of laughter." If they have felt anything, they have felt melancholy. Their allegiance and affection were still fixed on those mythical sentimental worlds which they saw to be illusory. The mechanical world they believed in could not please them, in spite of its extent and fertility. Giving rhetorical vent to their spleen and prejudice, they exaggerated nature's meagreness and mathematical dryness. When their imagination was chilled they spoke of nature, most unwarrantably, as dead, and when their judgment was heated they took the next step and called it unreal.</quote><quote id="22" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Let a man once overcome his selfish terror at his own finitude, and his finitude is, in one sense, overcome.</quote><quote id="23" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Perhaps the only true dignity of man is his capacity to despise himself.</quote><quote id="24" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Miracles are propitious accidents, the natural causes of which are too complicated to be readily understood.</quote><quote id="25" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">The Bible is literature, not dogma.</quote><quote id="26" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Professional philosophers are usually only apologists: that is, they are absorbed in defending some vested illusion or some eloquent idea. Like lawyers or detectives, they study the case for which they are retained.</quote><quote id="27" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">In Walt Whitman democracy is carried into psychology and morals. The various sights, moods, and emotions are given each one vote; they are declared to be all free and equal, and the innumerable commonplace moments of life are suffered to speak like the others. Those moments formerly reputed great are not excluded, but they are made to march in the ranks with their companions—plain foot-soldiers and servants of the hour.</quote><quote id="28" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Eternal vigilance is the price of knowledge.</quote><quote id="29" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">The pint would call the quart a dualist, if you tried to pour the quart into him.</quote><quote id="30" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Because the peculiarity of man is that his machinery for reaction on external things has involved an imaginative transcript of these things, which is preserved and suspended in his fancy; and the interest and beauty of this inward landscape, rather than any fortunes that may await his body in the outer world, constitute his proper happiness. By their mind, its scope, quality, and temper, we estimate men, for by the mind only do we exist as men, and are more than so many storage-batteries for material energy. Let us therefore be frankly human. Let us be content to live in the mind.</quote><quote id="31" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">England is the paradise of individuality, eccentricity, heresy, anomalies, hobbies, and humors.</quote><quote id="32" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">The world is a perpetual caricature of itself; at every moment it is the mockery and the contradiction of what it is pretending to be.</quote><quote id="33" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">"There is no cure for birth and death save to enjoy the interval."</quote><quote id="34" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">"I like to walk about amidst the beautiful things that adorn the world; but private wealth I should decline, or any sort of personal possessions, because they would take away my liberty."</quote><quote id="35" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">"Only the dead have seen the end of war."</quote><quote id="36" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">"My atheism, like that of Spinoza, is true piety towards the universe and denies only gods fashioned by men in their own image, to be servants of their human interests."</quote><quote id="37" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">The living have never shown me how to live.</quote><quote id="38" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">"Profound skepticism is favorable to conventions, because it doubts that the criticism of conventions is any truer than they are."</quote><quote id="39" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">All living souls welcome whatever they are ready to cope with; all else they ignore, or pronounce to be monstrous and wrong, or deny to be possible. </quote><quote id="40" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">The young man who has not wept is a savage, and the older man who will not laugh is a fool.</quote><quote id="41" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Philosophers are as jealous as women. Each wants a monopoly of praise.</quote><quote id="42" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">Religion in its humility restores man to his only dignity, the courage to live by grace.</quote><quote id="43" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">American life is a powerful solvent. As it stamps the immigrant, almost before he can speak English, with an unmistakable muscular tension, cheery self-confidence and habitual challenge in the voice and eyes, so it seems to neutralize every intellectual element, however tough and alien it may be, and to fuse it in the native good-will, complacency, thoughtlessness, and optimism.</quote><quote id="44" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">All his life he [the American] jumps into the train after it has started and jumps out before it has stopped; and he never once gets left behind, or breaks a leg.</quote><quote id="45" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">O world, thou choosest not the better part!
It is not wisdom to be only wise,
And on the inward vision close the eyes,
But it is wisdom to believe the heart.
Columbus found a world, and had no chart,
Save one that faith deciphered in the skies;
To trust the soul’s invincible surmise
Was all his science and his only art. </quote><quote id="46" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">In the Gospels, for instance, we sometimes find the kingdom of heaven illustrated by principles drawn from observation of this world rather than from an ideal conception of justice; ...  They remind us that the God we are seeking is present and active, that he is the living God; they are doubtless necessary if we are to keep religion from passing into a mere idealism and God into the vanishing point of our thought and endeavour.</quote><quote id="47" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">"There is nothing impossible in the existence of the supernatural: its existence seems to me decidedly probable."</quote><quote id="48" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">They [the wise spirits of antiquity in the first circle of Dante's "Inferno"] are condemned, Dante tells us, to no other penalty than to live in desire without hope, a fate appropriate to noble souls with a clear vision of life.</quote><quote id="49" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">"Skepticism, like chastity, should not be relinquished too readily."</quote><quote id="50" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">I leave you but the sound of many a word
In mocking echoes haply overheard,
I sang to heaven. My exile made me free,
from world to world, from all worlds carried me.</quote><quote id="51" author="George Santayana" cats="1950s deaths|American poets|Aphorists|Novelists|Philosophers|Spanish poets" ref="">The idea of Christ is much older than Christianity.</quote></quotes>