<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="en|ca|it|ar|cs|az|es|ru|pt|tr|lt|pl|be|fr|bg|de|hu|fa|bs|fi|he|ka|sr|ko|sk|uk|sl"><quote id="0" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Nothing is a greater stranger to my breast, or a sin that my soul more abhors, than that black and detestable one, ingratitude."</quote><quote id="1" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"There is a Destiny which has the control of our actions, not to be resisted by the strongest efforts of Human Nature."</quote><quote id="2" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Discipline is the soul of an army. It makes small numbers formidable; procures success to the weak, and esteem to all."</quote><quote id="3" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">The General is sorry to be informed —, that the foolish and wicked practice of profane cursing and swearing, a vice heretofore little known in an American army, is growing into a fashion; — he hopes the officers will, by example as well as influence, endeavor to check it, and that both they and the men will reflect that we can have little hope of the blessing of Heaven on our arms, if we insult it by impiety and folly; added to this, it is a vice so mean and low, without any temptation, that every man of sense and character detests and despises it.</quote><quote id="4" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">Unhappy it is though to reflect, that a Brother's Sword has been sheathed in a Brother's breast, and that, "the once happy and peaceful plains of America are either to be drenched with Blood, or Inhabited by Slaves. Sad alternative! But can a virtuous Man hesitate in his choice?"</quote><quote id="5" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"But lest some unlucky event should happen unfavorable to my reputation, I beg it may be remembered by every gentleman in the room that I this day declare with the utmost sincerity, I do not think myself equal to the command I am honored with."</quote><quote id="6" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Every post is honorable in which a man can serve his country."</quote><quote id="7" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">The reflection upon my situation, and that of this army, produces many an uneasy hour, when all around me are wrapped in sleep. "Few people know the predicament we are in, on a thousand accounts; fewer still will believe, if any disaster happens to these lines, from what cause it flows." I have often thought how much happier I should have been, if instead of accepting of a command under such circumstances, I had taken my musket upon my shoulders and entered the rank, or if I could have justified the measure of posterity, and my own conscience, had retired to the back country, and lived in a wigwam. If I shall be able to rise superior to these, and many other difficulties which might be enumerated, I shall most religiously believe that the finger of Providence is in it, to blind the eyes of our enemies; for surely if we get well through this month, it must be for want of their knowing the disadvantages we labor under. Could I have foreseen the difficulties which have come upon us, could I have known that such a backwardness would have been discovered in the old soldiers to the service, all the generals upon earth should not have convinced me of the propriety of delaying an attack upon Boston till this time.</quote><quote id="8" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">To expect ... the same service from raw and undisciplined recruits, as from veteran soldiers, is to expect what never did and perhaps never will happen. Men, who are familiarized to danger, meet it without shrinking; whereas troops unused to service often apprehend danger where no danger is.</quote><quote id="9" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Let us therefore animate and encourage each other, and show the whole world that a Freeman, contending for liberty on his own ground, is superior to any slavish mercenary on earth."</quote><quote id="10" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"The General hopes and trusts that every officer and man will endeavor to live and act as becomes a Christian soldier defending the dearest rights and liberties of his country."</quote><quote id="11" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"The time is now near at hand which must probably determine whether Americans are to be freemen or slaves"; whether they are to have any property they can call their own; whether their houses and farms are to be pillaged and destroyed, and themselves consigned to a state of wretchedness from which no human efforts will deliver them. "The fate of unborn millions will now depend, under God, on the courage and conduct of this army. Our cruel and unrelenting enemy leaves us only the choice of brave resistance, or the most abject submission. We have, therefore, to resolve to conquer or die."</quote><quote id="12" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">There is nothing that gives a man consequence, and renders him fit for command, like a support that renders him independent of everybody but the State he serves.</quote><quote id="13" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"To place any dependence upon militia, is, assuredly, resting upon a broken staff. "Men just dragged from the tender scenes of domestic life - unaccustomed to the din of arms - totally unacquainted with every kind of military skill, which being followed by a want of confidence in themselves when opposed to troops regularly trained, disciplined, and appointed, superior in knowledge, and superior in arms, makes them timid and ready to fly from their own shadows.</quote><quote id="14" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">My brave fellows, you have done all I asked you to do, and more than can be reasonably expected; but your country is at stake, your wives, your houses and all that you hold dear. You have worn yourselves out with fatigues and hardships, but we know not how to spare you. If you will consent to stay one month longer, you will render that service to the cause of liberty, and to your country, which you probably can never do under any other circumstances.</quote><quote id="15" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">Parade with me my brave fellows, we will have them soon!</quote><quote id="16" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">While we are zealously performing the duties of good citizens and soldiers, we certainly ought not to be inattentive to the higher duties of religion. To the distinguished character of Patriot, it should be our highest glory to add the more distinguished character of Christian.</quote><quote id="17" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Few men have virtue to withstand the highest bidder."</quote><quote id="18" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">No distance can keep anxious lovers long asunder.</quote><quote id="19" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"A slender acquaintance with the world must convince every man, that actions, not words, are the true criterion of the attachment of his friends, and that the most liberal professions of good will are very far from being the surest marks of it." I should be happy that my own experience had afforded fewer examples of the little dependence to be placed upon them.</quote><quote id="20" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">Example, whether it be good or bad, has a powerful influence.</quote><quote id="21" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">Without a decisive naval force we can do nothing definitive. And with it, everything honorable and glorious.</quote><quote id="22" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Be courteous to all, but intimate with few," and let those few be well tried before you give them your confidence; true friendship is a plant of slow growth, and must undergo and withstand the shocks of adversity before it is entitled to the appellation.</quote><quote id="23" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"If men are to be precluded from offering their sentiments on a matter which may involve the most serious and alarming consequences that can invite the consideration of mankind, reason is of no use to us; the freedom of speech may be taken away, and dumb and silent we may be led, like sheep to the slaughter."</quote><quote id="24" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">Gentlemen, you will permit me to put on my spectacles, for, I have grown not only gray, but almost blind in the service of my country.</quote><quote id="25" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"You will, by the dignity of your Conduct, afford occasion for Posterity to say, when speaking of the glorious example you have exhibited to Mankind, had this day been wanting, the World had never seen the last stage of perfection to which human nature is capable of attaining."</quote><quote id="26" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Happy, thrice happy shall they be pronounced hereafter, who have contributed any thing, who have performed the meanest office in erecting this stupendous fabrick of Freedom and Empire on the broad basis of Independency; who have assisted in protecting the rights of humane nature and establishing an Asylum for the poor and oppressed of all nations and religions."</quote><quote id="27" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"It may be laid down, as a primary position, and the basis of our system, that every citizen who enjoys the protection of a free government, owes not only a proportion of his property, but even of his personal services to the defence of it", and consequently that the Citizens of America (with a few legal and official exceptions) from 18 to 50 Years of Age should be borne on the Militia Rolls, provided with uniform Arms, and so far accustomed to the use of them, that the Total strength of the Country might be called forth at Short Notice on any very interesting Emergency.</quote><quote id="28" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Arbitrary power is most easily established on the ruins of liberty abused to licentiousness."</quote><quote id="29" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">I now make it my earnest prayer, that God would have you, and the State over which you preside, in his holy protection; that he would incline the hearts of the citizens to cultivate a spirit of subordination and obedience to Government; to entertain a brotherly affection and love for one another, for their fellow citizens of the United States at large; and, particularly, for their brethren who have served in the Geld; and finally, that he would most graciously be pleased to dispose us all to do justice, to love mercy, and to demean ourselves with that charity, humility, and pacifick temper of the mind, which were the characteristicks of the divine Author of our blessed religion ; without an humble imitation of whose example, in these things, we can never hope to be a happy Nation.</quote><quote id="30" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Having now finished the work assigned me, I retire from the great theatre of Action"; and bidding an Affectionate farewell to this August body under whose orders I have so long acted, I here offer my commission, and take my leave of all the employments of public life.</quote><quote id="31" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">I am become a private citizen on the banks of the Potomac, and under the shadow of my own Vine and my own Fig-tree, free from the bustle of a camp and the busy scenes of public life, I am solacing myself with those tranquil enjoyments, of which the Soldier who is ever in pursuit of fame, the Statesman whose watchful days and sleepless nights are spent in devising schemes to promote the welfare of his own, perhaps the ruin of other countries, as if this globe was insufficient for us all, and the Courtier who is always watching the countenance of his Prince, in hopes of catching a gracious smile, can have very little conception. I am not only retired from all public employments, but I am retiring within myself; and shall be able to view the solitary walk, and tread the paths of private life with heartfelt satisfaction. "Envious of none, I am determined to be pleased with all; and this my dear friend, being the order for my march, I will move gently down the stream of life, until I sleep with my Fathers."</quote><quote id="32" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">A people... who are possessed of the spirit of commerce, who see and who will pursue their advantages may achieve almost anything.</quote><quote id="33" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Democratical States must always feel before they can see: it is this that makes their Governments slow, but the people will be right at last."</quote><quote id="34" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"My first wish is, to see this plague of mankind banished from the earth, and the sons and daughters of this world employed in more pleasing and innocent amusements, than in preparing implements, and exercising them, for the destruction of mankind."</quote><quote id="35" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"My manner of living is plain. I do not mean to be put out of it." A glass of wine and a bit of mutton are always ready; and such as will be content to partake of them are always welcome. "Those, who expect more, will be disappointed, but no change will be effected by it."</quote><quote id="36" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"If you tell the Legislatures they have violated the treaty of peace and invaded the prerogatives of the confederacy they will laugh in your face. What then is to be done? Things cannot go on in the same train forever." It is much to be feared, as you observe, that the better kind of people being disgusted with the circumstances will have their minds prepared for any revolution whatever. "We are apt to run from one extreme into another. To anticipate &amp; prevent disasterous [sic] contingencies would be the part of wisdom &amp; patriotism."
"What astonishing changes a few years are capable of producing! I am told that even respectable characters speak of a monarchical form of government without horror." From thinking proceeds speaking, thence to acting is often but a single step. But how irrevocable &amp; tremendous! What a triumph for the advocates of despotism to find that we are incapable of governing ourselves, and that systems founded on the basis of equal liberty are merely ideal &amp; falacious![sic] Would to God that wise measures may be taken in time to avert the consequences we have but too much reason to apprehend.
Retired as I am from the world, I frankly acknowledge I cannot feel myself an unconcerned spectator. Yet having happily assisted in bringing the ship into port &amp; having been fairly discharged; it is not my business to embark again on a sea of troubles. Nor could it be expected that my sentiments and opinions would have much weight on the minds of my Countrymen — they have been neglected, tho' given as a last legacy in the most solemn manner. I had then perhaps some claims to public attention. I consider myself as having none at present.</quote><quote id="37" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"If they have real grievances redress them, if possible; or acknowledge the justice of them, and your inability to do it at the moment. If they have not, employ the force of government against them at once."</quote><quote id="38" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"The only stipulations I shall contend for are, that in all things you shall do as you please. I will do the same; and that no ceremony may be used or any restraint be imposed on any one."</quote><quote id="39" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"The preservation of the sacred fire of liberty, and the destiny of the republican model of government, are justly considered as deeply, perhaps as finally staked, on the experiment entrusted to the hands of the American people."</quote><quote id="40" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">For myself the delay may be compared with a reprieve; for in confidence I assure you, with the world it would obtain little credit that "my movements to the chair of Government will be accompanied by feelings not unlike those of a culprit who is going to the place of his execution: so unwilling am I, in the evening of a life nearly consumed in public cares, to quit a peaceful abode for an Ocean of difficulties", without that competency of political skill, abilities and inclination which is necessary to manage the helm.</quote><quote id="41" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">In executing the duties of my present important station, I can promise nothing but purity of intentions, and, in carrying these into effect, fidelity and diligence.</quote><quote id="42" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Happiness and moral duty are inseparably connected."</quote><quote id="43" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">Impressed with a conviction that the due administration of justice is the firmest pillar of good Government, I have considered the first arrangement of the Judicial department as essential to the happiness of our Country, and to the stability of its political system; hence the selection of the fittest characters to expound the law, and dispense justice, has been an invariable object of my anxious concern.</quote><quote id="44" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"The Citizens of the United States of America have a right to applaud themselves for giving to Mankind examples of an enlarged and liberal policy: a policy worthy of imitation." All possess alike liberty of conscience and immunities of citizenship. "It is now no more that toleration is spoken of, as if it was by the indulgence of one class of people that another enjoyed the exercise of their inherent natural rights. For happily the Government of the United States, which gives to bigotry no sanction, to persecution no assistance, requires only that they who live under its protection should demean themselves as good citizens in giving it on all occasions their effectual support."&lt;br/&gt;May the Children of the Stock of Abraham, who dwell in this land, continue to merit and enjoy the good will of the other Inhabitants; while every one shall sit under his own vine and fig tree, and there shall be none to make him afraid.</quote><quote id="45" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"To be prepared for war is one of the most effectual means of preserving peace."</quote><quote id="46" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"A free people ought not only to be armed, but disciplined; to which end a uniform and well-digested plan is requisite; and their safety and interest require that they should promote such manufactories as tend to render them independent of others for essential, particularly military, supplies."</quote><quote id="47" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"All see, and most admire, the glare which hovers round the external trappings of elevated office. To me there is nothing in it, beyond the lustre which may be reflected from its connection with a power of promoting human felicity. "</quote><quote id="48" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"It is better to offer no excuse than a bad one."</quote><quote id="49" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Religious controversies are always productive of more acrimony and irreconcilable hatreds than those which spring from any other cause; and I was not without hopes that the enlightened and liberal policy of the present age would have put an effectual stop to contentions of this kind."</quote><quote id="50" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Of all the animosities which have existed among mankind, those which are caused by difference of sentiments in religion appear to be the most inveterate and distressing, and ought most to be deprecated." I was in hopes that the enlightened and liberal policy, which has marked the present age, would at least have reconciled Christians of every denomination so far that we should never again see the religious disputes carried to such a pitch as to endanger the peace of society.</quote><quote id="51" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">To enlarge the sphere of social happiness is worthy of the benevolent design of a Masonic institution; and it is most fervently to be wished, that the conduct of every member of the fraternity, as well as those publications, that discover the principles which actuate them, may tend to convince mankind that the grand object of Masonry is to promote the happiness of the human race.</quote><quote id="52" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"We have abundant reason to rejoice, that, in this land, the light of truth and reason has triumphed over the power of bigotry and superstition, and that every person may here worship God according to the dictates of his own heart." In this enlightened age, &amp; in this land of equal liberty, it is our boast, that a man's religious tenets will not forfeit the protection of the laws, nor deprive him of the right of attaining &amp; holding the highest offices that are known in the United States. 
Your prayers for my present and future felicity are received with gratitude; and I sincerely wish, Gentlemen, that you may in your social and individual capacities taste those blessings, which a gracious God bestows upon the righteous.</quote><quote id="53" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"The friends of humanity will deprecate War, wheresoever it may appear; and we have experience enough of its evils, in this country, to know, that it should not be wantonly or unnecessarily entered upon." I trust, that the good citizens of the United States will show to the world, that they have as much wisdom in preserving peace at this critical juncture, as they have hitherto displayed valor in defending their just rights.</quote><quote id="54" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Make the most of the Indian hemp seed, and sow it everywhere!"</quote><quote id="55" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"When one side only of a story is heard and often repeated, the human mind becomes impressed with it insensibly."</quote><quote id="56" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Rise early, that by habit it may become familiar, agreeable, healthy, and profitable." It may, for a while, be irksome to do this, but that will wear off; and the practice will produce a rich harvest forever thereafter; whether in public or private walks of life.</quote><quote id="57" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"It is infinitely better to have a few good men than many indifferent ones."</quote><quote id="58" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"It was not my intention to doubt that, the Doctrines of the Illuminati, and principles of Jacobinism had not spread in the United States. On the contrary, no one is more truly satisfied of this fact than I am."
The idea that I meant to convey, was, that I did not believe that the "Lodges" of Free Masons in "this" Country had, as "Societies", endeavoured to propagate the diabolical tenets of the first, or pernicious principles of the latter (if they are susceptible of seperation[sic]). That Individuals of them may have done it, or that the "founder", or "instrument" employed to found, the Democratic Societies in the United States, may have had these objects; and actually had a seperation[sic] of the "People" from their "Government" in view, is too evident to be questioned.</quote><quote id="59" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">I am principled against this kind of traffic in the human species... and to disperse the families I have an aversion.</quote><quote id="60" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"I die hard but am not afraid to go". I believed from my first attack that I should not survive it — my breath cannot last long.</quote><quote id="61" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Tis well."</quote><quote id="62" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"For the sake of humanity, it is devoutly to be wished that the manly employment of agriculture, and the humanizing benefit of commerce, would supersede the waste of war and the rage of conquest; that the swords might be turned into ploughshares, the spears into pruning-hooks, and, as the Scriptures express it, "the nations learn war no more.""</quote><quote id="63" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"I had rather be in my grave than in my present situation, I had rather be on my farm than be emperor of the world; and yet they charge me with wanting to be a king."</quote><quote id="64" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Every day the increasing weight of years admonishes me more and more, that the shade of retirement is as necessary to me as it will be welcome." Satisfied, that, if any circumstances have given peculiar value to my services, they were temporary, "I have the consolation to believe, that, while choice and prudence invite me to quit the political scene, patriotism does not forbid it."</quote><quote id="65" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Interwoven as is the love of liberty with every ligament of your hearts, no recommendation of mine is necessary to fortify or confirm the attachment." &lt;br/&gt; The unity of Government, which constitutes you one people, is also now dear to you. It is justly so; for it is a main pillar in the edifice of your real independence, the support of your tranquillity at home, your peace abroad; of your safety; of your prosperity; of that very Liberty, which you so highly prize.</quote><quote id="66" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"It is of infinite moment, that you should properly estimate the immense value of your national Union to your collective and individual happiness"; that you should cherish a cordial, habitual, and immovable attachment to it; accustoming yourselves to think and speak of it as of the Palladium of your political safety and prosperity; watching for its preservation with jealous anxiety; discountenancing whatever may suggest even a suspicion, that it can in any event be abandoned; and indignantly frowning upon the first dawning of every attempt to alienate any portion of our country from the rest, or to enfeeble the sacred ties which now link together the various parts.</quote><quote id="67" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">While, then, every part of our country thus feels an immediate and particular interest in Union, all the parts combined cannot fail to find in the united mass of means and efforts greater strength, greater resource, proportionably greater security from external danger, a less frequent interruption of their peace by foreign nations; and, what is of inestimable value, they must derive from Union an exemption from those broils and wars between themselves, which so frequently afflict neighbouring countries not tied together by the same governments, which their own rivalships alone would be sufficient to produce, but which opposite foreign alliances, attachments, and intrigues would stimulate and embitter. "Hence, likewise, they will avoid the necessity of those overgrown military establishments, which, under any form of government, are inauspicious to liberty, and which are to be regarded as particularly hostile to Republican Liberty." In this sense it is, that your Union ought to be considered as a main prop of your liberty, and that the love of the one ought to endear to you the preservation of the other.</quote><quote id="68" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"One of the expedients of party to acquire influence, within particular districts, is to misrepresent the opinions and aims of other districts. "You cannot shield yourselves too much against the jealousies and heart-burnings, which spring from these misrepresentations; they tend to render alien to each other those, who ought to be bound together by fraternal affection.</quote><quote id="69" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"To the efficacy and permanency of your Union, a Government for the whole is indispensable." No alliances, however strict, between the parts can be an adequate substitute; they must inevitably experience the infractions and interruptions, which all alliances in all times have experienced. Sensible of this momentous truth, you have improved upon your first essay, by the adoption of a Constitution of Government better calculated than your former for an intimate Union, and for the efficacious management of your common concerns.</quote><quote id="70" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"The basis of our political systems is the right of the people to make and to alter their Constitutions of Government. But the Constitution which at any time exists, till changed by an explicit and authentic act of the whole people, is sacredly obligatory upon all." The very idea of the power and the right of the people to establish Government presupposes the duty of every individual to obey the established Government.</quote><quote id="71" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">I have already intimated to you the danger of parties in the state, with particular reference to the founding of them on geographical discriminations. "Let me now take a more comprehensive view, and warn you in the most solemn manner against the baneful effects of the spirit of party, generally."</quote><quote id="72" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"The alternate domination of one faction over another, sharpened by the spirit of revenge, natural to party dissension, which in different ages and countries has perpetrated the most horrid enormities, is itself a frightful despotism." But this leads at length to a more formal and permanent despotism. "The disorders and miseries, which result, gradually incline the minds of men to seek security and repose in the absolute power of an individual; and sooner or later the chief of some prevailing faction, more able or more fortunate than his competitors, turns this disposition to the purposes of his own elevation, on the ruins of Public Liberty."</quote><quote id="73" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"The common and continual mischiefs of the spirit of party are sufficient to make it the interest and duty of a wise people to discourage and restrain it. "&lt;br/&gt; It serves always to distract the Public Councils, and enfeeble the Public Administration. It agitates the Community with ill-founded jealousies and false alarms; kindles the animosity of one part against another, foments occasionally riot and insurrection.</quote><quote id="74" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Of all the dispositions and habits, which lead to political prosperity, Religion and Morality are indispensable supports." In vain would that man claim the tribute of Patriotism, who should labor to subvert these great pillars of human happiness, these firmest props of the duties of Men and Citizens. The mere Politician, equally with the pious man, ought to respect and to cherish them. A volume could not trace all their connexions with private and public felicity.</quote><quote id="75" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">Let us with caution indulge the supposition, that morality can be maintained without religion. Whatever may be conceded to the influence of refined education on minds of peculiar structure, reason and experience both forbid us to expect, that national morality can prevail in exclusion of religious principle.</quote><quote id="76" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"It is substantially true, that virtue or morality is a necessary spring of popular government. The rule, indeed, extends with more or less force to every species of free government."</quote><quote id="77" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Promote, then, as an object of primary importance, institutions for the general diffusion of knowledge. In proportion as the structure of a government gives force to public opinion, it is essential that public opinion should be enlightened."</quote><quote id="78" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">As a very important source of strength and security, cherish public credit. One method of preserving it is, to use it as sparingly as possible; avoiding occasions of expense by cultivating peace, but remembering also that timely disbursements to prepare for danger frequently prevent much greater disbursements to repel it; avoiding likewise the accumulation of debt, not only by shunning occasions of expense, but by vigorous exertions in time of peace to discharge the debts, which unavoidable wars may have occasioned, not ungenerously throwing upon posterity the burthen, which we ourselves ought to bear.</quote><quote id="79" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Observe good faith and justice towards all Nations; cultivate peace and harmony with all." Religion and Morality enjoin this conduct; and can it be, that good policy does not equally enjoin it? It will be worthy of a free, enlightened, and, at no distant period, a great Nation, to give to mankind the magnanimous and too novel example of a people always guided by an exalted justice and benevolence. Who can doubt, that, in the course of time and things, the fruits of such a plan would richly repay any temporary advantages, which might be lost by a steady adherence to it? Can it be, that Providence has not connected the permanent felicity of a Nation with its Virtue?</quote><quote id="80" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Nothing is more essential, than that permanent, inveterate antipathies against particular Nations, and passionate attachments for others, should be excluded; and that, in place of them, just and amicable feelings towards all should be cultivated." The Nation, which indulges towards another an habitual hatred, or an habitual fondness, is in some degree a slave. It is a slave to its animosity or to its affection, either of which is sufficient to lead it astray from its duty and its interest. Antipathy in one nation against another disposes each more readily to offer insult and injury, to lay hold of slight causes of umbrage, and to be haughty and intractable, when accidental or trifling occasions of dispute occur. Hence frequent collisions, obstinate, envenomed, and bloody contests.</quote><quote id="81" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">Real Patriots, who may resist the intrigues of the favourite, are liable to become suspected and odious; while its tools and dupes usurp the applause and confidence of the people, to surrender their interests. (Note: spelling/capitalization likely original.[http://www.bartleby.com/43/24.html]).</quote><quote id="82" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">The great rule of conduct for us, in regard to foreign nations, is, in extending our commercial relations, to have with them as little political connexion as possible. So far as we have already formed engagements, let them be fulfilled with perfect good faith. Here let us stop.</quote><quote id="83" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">" 'Tis our true policy to steer clear of permanent alliances with any portion of the foreign world"; so far, I mean, as we are now at liberty to do it; for let me not be understood as capable of patronizing infidelity to existing engagements. "I hold the maxim no less applicable to public than to private affairs, that honesty is always the best policy." I repeat it, therefore, let those engagements be observed in their genuine sense. But, in my opinion, it is unnecessary and would be unwise to extend them.</quote><quote id="84" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">There can be no greater error than to expect or calculate upon real favors from nation to nation.</quote><quote id="85" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">"Harmony, liberal intercourse with all nations, are recommended by policy, humanity, and interest."</quote><quote id="86" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">In offering to you, my countrymen, these counsels of an old and affectionate friend, I dare not hope they will make the strong and lasting impression I could wish; that they will control the usual current of the passions, or prevent our nation from running the course, which has hitherto marked the destiny of nations. "But, if I may even flatter myself, that they may be productive of some partial benefit, some occasional good; that they may now and then recur to moderate the fury of party spirit, to warn against the mischiefs of foreign intrigue, to guard against the impostures of pretended patriotism; this hope will be a full recompense for the solicitude for your welfare, by which they have been dictated."</quote><quote id="87" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">The duty of holding a neutral conduct may be inferred, without any thing more, from the obligation which justice and humanity impose on every nation, in cases in which it is free to act, to maintain inviolate the relations of peace and amity towards other nations.</quote><quote id="88" author="George Washington" cats="Founding Fathers|Military leaders|Political leaders|Politicians|United States Presidents|Virginians" ref="">Though, in reviewing the incidents of my administration, I am unconscious of intentional error, I am nevertheless too sensible of my defects not to think it probable that I may have committed many errors. Whatever they may be, I fervently beseech the Almighty to avert or mitigate the evils to which they may tend. I shall also carry with me the hope, that my Country will never cease to view them with indulgence; and that, after forty-five years of my life dedicated to its service with an upright zeal, the faults of incompetent abilities will be consigned to oblivion, as myself must soon be to the mansions of rest.</quote></quotes>