<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="en|pt|de|tr|it|fi"><quote id="0" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">All right, have it your way - you heard a seal bark!</quote><quote id="1" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">"Le coeur a ses raisons, "Mrs. Bence", que la raison ne connait pas." </quote><quote id="2" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Well, if I called the wrong number, why did you answer the phone?</quote><quote id="3" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">I love the idea of there being two sexes, don't you?</quote><quote id="4" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">He knows all about art, but he doesn't know what he likes.</quote><quote id="5" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">It's a naïve domestic Burgundy without any breeding, but I think you'll be amused by its presumption.</quote><quote id="6" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Precision of communication is important, more important than ever, in our era of hair trigger balances, when a false or misunderstood word may create as much disaster as a sudden thoughtless act.</quote><quote id="7" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">There are two kinds of light — the glow that illumines, and the glare that obscures.</quote><quote id="8" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">A burden in the bush is worth two on your hands.</quote><quote id="9" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">It is better to ask some of the questions than to know all the answers.</quote><quote id="10" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">There is no safety in numbers, or in anything else.</quote><quote id="11" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Early to rise and early to bed makes a male healthy and wealthy and dead.</quote><quote id="12" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">You might as well fall flat on your face as lean over too far backward.</quote><quote id="13" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">You can fool too many of the people too much of the time.</quote><quote id="14" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Once upon a sunny morning a man who sat in a breakfast nook looked up from his scrambled eggs to see a white unicorn with a golden horn quietly cropping the roses in the garden. The man went up to the bedroom where his wife was still asleep and woke her. "There's a unicorn in the garden," he said. "Eating roses." She opened one unfriendly eye and looked at him. "The unicorn is a mythical beast," she said, and turned her back on him. The man walked slowly downstairs and out into the garden. The unicorn was still there; he was now browsing among the tulips. </quote><quote id="15" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Don't count your boobies until they are hatched.</quote><quote id="16" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">He who hesitates is sometimes saved.</quote><quote id="17" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Don't get it right, just get it written.</quote><quote id="18" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">It is better to have loafed and lost, than never to have loafed at all.</quote><quote id="19" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Nowadays most men lead lives of noisy desperation.</quote><quote id="20" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Love is blind, but desire just doesn't give a good goddam. (sic)</quote><quote id="21" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">A word to the wise is not sufficient if it doesn't make any sense.</quote><quote id="22" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">All men kill the thing they hate, too, unless, of course, it kills them first.</quote><quote id="23" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">All men should strive to learn before they die what they are running from, and to, and why.</quote><quote id="24" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">The pounding of the cylinders increased: "ta-pocketa-pocketa-pocketa-pocketa-pocketa".</quote><quote id="25" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">"To hell with the handkerchief," said Walter Mitty scornfully. He took one last drag on his cigarette and snapped it away. Then, with that faint, fleeting smile playing about his lips, he faced the firing squad; erect and motionless, proud and disdainful, Walter Mitty the Undefeated, inscrutable to the last.</quote><quote id="26" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">"Who are you?" the minstrel asked. "I am the Golux," said the Golux, proudly, "the only Golux in the world, and not a mere Device."</quote><quote id="27" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Boys are perhaps beyond the range of anybody's sure understanding, at least when they are between the ages of eighteen months and ninety years.</quote><quote id="28" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">A pinch of probability is worth a pound of perhaps.</quote><quote id="29" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Now I am not a cat man, but a dog man, and all felines can tell this at a glance — a sharp, vindictive glance.</quote><quote id="30" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Man has gone long enough, or even too long, without being man enough to face the simple truth that the trouble with Man is Man.</quote><quote id="31" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">The only rules comedy can tolerate are those of taste, and the only limitations those of libel.</quote><quote id="32" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Discussion in America means dissent.</quote><quote id="33" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Somebody has said that woman's place is in the wrong. That's fine. What the wrong needs is a woman's presence and a woman's touch. She is far better equipped than men to set it right.</quote><quote id="34" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">If I have sometimes seemed to make fun of Woman, I assure you it has only been for the purpose of egging her on.</quote><quote id="35" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">She came naturally by her confused and groundless fears, for her own mother lived the latter years of her life in the horrible suspicion that electricity was dripping invisibly all over the house. </quote><quote id="36" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">In order to be eligible to play it was necessary for him to keep up in his studies, a very difficult matter, for while he was not dumber than an ox he was not any smarter.</quote><quote id="37" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">I do not have a psychiatrist and I do not want one, for the simple reason that if he listened to me long enough, he might become disturbed. </quote><quote id="38" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Every time is a time for comedy in a world of tension that would languish without it. But I cannot confine myself to lightness in a period of human life that demands light ... We all know that, as the old adage has it, "It is later than you think." ..., but I also say occasionally: "It is lighter than you think." In this light let's not look back in anger, or forward in fear, but around in awareness.</quote><quote id="39" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">The dog has got more fun out of Man than Man has got out of the dog, for the clearly demonstrable reason that Man is the more laughable of the two animals.</quote><quote id="40" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">The dog has seldom been successful in pulling Man up to its level of sagacity, but Man has frequently dragged the dog down to his.</quote><quote id="41" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">I am not a dog lover. A dog lover to me means a dog that is in love with another dog.</quote><quote id="42" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">He picked out this sentence in a "New Yorker" casual of mine: "After dinner, the men moved into the living room," and he wanted to know why I, or the editors, had put in the comma. I could explain that one all night. I wrote back that this particular comma was Ross's way of giving the men time to push back their chairs and stand up.</quote><quote id="43" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">From now on, I think it is safe to predict, neither the Democratic nor the Republican Party will ever nominate for President a candidate without good looks, stage presence, theatrical delivery, and a sense of timing.</quote><quote id="44" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">A drawing is always dragged down to the level of its caption.</quote><quote id="45" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">But those rare souls whose spirit gets magically into the hearts of men, leave behind them something more real and warmly personal than bodily presence, an ineffable and eternal thing. It is everlasting life touching us as something more than a vague, recondite concept. The sound of a great name dies like an echo; the splendor of fame fades into nothing; but the grace of a fine spirit pervades the places through which it has passed, like the haunting loveliness of mignonette.</quote><quote id="46" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Sophistication might be described as the ability to cope gracefully with a situation involving the presence of a formidable menace to one's poise and prestige (such as the butler, or the man under the bed — but never the husband).</quote><quote id="47" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Speed is scarcely the noblest virtue of graphic composition, but it has its curious rewards. There is a sense of getting somewhere fast, which satisfies a native American urge.</quote><quote id="48" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Comedy has to be done "en clair". You can't blunt the edge of wit or the point of satire with obscurity. Try to imagine a famous witty saying that is not immediately clear.</quote><quote id="49" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">With 60 staring me in the face, I have developed inflammation of the sentence structure and a definite hardening of the paragraphs.</quote><quote id="50" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">The laughter of man is more terrible than his tears, and takes more forms — hollow, heartless, mirthless, maniacal.</quote><quote id="51" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">I always begin at the left with the opening word of the sentence and read toward the right and I recommend this method.</quote><quote id="52" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">When all things are equal, translucence in writing is more effective than transparency, just as glow is more revealing than glare.</quote><quote id="53" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Editing should be, especially in the case of old writers, a counseling rather than a collaborating task. The tendency of the writer-editor to collaborate is natural, but he should say to himself, "How can I help this writer to say it better in his own style?" and avoid "How can I show him how I would write it, if it were my piece?"</quote><quote id="54" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">The wit makes fun of other persons; the satirist makes fun of the world; the humorist makes fun of himself, but in so doing, he identifies himself with people — that is, people everywhere, not for the purpose of taking them apart, but simply revealing their true nature.</quote><quote id="55" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">We all know that the theater and every play that comes to Broadway have within themselves, like the human being, the seed of self-destruction and the certainty of death. The thing is to see how long the theater, the play, and the human being can last in spite of themselves.</quote><quote id="56" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">If a playwright tried to see eye to eye with everybody, he would get the worst case of strabismus since Hannibal lost an eye trying to count his nineteen elephants during a snowstorm while crossing the Alps.</quote><quote id="57" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">Humor is emotional chaos remembered in tranquility.</quote><quote id="58" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">My drawings have been described as pre-intentionalist, meaning that they were finished before the ideas for them had occurred to me. I shall not argue the point.</quote><quote id="59" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">I’m 65 and I guess that puts me in with the geriatrics. But if there were fifteen months in every year, I’d only be 48. That’s the trouble with us. We number everything. Take women, for example. I think they deserve to have more than twelve years between the ages of 28 and 40.</quote><quote id="60" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">One (martini) is all right, two is too many, three is not enough.</quote><quote id="61" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">My opposition lies in the fact that offhand answers have little value or grace of expression, and that such oral give and take helps to perpetuate the decline of the English language.</quote><quote id="62" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">The difference between our decadence and the Russians is that while theirs is brutal, ours is apathetic.</quote><quote id="63" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">[http://home.earthlink.net/~ritter/thurber/ Thurber's World (and Welcome To it)]</quote><quote id="64" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">[http://www.bigeye.com/thurber.htm James Thurber Web Collection] - includes online versions of some of his works</quote><quote id="65" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">[http://www.budgetweb.com/heather/thurber/Thurber.html Pathfinder: James Grover Thurber] - collects many Thurber links</quote><quote id="66" author="James Thurber" cats="1960s deaths|Cartoonists|Humorists" ref="">[http://www.thurberhouse.org/james/james.html Thurber House]</quote></quotes>