<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="en|pt|de|it|az|pl"><quote id="0" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">Is not old wine wholesomest, old pippins toothsomest, old wood burn brightest, old linen wash whitest? Old soldiers, sweethearts, are surest, and old lovers are soundest.</quote><quote id="1" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">I saw him going the way of all flesh.</quote><quote id="2" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">Vain the ambition of kings
Who seek by trophies and dead things
To leave a living name behind,
And weave but nets to catch the wind.</quote><quote id="3" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">'T is just like a summer bird-cage in a garden,—the birds that are without despair to get in, and the birds that are within despair and are in a consumption for fear they shall never get out. 2</quote><quote id="4" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">Condemn you me for that the duke did love me?
So may you blame some fair and crystal river
For that some melancholic, distracted man
Hath drown'd himself in 't.</quote><quote id="5" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">Glories, like glow-worms, afar off shine bright,
But look'd too near have neither heat nor light.</quote><quote id="6" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">Call for the robin redbreast and the wren,
Since o'er shady groves they hover,
And with leaves and flowers do cover
The friendless bodies of unburied men.</quote><quote id="7" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">But keep the wolf far thence, that's foe to men,
For with his nails he'll dig them up again.</quote><quote id="8" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">Prosperity doth bewitch men, seeming clear;
But seas do laugh, show white, when rocks are near.</quote><quote id="9" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">Glories, like glowworms, afar off shine bright,
But looked to near have neither heat nor light.</quote><quote id="10" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">Of what is't fools make such vain keeping?
Sin their conception, their birth, weeping:
Their life, a general mist of error,
Their death, a hideous storm of terror.</quote><quote id="11" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">I know death hath ten thousand several doors
For men to take their exits.</quote><quote id="12" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">"Heaven-gates are not so highly arched
As princes' palaces; they that enter there
Must go upon their knees."</quote><quote id="13" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">Cover her face; mine eyes dazzle:  she died young.</quote><quote id="14" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">Whether we fall by ambition, blood, or lust, Like diamonds, we are cut with our own dust.</quote><quote id="15" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">Webster was much possessed by death
And saw the skull beneath the skin.</quote><quote id="16" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">Webster is not concerned with humanity.  He is the poet of bile and brainstorm, the sweet singer of apoplexy; ideally, one feels, he would have had all his characters drowned in a sea of cold sweat.  His muse drew nourishment from Bedlam, and might, a few centuries later, have done the same from Belsen.</quote><quote id="17" author="John Webster" cats="English playwrights" ref="">{{gutenberg author| id=John+Webster | name=John Webster}}</quote></quotes>