<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="cs|en|tr|it"><quote id="0" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">"We are, the great spiritual writers insist, most fully ourselves when we give ourselves away, and it is egotism that holds us back from that transcendent experience that has been called Nirvana, Brahman, or the all the great faiths have devised all kinds of myths to show that this type of "kenosis", or self-emptying, is found in the life of God itself." They do not do this because it sounds edifying, but because this is the way that human nature seems to work. "We are most creative and sense other possibilities that transcend our ordinary experience when we leave ourselves behind."</quote><quote id="1" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">"The one and only test of a valid religious idea, doctrinal statement, spiritual experience, or devotional practice was that it must lead directly to practical compassion." If your understanding of the divine made you kinder,  more empathetic, and impelled you to express this sympathy in concrete acts of loving-kindness, this was good theology. But if your notion of God made you unkind, belligerent, cruel, or self-righteous, or if it led you to kill in God's name, it was bad theology. Compassion was the litmus test for the prophets of Israel, for the rabbis of the Paul, and for Lao-tsu, the Buddha, or the sages of the Upanishads.</quote><quote id="2" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">I tremble for our world, where, in the smallest ways, we find it impossible, as Marshall Hodgson enjoined, to find room for the other in our minds. If we cannot accommodate a viewpoint in a friend without resorting to unkindness, how can we hope to heal the terrible problems of our planet? I no longer think that any principle or opinion is worth anything if it makes you unkind or intolerant. </quote><quote id="3" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">""My thoughts are not your thoughts. For as high as the heavens are the above the earth, so are my thoughts above your thoughts, my ways above your ways." … should be written over every … pulpit. …  Because so often we think that God's ways are our ways." God's thoughts are our thoughts. And we created God in our own image and likeness saying, "God approves of this. God forbids that. God desires the other." 
"This is where some of the worst atrocities of religion have come from. Because people have used [it] — to give a sacred seal of a divine approval to some of their most worst hatreds, loathings, and fears." Whereas to the great theologians — what I found when I was studying for "A History Of God" — the great theologians in all three of the monotheistic religions, Jewish, Christian, Muslim — all insisted that yes, God was personal. But God went beyond the personal. 
You shouldn't speak glibly about God … "in Judaism you may not speak God's name as a reminder that any human expression of the divine is likely to be so limited as to be blasphemous. But God should challenge your assumptions … you shouldn't imagine you've got Him in your pocket."</quote><quote id="4" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">"A project like Pangea, which enables us to enter in to the situations of others, imaginatively, is fulfilling what the religions call the Golden Rule..." going into one's own experience, and going into other's experience, and seeing the world from another perspective — "that's what we desperately need in our dangerously polarized world."</quote><quote id="5" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">"I say that religion isn’t about believing things. It’s ethical alchemy. It’s about behaving in a way that changes you, that gives you intimations of holiness and sacredness."</quote><quote id="6" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">"There are some forms of religion that must make God weep." There are some forms of religion that are bad, just as there's bad cooking or bad art or bad sex, you have bad religion too. Religion that has concentrated on egotism, that's concentrated on belligerence rather than compassion. … But then you have to remember that this is what human beings do. "Secularism has shown that it can be just as murderous, just as lethal … as religion." Now I think one of the reasons why religion developed in the way that it did over the centuries was precisely to curb this murderous bent that we have as human beings.</quote><quote id="7" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">"Compassion is not a popular virtue." Very often when I talk to religious people, and mention how important it is that compassion is the key, that it's the "sine qua non" of religion, people look kind of balked, and stubborn sometimes, as much to say, ""what's the point of having religion if you can't disapprove of other people?"" And sometimes we use religion just to back up these unworthy hatreds, because we're frightened too.</quote><quote id="8" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">"Ironically, the first thing that appealed to me about Islam was its pluralism. The fact that the Mohammed didn't believe he had come to found a new religion to which everybody had to convert, but he was just the prophet sent to the Arabs, who hadn't had a prophet before, and left out of the divine plan. There's a story where Mohammed makes a sacred flight from Mecca to Jerusalem, to the Temple Mount. And there he is greeted by all the great prophets of the past. And he ascends to the divine throne, speaking to the prophets like Aaron, Sufis ...the mystical branch of Islam, the Sufi movement, insisted that when you had encountered God, you were neither a Jew, a Christian, a Muslim. "You were at home equally in a synagogue, a mosque, a temple or a church, because all rightly guided religion comes from God, and a man of God, once he's glimpsed the divine, has left these man-made distinctions behind."</quote><quote id="9" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">"All fundamentalist movements… whether they're Jewish, Christian or Muslim or Buddhist, all begin as an intra-religious debate, an intra-religious struggle." Then, at a later stage, fundamentalists sometimes reach out towards a foreign foe and hence the Muslim feeling that American foreign policy ... is holding them back.</quote><quote id="10" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">At the beginning of the twentieth century, every single leading Muslim intellectual was in love with the west, and wanted their countries to look just like Britain and France. "Some of them even said that the Europeans … were better Muslims than they themselves, because their modern society had enabled them to create a fairer and more just distribution of wealth, than was possible in their pre-modern climates, and that accorded more perfectly with the vision of the Quran." 
Then there was the experience of colonialism under Britain and France, experiences like Suez, the Iranian revolution, Israel, and some people, not all by any means… have allowed this ... these series of disasters to corrode into hatred. Islam is a religion of success. Unlike Christianity, which has as its main image, in the west at least, a man dying in a devastating, disgraceful, helpless death. … crucified, and that turned into victory. "Mohammed was not an apparent failure. He was a dazzling success, politically as well as spiritually, and Islam went from strength to strength to strength." But against the West, it's been able to make no headway, and this is as disturbing for Muslims as the discoveries of Darwin have been to some Christians. The Quran says that if you live according to the Quranic ideal, implementing justice in your society, then your society will prosper, because this is the way human beings are supposed to live. But whatever they do, they cannot seem to get Muslim history back on track, and this has led some, and only a minority, it must be said, to desperate conclusions.</quote><quote id="11" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">"Religion is hard work. Its insights are not self-evident and have to be cultivated in the same way as an appreciation of art, music, or poetry must be developed."</quote><quote id="12" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">"A lot of the arguments about religion going on at the moment spring from a rather inept understanding of religious truth" … Our notion changed during the early modern period when we became convinced that the only path to any kind of truth was reason. That works beautifully for science but doesn't work so well for the humanities. "Religion is really an art form and a struggle to find value and meaning amid the ghastly tragedy of human life."</quote><quote id="13" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">The cosmology of the ancient world was telling you about the nature of life here and now. "Genesis" is not about the origins of life. There were many other creation stories current in Israel at that time and no one was required to believe in that one.</quote><quote id="14" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">People like Thomas Aquinas would say we can't talk about God as a creator because we can only have in our heads the idea of a human creator and that can't apply to God. "We can't even say that God exists because our notion of existence is too limited to apply to God." People were instructed to think about this in those terms.</quote><quote id="15" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">Isaac Newton|Newton and René Descartes|Descartes started to try and prove that God existed in the same way as they would try and prove something in the laboratory or with their mathematics … And when you try and mix science and religion you get bad science and bad religion. The two are doing two different things. ... Science can give you a diagnosis of cancer. It can even cure your disease, but it cannot touch your grief and disappointment, nor can it help you to die well.</quote><quote id="16" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">It's not easy to talk about transcendence, just as it's not easy to play or listen to a late Beethoven quartet … "You have to practice quite hard, like you do with any art form. Religion is hard work."</quote><quote id="17" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">"This is the "apophatic" tradition, in which nothing about God can be put into words." Armstrong firmly recommends silence, having written at least 15 books on the topic. "Words such as "God" have to be seen as symbols, not names, but any word falls short of describing what it symbolises, and will always be inadequate, contradictory, metaphorical or allegorical. The mystery at the heart of religious practice is ineffable, unapproachable by reason and by language. Silence is its truest expression." The right kind of silence, of course, not that of the pothead or inebriate. The religious state is exactly that of Alice after hearing the nonsense poem "Jabberwocky": "Somehow it seems to fill my head with ideas — only I don't exactly know what they are." … Armstrong is not presenting a case for God in the sense most people in our idolatrous world would think of it. "The ordinary man or woman in the pew or on the prayer mat probably thinks of God as a kind of large version of themselves with mysterious powers and a rather nasty temper." That is the vice of theory again, and as long as they think like that, ordinary folk are not truly religious, whatever they profess. By contrast, Armstrong promises that her kinds of practice will make us better, wiser, more forgiving, loving, courageous, selfless, hopeful and just. Who can be against that? 
The odd thing is that the book presupposes that such desirable improvements are the same thing as an increase in understanding — only a kind of understanding that has no describable content. It is beyond words, yet is nevertheless to be described in terms of awareness and truth.</quote><quote id="18" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">Like Austen, and in a polished English accent, Armstrong is sharp-witted, quick to ridicule nonsense, and a good storyteller. … In conversation, Armstrong spins the threads of her research with agile, unhesitating precision, leaping across centuries of scripture, philosophy and theology.</quote><quote id="19" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">[http://www.randomhouse.com/modernlibrary/library/author.pperl?authorid=834 Author Spotlight at Random House]</quote><quote id="20" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">[http://www.pbs.org/now/search_google.html?q=Karen+Armstrong&amp;simplesearch=Search NOW Interviews at PBS]</quote><quote id="21" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">[http://www.islamfortoday.com/karenarmstrong.htm Profile at Islamfortoday.com]</quote><quote id="22" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">[http://www.bbc.co.uk/worldservice/documentaries/2009/07/090714_theforum_120709.shtml Audio: Karen Armstrong in conversation on "The Forum" (BBC World Service)]</quote><quote id="23" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">[http://charterforcompassion.org Charter for Compassion]</quote><quote id="24" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">[http://www.fifthestate.co.uk/author/karenarmstrong/ Articles by Karen Armstrong on the 5th Estate blog]</quote><quote id="25" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">[http://www.readthespirit.com/explore/2007/11/049-conversatio.html Interview with Karen Armstrong on "The Bible"]</quote><quote id="26" author="Karen Armstrong" cats="Authors|English people|Living people" ref="">[http://www.ted.com/talks/karen_armstrong_let_s_revive_the_golden_rule.html Karen Armstrong's TED Talk "Let's revive the golden rule"]</quote></quotes>