<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="ru|ka|bg|zh|pt|hr|de|tr|it|hu|lt|en|li|br|bs|cs|fi|gl|pl|he"><quote id="0" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I sometimes wondered what the use of any of the arts was. The best thing I could come up with was what I call the canary in the coal mine theory of the arts." This theory says that artists are useful to society because they are so sensitive. They are super-sensitive. They keel over like canaries in poison coal mines long before more robust types realize that there is any danger whatsoever.</quote><quote id="1" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"High school is closer to the core of the American experience than anything else I can think of."</quote><quote id="2" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I was taught in the sixth grade that we had a standing army of just over a hundred thousand men and that the generals had nothing to say about what was done in Washington. I was taught to be proud of that and to pity Europe for having more than a million men under arms and spending all their money on airplanes and tanks. "I simply never unlearned junior civics. I still believe in it." I got a very good grade.</quote><quote id="3" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Well, I've worried some about, you know, why write books" ... why are we teaching people to write books when presidents and senators do not read them, and generals do not read them. And it's been the university experience that taught me that there is a very good reason, that you catch people before they become generals and presidents and so forth and you poison their minds with ... humanity, and however you want to poison their minds, it's presumably to encourage them to make a better world.</quote><quote id="4" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I was taught that the human brain was the crowning glory of evolution so far, but I think it’s a very poor scheme for survival."</quote><quote id="5" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">1. "Find a subject you care about."&lt;br /&gt;2. Do not ramble, though.&lt;br /&gt;3. Keep it simple.&lt;br /&gt;4. Have the guts to cut.&lt;br /&gt;5. Sound like yourself.&lt;br /&gt;6. Say what you mean to say.&lt;br /&gt;7. Pity the readers.</quote><quote id="6" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"You learn about life by the accidents you have, over and over again", and your father is always in your head when that stuff happens. Writing, most of the time, for most people, is an accident and your father is there for that, too. You know, I taught writing for a while and whenever somebody would tell me they were going to write about their dad, I would tell them they might as well go write about killing puppies because neither story was going to work. It just doesn't work. Your father won't let it happen.</quote><quote id="7" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"The telling of jokes is an art of its own, and it always rises from some emotional threat. The best jokes are dangerous, and dangerous because they are in some way truthful."</quote><quote id="8" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">One of the great American tragedies is to have participated in a just war. It's been possible for politicians and movie-makers to encourage us we're always good guys. The Second World War absolutely had to be fought. I wouldn't have missed it for the world. But we never talk about the people we kill. This is never spoken of.</quote><quote id="9" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I urge you to please notice when you are happy, and exclaim or murmur or think at some point, "If this isn't nice, I don't know what is." "</quote><quote id="10" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">We're terrible animals. I think that the Earth's immune system is trying to get rid of us, as well it should.</quote><quote id="11" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I have wanted to give Iraq a lesson in democracy — because we’re experienced with it, you know. And, in democracy, after a hundred years, you have to let your slaves go. And, after a hundred and fifty years, you have to let your women vote. And, at the beginning of democracy, is that quite a bit of genocide and ethnic cleansing is quite okay. And that’s what’s going on now.</quote><quote id="12" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I do feel that evolution is being controlled by some sort of divine engineer. I can't help thinking that. And this engineer knows exactly what he or she is doing and why, and where evolution is headed. That’s why we’ve got giraffes and hippopotami and the clap.</quote><quote id="13" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"[When Vonnegut tells his wife he's going out to buy an envelope]" Oh, she says, well, you're not a poor man. You know, why don't you go online and buy a hundred envelopes and put them in the closet? And so I pretend not to hear her. And go out to get an envelope because "I'm going to have a hell of a good time in the process of buying one envelope." I meet a lot of people. And, see some great looking babes. And a fire engine goes by. And I give them the thumbs up. And, and ask a woman what kind of dog that is. And, and I don't know. "The moral of the story is, is we're here on Earth to fart around. And, of course, the computers will do us out of that. And, what the computer people don't realize, or they don't care, is we're dancing animals. You know, we love to move around. And, we're not supposed to dance at all anymore."</quote><quote id="14" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Where is home? I've wondered where home is, and I realized, it's not Mars or someplace like that, it's Indianapolis when I was nine years old. I had a brother and a sister, a cat and a dog, and a mother and a father and uncles and aunts. And there's no way I can get there again.</quote><quote id="15" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">If I should ever die, God forbid, let this be my epitaph:&lt;br /&gt;THE ONLY PROOF HE NEEDED&lt;br /&gt;FOR THE EXISTENCE OF GOD&lt;br /&gt;WAS MUSIC</quote><quote id="16" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Well, I just want to say that George W. Bush is the syphilis president.</quote><quote id="17" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">The only difference between Bush and Hitler is that Hitler was elected.</quote><quote id="18" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I don't think there would be many jokes, if there weren't constant frustration and fear and so forth. It's a response to bad troubles like crime."</quote><quote id="19" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">People hate it when they're tickled because laughter is not pleasant, if it goes on too long. I think it's a desperate sort of convulsion in desperate circumstances, which helps a little.</quote><quote id="20" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">“My theory is that all women have hydrofluoric acid bottled up inside,” he wrote. </quote><quote id="21" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">During the war, in hundreds of Iliums over America, managers and engineers learned to get along without their men and women, who went to fight. It was the miracle that won the war — production with almost no manpower. In the patois of the north side of the river, it was the know-how that won the war. "Democracy owed its life to know-how."</quote><quote id="22" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"You think I'm insane?" said Finnerty. Apparently he wanted more of a reaction than Paul had given him.&lt;br /&gt;"You're still in touch. I guess that's the test."&lt;br /&gt;"Barely — "barely"."&lt;br /&gt;"A psychiatrist could help. There's a good man in Albany."&lt;br /&gt;Finnerty shook his head. "He'd pull me back into the center, and "I want to stay as close to the edge as I can without going over. Out on the edge you see all kinds of things you can't see from the center."" He nodded, "Big, undreamed-of things — the people on the edge see them first."</quote><quote id="23" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Strange business," said Lasher. "This crusading spirit of the managers and engineers, the idea of designing and manufacturing and distributing being sort of a holy war: all that folklore was cooked up by public relations and advertising men hired by managers and engineers to make big business popular in the old days, which it certainly wasn't in the beginning. "Now, the engineers and managers believe with all their hearts the glorious things their forebears hired people to say about them. Yesterday's snow job becomes today's sermon.""</quote><quote id="24" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"In order to get what we've got, Anita, we have, in effect, traded these people out of what was the most important thing on earth to them — the feeling of being needed and useful, the foundation of self-respect."</quote><quote id="25" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Here it was again, the most ancient of roadforks", one that Paul had glimpsed before, in Kroner's study, months ago. The choice of one course or the other had nothing to do with machines, hierarchies, economics, love, age. It was a purely internal matter. Every child older than six knew the fork, and knew what the good guys did here, and what the bad guys did here. The fork was a familiar one in folk tales the world over, and the good guys and the bad guys, whether in chaps, breechclouts, serapes, leopardskins, or banker's gray pinstripes, all separated here.&lt;br /&gt;"Bad guys turned informer. Good guys didn't — no matter when, no matter what."</quote><quote id="26" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">And a step backward, after making a wrong turn, is a step in the right direction.</quote><quote id="27" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Things don't stay the way they are," said Finnerty. "It's too entertaining to try to change them."</quote><quote id="28" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Everybody's shaking in his boots, so don't be bluffed.</quote><quote id="29" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Almost nobody's competent, Paul. It's enough to make you cry to see how bad most people are at their jobs. "If you can do a half-assed job of anything, you're a one-eyed man in the kingdom of the blind."</quote><quote id="30" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Every passing hour brings the Solar System forty-three thousand miles closer to Globular Cluster M13 in Hercules — and still there are some misfits who insist that there is no such thing as progress."</quote><quote id="31" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">He ransacked his memory like a thief going through another man's billfold.</quote><quote id="32" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"A purpose of human life, no matter who is controlling it, is to love whoever is around to be loved."</quote><quote id="33" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">It is always pitiful when any human being falls into a condition hardly more respectable than that of an animal. How much more pitiful it is when the person who falls has had all the advantages!</quote><quote id="34" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"There is no reason why good cannot triumph as often as evil. The triumph of anything is a matter of organization. If there are such things as angels, I hope that they are organized along the lines of the Mafia."</quote><quote id="35" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Sometimes I think it is a great mistake to have matter that can think and feel. It complains so. By the same token, though, I suppose that boulders and mountains and moons could be accused of being a little too phlegmatic.</quote><quote id="36" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Son — they say there isn't any royalty in this country, but do you want me to tell you how to be king of the United States of America? Just fall through the hole in a privy and come out smelling like a rose.</quote><quote id="37" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Take Care of the People, and God Almighty Will Take Care of Himself."</quote><quote id="38" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"The big trouble with dumb bastards is that they are too dumb to believe there is such a thing as being smart."</quote><quote id="39" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I was a victim of a series of accidents, as are we all.</quote><quote id="40" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"The worst thing that could possibly happen to anybody would be to not be used for anything by anybody. Thank you for using me, even though I didn't want to be used by anybody."</quote><quote id="41" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Puny man can do nothing at all to help or please God Almighty, and Luck is not the hand of God.</quote><quote id="42" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">You go up to a man, and you say, "How are things going, Joe?" and he says, "Oh fine, fine — couldn't be better." And you look into his eyes, and you see things really couldn't be much worse. When you get right down to it, everybody's having a perfectly lousy time of it, and I mean everybody. And the hell of it is, nothing seems to help much.</quote><quote id="43" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Life for a punctual person is like a roller coaster.  All kinds of things are going to happen to you! Sure, I can see the whole roller coaster you're on. And sure — I could give you a piece of paper that would tell you about every dip and turn, warn you about every bogeyman that was going to pop out at you in the tunnels. But that wouldn't help you any. Because you'd still have to take the roller-coaster ride, I didn't design the roller coaster, I don't own it, and I don't say who rides and who doesn't. I just know what it's shaped like.</quote><quote id="44" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"We are what we pretend to be, so we must be careful about what we pretend to be."</quote><quote id="45" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">And the city was lovely, highly ornamented, like Paris, and untouched by war. It was supposedly an “open” city, not to be attacked since there were no troop concentrations or war industries there. But high explosives were dropped on Dresden by American and British planes on the night of February 13, 1945, just about twenty-one years ago, as I now write. There were no particular targets for the bombs. The hope was that they would create a lot of kindling and drive firemen underground. And then tens of thousands of tiny incendiaries were scattered over the kindling, like seeds on freshly turned loam. More bombs were dropped to keep firemen in their holes, and all the little fires grew, joined one another, became one apocalyptic flame. Hey presto: fire storm. It was the largest massacre in European history, by the way. (...) Everything was gone but the cellars where 135'000 Hansels and Gretels had been baked like gingerbread men.</quote><quote id="46" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">If I'd been born in Germany, I suppose I would have been a Nazi, bopping Jews and gypsies and Poles around, leaving boots sticking out of snowbanks, warming myself with my secretly virtuous insides. So it goes.</quote><quote id="47" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">When you're dead you're dead.</quote><quote id="48" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Make love when you can. It's good for you.</quote><quote id="49" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Here lies Howard Campbell’s essence,&lt;br /&gt;Freed from his body’s noisome nuisance.&lt;br /&gt;His body, empty, prowls the earth,&lt;br /&gt;Earning what a body’s worth.&lt;br /&gt;If his body and his essence remain apart,&lt;br /&gt;Burn his body, but spare this, his heart.</quote><quote id="50" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"All people are insane," he said. "They will do anything at any time, and God help anybody who looks for reasons."</quote><quote id="51" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"There are plenty of good reasons for fighting," I said, "but no good reason ever to hate without reservation, to imagine that God Almighty Himself hates with you, too. Where's evil? It's that large part of every man that wants to hate without limit, that wants to hate with God on its side. It’s that part of every man that finds all kinds of ugliness so attractive."</quote><quote id="52" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Say what you will about the sweet miracle of unquestioning faith, I consider a capacity for it terrifying and absolutely vile."</quote><quote id="53" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"You hate America, don't you?" she said.&lt;br /&gt;"That would be as silly as loving it," I said. "It's impossible for me to get emotional about it, because real estate doesn't interest me. It's no doubt a great flaw in my personality, but "I can't think in terms of boundaries. Those imaginary lines are as unreal to me as elves and pixies. I can't believe that they mark the end or the beginning of anything of real concern to the human soul. Virtues and vices, pleasures and pains cross boundaries at will.""</quote><quote id="54" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Drawn crudely in the dust of three window-panes were a swastika, a hammer and sickle, and the Stars and Stripes. I had drawn the three symbols weeks before, at the conclusion of an argument about patriotism with Kraft. I had given a hearty cheer for each symbol, demonstrating to Kraft the meaning of patriotism to, respectively, a Nazi, a Communist, and an American. "Hooray, hooray, hooray," I'd said.</quote><quote id="55" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">What froze me was the fact that I had absolutely no reason to move in any direction. "What had made me move through so many dead and pointless years was curiosity. Now even that flickered out." (232)</quote><quote id="56" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Generally speaking, espionage offers each spy an opportunity to go crazy in a way he finds irresistible.</quote><quote id="57" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Nothing in this book is true."</quote><quote id="58" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"We Bokonists believe that humanity is organized into teams, teams that do God's Will without ever discovering what they are doing." Such a team is called a "karass" by Bokonon "If you find your life tangled up with somebody else's life for no very logical reasons," writes Bokonon, "that person may be a member of your karass." At another point in "The Books of Bokonon" he tells us, "Man created the checkerboard; God created the "karass"." By that he means that "a karass ignores national, institutional, occupational, familial, and class boundaries. It is as free form as an amoeba."</quote><quote id="59" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Busy, busy, busy."</quote><quote id="60" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Someday, someday, this crazy world will have to end,&lt;br /&gt;And our God will take things back that He to us did lend.&lt;br /&gt;And if, on that sad day, you want to scold our God,&lt;br /&gt;Why go right ahead and scold Him. He'll just smile and nod.</quote><quote id="61" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Peculiar Travel Suggestions are Dancing Lessons From God</quote><quote id="62" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I love you sons of bitches. You’re all I read any more." You're the only ones who’ll talk all about the really terrific changes going on, the only ones crazy enough to know that life is a space voyage, and not a short one, either, but one that’ll last for billions of years. You’re the only ones with guts enough to really care about the future, who really notice what machines do to us, what wars do to us, what cities do to us, what big, simple ideas do to us, what tremendous misunderstanding, mistakes, accidents, catastrophes do to us. "You're the only ones zany enough to agonize over time and distance without limit, over mysteries that will never die, over the fact that we are right now determining whether the space voyage for the next billion years or so is going to be Heaven or Hell."</quote><quote id="63" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">We few, we happy few, we band of brothers — joined in the serious business of keeping our food, shelter, clothing and loved ones from combining with oxygen.</quote><quote id="64" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Like all real heroes, Charley had a fatal flaw. He refused to believe that he had gonorrhea, whereas the truth was that he did.</quote><quote id="65" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">He alienated his friends in the sciences by thanking them extravagantly for scientific advances he had read about in the recent newspapers and magazines, by assuring them, with a perfectly straight face, that life was getting better and better, thanks to scientific thinking.</quote><quote id="66" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">A sum of money is a leading character in this tale about people, just as a sum of honey might properly be a leading character in a tale about bees.</quote><quote id="67" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Hello, babies. Welcome to Earth. It's hot in the summer and cold in the winter. It's round and wet and crowded. At the outside, babies, you've got about a hundred years here. "There's only one rule that I know of, babies — "God damn it, you've got to be kind.""</quote><quote id="68" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">We don't piss in your ashtrays,&lt;br /&gt;So please don't throw cigarettes in our urinals.</quote><quote id="69" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Pretend to be good always, and even God will be fooled.</quote><quote id="70" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">The public health authorities never mention the main reason many Americans have for smoking heavily, which is that smoking is a fairly sure, fairly honorable form of suicide.</quote><quote id="71" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I never knew a writer's wife who wasn't beautiful.</quote><quote id="72" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"So it goes."</quote><quote id="73" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"The most important thing I learned on Tralfamadore was that when a person dies he only "appears" to die." He is still very much alive in the past, so it is very silly for people to cry at his funeral. "All moments, past, present and future, always have existed, always will exist. The Tralfamadorians can look at all the different moments just that way we can look at a stretch of the Rocky Mountains, for instance. They can see how permanent all the moments are, and they can look at any moment that interests them." It is just an illusion we have here on Earth that one moment follows another one, like beads on a string, and that once a moment is gone it is gone forever.&lt;br /&gt;When a Tralfamadorian sees a corpse, all he thinks is that the dead person is in bad condition in the particular moment, but that the same person is just fine in plenty of other moments. Now, when I myself hear that somebody is dead, I simply shrug and say what the Tralfamadorians say about dead people, which is ""So it goes.""</quote><quote id="74" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Billy coughed when the door was opened, and when he coughed he shit thin gruel. This was in accordance with the Third Law of Motion according to Sir Isaac Newton. This law tells us that for each reaction there is a reaction which is equal and opposite in direction. This can be useful in rocketry.</quote><quote id="75" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Derby described the incredible artificial weather that Earthlings sometimes create for other Earthlings when they don't want those other Earthlings to inhabit Earth any more.</quote><quote id="76" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Robert F. Kennedy|Robert Kennedy, whose summer home is eight miles away from the home I live in all year round, was shot two nights ago. He died last night. So it goes. &lt;br /&gt;Martin Luther King, Jr.|Martin Luther King was shot a month ago. He died, too. So it goes.&lt;br /&gt; And everyday my government gives me a count of corpses created by the military service in Vietnam. So it goes.&lt;br /&gt;My father died many years ago now--of natural causes. So it goes. He was a sweet man. He was a gun nut, too. He left me his guns. They rust. </quote><quote id="77" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Po-Tee-Weet?"</quote><quote id="78" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Things die. All things die."</quote><quote id="79" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">All through the day I'm so confident. That's why I'm such a good salesman, you know? I have confidence, and I look like I have confidence, and that gives other people confidence.</quote><quote id="80" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Maybe God has let everybody who ever lived be reborn — so he or she can see how it ends." Even Pitecanthropus erectus and Australopithecus and Sinanthropus pekensis and the Neanderthalers are back on Earth — to see how it ends. They're all on Times Square — making change for peepshows. Or recruiting Marines.</quote><quote id="81" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">You know what gets me? ... How everybody says "fuck" and "shit" all the time. I used to be scared shitless if I'd say "fuck" or "shit" in public, by accident. Now everybody says "fuck" and "shit", "fuck" and "shit" all the time. Something very big must have happened while we were out of the country.</quote><quote id="82" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">The new heroism — put a village idiot into a pressure cooker, seal it up tight, and shoot him at the moon.</quote><quote id="83" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Hello, I am Wanda June. Today was going to be my birthday, but I was hit by an ice-cream truck before I could have my party." I am dead now. I am in Heaven. That is why my parents did not pick up my cake at the bakery. I am not mad at the ice-cream truck driver, even though he was drunk when he hit me. It didn't hurt much. It wasn't even as bad as the sting of a bumblebee. I am really "happy" here! It's so much fun. I'm glad the driver was drunk. If he hadn't been, I might not have gone to Heaven for years and years and years. I would have had to go to high school first, and then beauty college. I would have had to get married and have babies and everything. Now I can just play and play and play. Any time I want any pink cotton candy I can have some. Everybody up here is happy — the animals and the dead soldiers and people who went to the electric chair and everything. They're all glad for whatever sent them here. Nobody is mad. We're all too busy playing shuffleboard. So if you think of killing somebody, don't worry about it. Just go ahead and do it. Whoever you do it to should kiss you for doing it. The soldiers up here just love the shrapnel and the tanks and the bayonets and the dum dums that let them play shuffleboard all the time — and drink beer.</quote><quote id="84" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Don't lecture me on race relations. I don't have a molecule of prejudice. I've been in battle with every kind of man there is. I've been in bed with every kind of woman there is — from a Laplander to a Tierra del Fuegian. If I'd ever been to the South Pole, there'd be a hell of a lot of penguins who looked like me.</quote><quote id="85" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">No grown woman is a fan of premature ejaculation.</quote><quote id="86" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I have this theory about why men kill each other and break things. ... Never mind. It's a dumb theory. I was going to say it was all sexual ... but everything is sexual ... but alcohol.</quote><quote id="87" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">When I was a naive young recruit in Spain, I used to wonder why soldiers bayoneted oil paintings, shot the noses off statues and defecated into grand pianos. I now understand: it was to teach civilians the deepest sort of respect for men in uniform — uncontrollable fear.</quote><quote id="88" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Wars would be a lot better, I think, if guys would say to themselves sometimes "Jesus — I'm not going to do that to the enemy. That's "too" much." "</quote><quote id="89" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">This script, it seems to me, is the work of professionals who yearned to be as charming as inspired amateurs can sometimes be.</quote><quote id="90" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I don't like film. Film is too clankingly real, too permanent, too industrial for me. ... The worst thing about film, from my point of view, is that it cripples illusions which I have encouraged people to create in their heads. Film doesn't create illusions. It makes them impossible. It's a bullying form of reality, like the model rooms in the furniture department of Bloomingdale's.</quote><quote id="91" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I have become an enthusiast for the printed word again. I have to be that, I now understand, because I want to be a character in all of my works. I can do that in print. In a movie, somehow, the author always vanishes. "Everything of mine which has been filmed so far has been one character short, and that character is me."</quote><quote id="92" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">And so on.</quote><quote id="93" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Charm was a scheme for making strangers like and trust a person immediately, no matter what the charmer had in mind.</quote><quote id="94" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I can have oodles of charm when I want to.</quote><quote id="95" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">What do I myself think of this particular book? I feel lousy about it, but I always feel lousy about my books.</quote><quote id="96" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"This book is my fiftieth-birthday present to myself." I feel as though I am crossing the spine of a roof—having ascended one slope.&lt;br /&gt;I am programmed at fifty to perform childishly—to insult “The Star-Spangled Banner,” to scrawl pictures of a Nazi flag and an asshole and a lot of other things with a felt-tipped pen. To give an idea of the maturity of my illustrations for this book, here is my picture of an asshole:&lt;br /&gt;I think I am trying to clear my head of all the junk in there—the assholes, the flags, the underpants. Yes—there is a picture in this book of underpants. I’m throwing out characters from my other books, too. I’m not going to put on any more puppet shows.&lt;br /&gt;"I think I am trying to make my head as empty as it was when I was born onto this damaged planet fifty years ago."&lt;br /&gt;I suspect that this is something most white Americans, and nonwhite Americans who imitate white Americans, should do. "The things other people have put into my head", at any rate, do not fit together nicely, are often useless and ugly, are out of proportion with one another, are out of proportion with life as it really is outside my head.&lt;br /&gt;I have no culture, no humane harmony in my brains. "I can’t live without a culture anymore."&lt;br /&gt;So this book is a sidewalk strewn with junk, trash which I throw over my shoulders as I travel in time back to November eleventh, nineteen hundred and twenty-two.&lt;br /&gt;"I will come to a time in my backwards trip when November eleventh, accidentally my birthday, was a sacred day called "Armistice Day"." When I was a boy, and when Dwayne Hoover was a boy, all the people of all the nations which had fought in the First World War were silent during the eleventh minute of the eleventh hour of Armistice Day, which was the eleventh day of the eleventh month.&lt;br /&gt;"It was during that minute in nineteen hundred and eighteen, that millions upon millions of human beings stopped butchering one another." I have talked to old men who were on battlefields during that minute. They have told me in one way or another that the sudden silence was the Voice of God. "So we still have among us some men who can remember when God spoke clearly to mankind."&lt;br /&gt;Armistice Day has become Veterans' Day. Armistice Day was sacred. Veterans' Day is not.&lt;br /&gt;So I will throw Veterans' Day over my shoulder. Armistice Day I will keep. I don't want to throw away any sacred things.&lt;br /&gt;What else is sacred? Oh, "Romeo and Juliet", for instance.&lt;br /&gt;"And all music is."</quote><quote id="97" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Ideas or the lack of them can cause disease."</quote><quote id="98" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Let us devote to unselfishness the frenzy we once gave gold and underpants.</quote><quote id="99" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Teachers of children in the United States of America wrote this date on blackboards again and again, and asked the children to memorize it with pride and joy: "1492". The teachers told the children that this was when their continent was discovered by human beings. Actually, millions of human beings were already living full and imaginative lives on the continent in 1492. That was simply the year in which sea pirates began to cheat and rob and kill them.</quote><quote id="100" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Like most science-fiction writers, Trout knew almost nothing about science.</quote><quote id="101" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">""Roses are red&lt;br /&gt;And ready for plucking&lt;br /&gt;You're sixteen&lt;br /&gt;And ready for high school.""</quote><quote id="102" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">""To be&lt;br /&gt;the eyes&lt;br /&gt;and ears&lt;br /&gt;and conscience&lt;br /&gt;of the Creator of the Universe,&lt;br /&gt;you fool.""</quote><quote id="103" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Trout trudged onward, a stranger in a strange land. His pilgrimage was rewarded with new wisdom, which would never have been his had he remained in his basement in Cohoes. He learned the answer to a question many human beings were asking themselves so frantically: "What's blocking the traffic on the westbound barrel of the Midland City stretch of the Interstate?"</quote><quote id="104" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I was on par with the Creator of the Universe there in the dark in the cocktail lounge. I shrunk the Universe to a ball exactly one light-year in diameter." I had it explode. I had it disperse itself again.&lt;br /&gt;Ask me a question, any question. "How old is the Universe? It is one half-second old, but the half-second has lasted one quintillion years so far." Who created it? Nobody created it. It has always been here.&lt;br /&gt;"What is time? It is a serpent which eats its tail", like this:&lt;br /&gt;This is the snake which uncoiled itself long enough to offer Eve the apple, which looked like this:&lt;br /&gt;What was the apple which Eve and Adam ate? It was the Creator of the Universe.&lt;br /&gt;And so on.&lt;br /&gt;"Symbols can be so beautiful, sometimes."</quote><quote id="105" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">He was a graduate of West Point, a military academy which turned young men into homicidal maniacs for use in war.</quote><quote id="106" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">It was Trout’s fantasy that somebody would be outraged by the footprints. This would give him the opportunity to reply grandly, “What is it that offends you so? I am simply using man’s first printing press. "You are reading a bold and universal headline which says ,’I am here, I am here, I am here.’ "</quote><quote id="107" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Listen:&lt;br /&gt;The waitress brought me another drink. She wanted to light my hurricane lamp again. I wouldn't let her. "Can you see anything in the dark, with your sunglasses on?" she asked me.&lt;br /&gt;""The big show is inside my head"," I said</quote><quote id="108" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"We are healthy only to the extent that our ideas are humane."</quote><quote id="109" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Hey — guess what: You're the only creature with free will. How does that make you feel?</quote><quote id="110" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Our awareness is all that is alive and maybe sacred in any of us. Everything else about us is dead machinery."</quote><quote id="111" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I thought Beatrice Keedsler had joined hands with other old-fashioned storytellers to make people believe that life had leading characters, minor characters, significant details, insignificant details, that it had lessons to be learned, tests to be passed, and a beginning, a middle, and an end.&lt;br /&gt;As I approached my fiftieth birthday, I had become more and more enraged and mystified by the idiot decisions made by my countrymen. And then I had come suddenly to pity them, for I understood how innocent and natural it was for them to behave so abominably, and with such abominable results: "They were doing their best to live like people invented in story books." This was the reason Americans shot each other so often: It was a convenient literary device for ending short stories and books.&lt;br /&gt;"Why were so many Americans treated by their government as though their lives were as disposable as paper facial tissues? Because that was the way authors customarily treated bit-part players in their madeup tales."&lt;br /&gt;And so on.&lt;br /&gt;Once I understood what was making America such a dangerous, unhappy nation of people who had nothing to do with real life, "I resolved to shun storytelling. I would write about life. Every person would be exactly as important as any other. All facts would also be given equal weightiness. Nothing would be left out. Let others bring order to chaos. I would bring chaos to order, instead, which I think I have done."&lt;br /&gt;If all writers would do that, then perhaps citizens not in the literary trades will understand that "there is no order in the world around us, that we must adapt ourselves to the requirements of chaos instead.&lt;br /&gt;It is hard to adapt to chaos, but it can be done. I am living proof of that: It can be done."</quote><quote id="112" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">You are pooped and demoralized. Why wouldn't you be? Of course it is exhausting, having to reason all the time in a universe which wasn't meant to be reasonable.</quote><quote id="113" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Here was what Kilgore Trout cried out to me in my father's voice: "Make me young, make me young, make me young!"</quote><quote id="114" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Dear Reader: The title of this book is composed of three words from my novel "Cat's Cradle". A "wampeter" is an object around which the lives of many otherwise unrelated people may revolve. The Holy Grail would be a case in point. "Foma" are harmless untruths, intended to comfort simple souls. An example: "Prosperity is just around the corner." A "granfalloon" is a proud and meaningless association of human beings. Taken together, the words form as good an umbrella as any for this collection of some of the reviews and essays I've written, a few of the speeches I made.</quote><quote id="115" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I have been a soreheaded occupant of a file drawer labeled “Science Fiction” ... and I would like out, particularly since so many serious critics regularly mistake the drawer for a urinal."</quote><quote id="116" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">The two real political parties in America are the Winners and the Losers. The people don’t acknowledge this. They claim membership in two imaginary parties, the Republicans and the Democrats, instead.</quote><quote id="117" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">This theory argues that artists are useful to society because they are so sensitive. They are supersensitive. They keel over like canaries in coal mines filled with poison gas, long before more robust types realize that any danger is there.</quote><quote id="118" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">The most useful thing I could do before this meeting is to keel over. On the other hand, artists are keeling over by the thousands every day and nobody seems to pay the least attention.</quote><quote id="119" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I couldn't survive my own pessimism if I didn't have some kind of sunny little dream. ... "Human beings will be happier — not when they cure cancer or get to Mars or eliminate racial prejudice or flush Lake Erie — but when they find ways to inhabit primitive communities again. That’s my utopia." That's what I want for me.</quote><quote id="120" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"It goes against the American storytelling grain to have someone in a situation he can't get out of, but I think this is very usual in life." There are people, particularly dumb people, who are in terrible trouble and never get out of it, because they're not intelligent enough. It strikes me as gruesome and comical that in our culture we have an expectation that man can always solve his problems. This is so untrue that it makes me want to cry — or laugh.</quote><quote id="121" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I've often thought there ought to be a manual to hand to little kids, telling them what kind of planet they're on, why they don't fall off it, how much time they've probably got here, how to avoid poison ivy, and so on." I tried to write one once. It was called "Welcome to Earth." But I got stuck on explaining why we don't fall off the planet. Gravity is just a word. It doesn't explain anything. If I could get past gravity, I'd tell them how we reproduce, how long we've been here, apparently, and a little bit about evolution. I didn't learn until I was in college about all the other cultures, and I should have learned that in the first grade. "A first grader should understand that his or her culture isn't a rational invention; that there are thousands of other cultures and they all work pretty well; that all cultures function on faith rather than truth; that there are lots of alternatives to our own society. Cultural relativity is defensible and attractive. It's also a source of hope. It means we don't have to continue this way if we don't like it."</quote><quote id="122" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I thought scientists were going to find out exactly how everything worked, and then make it work better." I fully expected that by the time I was twenty-one, some scientist, maybe my brother, would have taken a color photograph of God Almighty — and sold it to "Popular Mechanics" magazine.&lt;br /&gt;"Scientific truth was going to make us so happy and comfortable. What actually happened when I was twenty-one was that we dropped scientific truth on Hiroshima."</quote><quote id="123" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">We would be a lot safer if the Government would take its money out of science and put it into astrology and the reading of palms. "I used to think that science would save us, and science certainly tried. But we can't stand any more tremendous explosions, either for or against democracy."</quote><quote id="124" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I know that millions of dollars have been spent to produce this splendid graduating class, and that the main hope of your teachers was, once they got through with you, that you would no longer be superstitious. I'm sorry — I have to undo that now. I beg you to believe in the most ridiculous superstition of all: that humanity is at the center of the universe, the fulfiller or the frustrator of the grandest dreams of God Almighty.&lt;br /&gt;If you can believe that, and make others believe it, then there might be hope for us. Human beings might stop treating each other like garbage, might begin to treasure and protect each other instead. Then it might be all right to have babies again.</quote><quote id="125" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">About astrology and palmistry: They are good because they make people feel vivid and full of possibilities. They are communism at its best. Everybody has a birthday and almost everybody has a palm.</quote><quote id="126" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Which brings us to the arts, whose purpose, in common with astrology, is to use frauds in order to make human beings seem more wonderful than they really are. Dancers show us human beings who move much more gracefully than human beings really move. Films and books and plays show us people talking much more entertainingly than people really talk, make paltry human enterprises seem important. Singers and musicians show us human beings making sounds far more lovely than human beings really make. Architects give us temples in which something marvelous is obviously going on. Actually, practically nothing is going on inside. And on and on.</quote><quote id="127" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"The arts put man at the center of the universe, whether he belongs there or not." Military science, on the other hand, treats man as garbage — and his children, and his cities, too. Military science is probably right about the contemptibility of man in the vastness of the universe. Still — I deny that contemptibility, and I beg you to deny it, through the creation of appreciation of art.</quote><quote id="128" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"A great swindle of our time is the assumption that science has made religion obsolete." All science has damaged is the story of Adam and Eve and the story of Jonah and the Whale. Everything else holds up pretty well, particularly lessons about fairness and gentleness. "People who find those lessons irrelevant in the twentieth century are simply using science as an excuse for greed and harshness. Science has nothing to do with it, friends."</quote><quote id="129" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Hi Ho"</quote><quote id="130" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Love is where you find it." I think it is foolish to go looking for it, and I think it can often be poisonous.</quote><quote id="131" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I wish that people who are conventionally supposed to love each other would say to each other, when they fight, "Please — a little less love, and a little more common decency.""</quote><quote id="132" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Eliza and I composed a precocious critique of the Constitution of the United States of America ... We argued that is was as good a scheme for misery as any, since its success in keeping the common people reasonably happy and proud depended on the strength of the people themselves — and yet it prescribed no practical machinery which would tend to make the people, as opposed to their elected representatives, strong.&lt;br /&gt;We said it was possible that the framers of the Constitution were blind to the beauty of persons who were without great wealth or powerful friends or public office, but who were nonetheless genuinely strong.&lt;br /&gt;We thought it was more likely, though, that their framers had not noticed that it was natural, and therefore almost inevitable, that human beings in extraordinary and enduring situations should think of themselves of composing new families. Eliza and I pointed out that this happened no less in democracies than in tyrannies, since human beings were the same the wide world over, and civilized only yesterday.&lt;br /&gt;Elected representatives, hence, could be expected to become members of the famous and powerful family of elected representatives — which would, perfectly naturally, make them wary and squeamish and stingy with respect to all the other sorts of families which, again, perfectly naturally, subdivided mankind.&lt;br /&gt;Eliza and I ... proposed that the Constitution be amended so as to guarantee that every citizen, no matter how humble, or crazy or incompetent or deformed, somehow be given membership in some family as covertly xenophobic and crafty as the one their public servants formed.</quote><quote id="133" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Why don't you take a flying fuck at a rolling doughnut. Why don't you take a flying fuck at the mooooooooooooon!</quote><quote id="134" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"History is merely a list of surprises. ... It can only prepare us to be surprised yet again. Please write that down."</quote><quote id="135" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">If you can do no good, at least do no harm.</quote><quote id="136" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Sally In The Garden:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sally in the garden,&lt;br /&gt;Siftin' cinders,&lt;br /&gt;Lifted up her leg,&lt;br /&gt;And farted like a man,&lt;br /&gt;The bursting of her bloomers broke sixteen winders,&lt;br /&gt;The cheeks of her ass went (blam, blam, blam)&lt;br /&gt;</quote><quote id="137" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I still believe that peace and plenty and happiness can be worked out some way. I am a fool."</quote><quote id="138" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">What is flirtatiousness but an argument that life must go on and on and on?</quote><quote id="139" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Congressman Nixon had asked me why, as the son of immigrants who had been treated so well by Americans, as a man who had been treated like a son and been sent to Harvard by an American capitalist, I had been so ungrateful to the American economic system.&lt;br /&gt;The answer I gave him was not original. Nothing about me has ever been original. I repeated what my one-time hero, Kenneth Whistler, had said in reply to the same general sort of question long, long ago. Whistler had been a witness at a trial of strikers accused of violence. The judge had become curious about him, had asked him why such a well-educated man from such a good family would so immerse himself in the working class.&lt;br /&gt;My stolen answer to Nixon was this:" "Why? The Sermon on the Mount, sir." "</quote><quote id="140" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">You couldn't help that you were born without a heart. At least you tried to believe what the people with hearts believed — so you were a good man just the same.</quote><quote id="141" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"That was the strength of the Nazis," she said. "They understood God better than anyone. They knew how to make him stay away."</quote><quote id="142" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"What we will be seeking ... for the rest of our lives will be large, stable communities of like-minded people, which is to say relatives. They no longer exist." The lack of them is not only the main cause, but probably the only cause of our shapeless discontent in the midst of such prosperity.</quote><quote id="143" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"What should young people do with their lives today? Many things, obviously. But the most daring thing is to create stable communities in which the terrible disease of loneliness can be cured."</quote><quote id="144" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I think it can be tremendously refreshing if a creator of literature has something on his mind other than the history of literature so far. Literature should not disappear up its own asshole, so to speak."</quote><quote id="145" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">[Gay Talese's "Thy Neighbor's Wife"] is for me a secretly deep history of a generation of middle-class American males, my own, which was taught by parents and athletic coaches and scoutmasters and military chaplains and quack doctors and so on to be deeply ashamed of masturbation and wet dreams.&lt;br /&gt;And the hidden plea in the book is one which first appeared in my eyes when I was fourteen, say, and which has not vanished entirely to this day. It is part of the mystery of me. The plea is addressed by old-fashioned males forever full of jism to any pretty human female, on the street, in a magazine, in a movie — anywhere. The plea is this: "Please, pretty lady, don't make me play with my private parts again."</quote><quote id="146" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Jokes can be noble. Laughs are exactly as honorable as tears. Laughter and tears are both responses to frustration and exhaustion, to the futility of thinking and striving anymore." I myself prefer to laugh, since there is less cleaning up to do afterward — and since I can start thinking and striving again that much sooner.</quote><quote id="147" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">As for literary criticism in general: I have long felt that any reviewer who expresses rage and loathing for a novel or a play or a poem is preposterous. He or she is like a person who has put on full armor and attacked a hot fudge sundae or a banana split.</quote><quote id="148" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">And I believe that reading and writing are the most nourishing forms of meditation anyone has so far found. "By reading the writings of the most interesting minds in history, we meditate with our own minds and theirs as well." This to me is a miracle.</quote><quote id="149" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"This is my principal objection to life, I think: It is too easy, when alive, to make perfectly horrible mistakes."</quote><quote id="150" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Many people found our house spooky, and the attic in fact as full of evil when I was born. It housed a collection of more than three hundred antique and modern firearms. Father had bought them during his and Mother's six-month honeymoon in Europe in 1922. Father thought them beautiful, but they might as well have been copperheads and rattlesnakes. They were murder.</quote><quote id="151" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I hadn't aimed at anything. If I had thought of the bullet's hitting anything, I don't remember now. I was the great marksman, anyway. If I aimed at nothing, then nothing is what I would hit. The bullet was a symbol, and nobody was ever hurt by a symbol. It was a farewell to my childhood and a confirmation of my manhood. Why didn't I use a blank cartridge? What kind of a symbol would that have been?</quote><quote id="152" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">My wife has been killed by a machine which should never have come into the hands of any human being. It is called a firearm. It makes the blackest of all human wishes come true at once, at a distance: that something die. There is evil for you. We cannot get rid of mankind's fleetingly evil wishes. We can get rid of the machines that make them come true. I give you a holy word: DISARM.</quote><quote id="153" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">You want to know something? We are still in the Dark Ages. The Dark Ages — they haven't ended yet.</quote><quote id="154" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Mere opinions, in fact, were as likely to govern people's actions as hard evidence, and were subject to sudden reversals as hard evidence could never be." So the Galapagos Islands could be hell in one moment and heaven in the next, and Julius Caesar could be a statesman in one moment and a butcher in the next, and Ecuadorian paper money could be traded for food, shelter, and clothing in one moment and line the bottom of a birdcage in the next, and the universe could be created by God Almighty in one moment and by a big explosion in the next — and on and on.</quote><quote id="155" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">That, in my opinion, was the most diabolical aspect of those old-time brains: They would tell their owners, in effect, "Here's a crazy thing we could actually do, probably, but would never do it, of course. It's just fun to think about." 
And then, as though in trances, the people would really do it — have slaves fight each other to death in the Colosseum, or burn people alive in the public square for holding opinions which were locally unpopular, or build factories whose only purpose was to kill people in industrial quantities, or to blow up whole cities, and on and on.</quote><quote id="156" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Why so many of us a million years ago purposely knocked out major chunks of our brains with alcohol from time to time remains an interesting mystery. It may be we were trying to give evolution a shove in the right direction -- in the direction of smaller brains.</quote><quote id="157" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Time is liquid." One moment is no more important than any other and all moments quickly run away.</quote><quote id="158" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I've got news for Mr. Santayana: we're doomed to repeat the past no matter what. That's what it is to be alive.</quote><quote id="159" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Belief is nearly the whole of the Universe, whether based on truth or not."</quote><quote id="160" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Who is more to be pitied, a writer bound and gagged by policemen or one living in perfect freedom who has nothing more to say?</quote><quote id="161" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">What is literature but an insider's newsletter about affairs relating to molecules, of no importance to anything in the Universe but a few molecules who have the disease called 'thought'.</quote><quote id="162" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">My soul knows my meat is doing bad things, and is embarrassed. But my meat just keeps right on doing bad, dumb things."</quote><quote id="163" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"We're having a celebration, so all sorts of things have been said which are not true," I said. "That's how to act at a party."</quote><quote id="164" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I can't help it," I said. "My soul knows my meat is doing bad things, and is embarrassed. But my meat just keeps right on doing bad, dumb things."&lt;br /&gt;"You and your what?" he said.&lt;br /&gt;"My soul and my meat," I said.&lt;br /&gt;"They're separate?" he said.&lt;br /&gt;"I sure hope they are," I said. I laughed. "I would hate to be responsible for what my meat does."</quote><quote id="165" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">It is a gruesome Disneyland. Nobody is cute there.</quote><quote id="166" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"And what is literature but an insider's newsletter about affairs relating to molecules, of no importance to anything in the Universe but a few molecules who have a disease called 'thought'."</quote><quote id="167" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"When the excrement hit the air condition" (Recurring phrase throughout many chapters)</quote><quote id="168" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I think William Shakespeare was the wisest human being I ever heard of. To be perfectly frank, though, that's not saying much." We are impossibly conceited animals, and actually dumb as heck. Ask any teacher. You don't even have to ask a teacher. Ask anybody. Dogs and cats are smarter than we are.</quote><quote id="169" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"The sermon was based on what he claimed was a well-known fact, that there were no Atheists in foxholes. I asked Jack what he thought of the sermon afterwards, and he said, "There's a Chaplain who never visited the front.""</quote><quote id="170" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">If facts weren't funny, or scary, or couldn't make you rich, the heck with them.</quote><quote id="171" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"The most important message of a crucifix, to me anyway, was how unspeakably cruel supposedly sane human beings can be when under orders from a superior authority."</quote><quote id="172" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"See the nigger fly the airplane!"</quote><quote id="173" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">They're playin our song Gene!</quote><quote id="174" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Beer, of course, is actually a depressant. But poor people will never stop hoping otherwise."</quote><quote id="175" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">She was an alcoholic. I didn't blame myself for that. The worst problem in the life of any alcoholic is alcohol.</quote><quote id="176" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I wish I had been born a bird instead," he said.&lt;br /&gt;"I wish we had all been born birds instead."</quote><quote id="177" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Just because some of us can read and write and do a little math, that doesn't mean we deserve to conquer the Universe."</quote><quote id="178" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">How embarrassing to be human.</quote><quote id="179" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I asked Rob Roy where he had gone to college.&lt;br /&gt;"Yale," he said.&lt;br /&gt;I told him what Helen Dole said about Yale, that it ought to be called "Plantation Owners' Tech."&lt;br /&gt;"I don't get it," he said.&lt;br /&gt;"I had to ask her to explain it myself," I said. "She said Yale was where plantation owners learned how to get the natives to kill each other instead of them."</quote><quote id="180" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">[Freedom of speech] isn't something somebody else gives you. That's something you give to yourself.</quote><quote id="181" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Bergeron's epitaph for the planet, I remember, which he said should be carved in big letters in a wall of the Grand Canyon for the flying-saucer people to find, was this:&lt;p&gt;WE COULD HAVE SAVED IT&lt;br /&gt;BUT WE WERE TOO DOGGONE CHEAP&lt;p&gt;Only he didn't say 'doggone.'"</quote><quote id="182" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Another flaw in the human character is that everybody wants to build and nobody wants to do maintenance."</quote><quote id="183" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">During my three years in Vietnam, I certainly heard plenty of last words by dying American footsoldiers. Not one of them, however, had illusions that he had somehow accomplished something worthwhile in the process of making the Supreme Sacrifice.</quote><quote id="184" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">profanity and obscenity entitle people who don't want unpleasant information to close their ears and eyes to you.</quote><quote id="185" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I think yet again of my father, who struggled to become a painter after he was forced into early and unwelcome retirement by the Great Depression. He has reason to be optimistic about his new career, since the early stages of his pictures, whether still or portraits or landscapes, were full of pow. Mother, meaning to be helpful, would say of each one: "That's really wonderful, Kurt. Now all you have to do is finish it." He would then ruin it. I remember a portrait he did of his only brother, Alex, who was an insurance salesman, which he called "Special Agent". When he roughed it in, his hand and eye conspired with a few bold strokes to capture several important truths about Alex, including a hint of disappointment. Uncle Alex was a proud graduate of Harvard, who would rather have been a scholar of literature than an insurance man.&lt;br /&gt;When Father finished the portrait, made sure every square inch of masonite had its share of paint, Uncle Alex had disappeared entirely. We had a drunk and lustful Queen Victoria instead. This was terrible.</quote><quote id="186" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I don't care if I'm remembered or not when I'm dead. (A scientist I knew at General Electric, who was married to a woman named Josephine, said to me, "Why should I buy life insurance? If I die, I won't care what's happening to Jo. I won't care about anything. I'll be dead.")</quote><quote id="187" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"All persons, living and dead, are purely coincidental."</quote><quote id="188" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Many people need desperately to receive this message: "I feel and think much as you do, care about many of the things you care about, although most people don't care about them. You are not alone."</quote><quote id="189" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"You were sick, but now you're well, and there's work to do."</quote><quote id="190" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Why throw money at problems? That's what money is "for".&lt;br /&gt;Should the nation's wealth be redistributed? It has been and continues to be redistributed to a few people in a manner strikingly unhelpful.</quote><quote id="191" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">As in my other works of fiction: All persons living and dead are purely coincidental, and should not be construed. No names have been changed in order to protect the innocent. Angels protect the innocent as a matter of Heavenly routine.</quote><quote id="192" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">My first near-death experience was an accident, a botched anesthesia during a triple bypass. I had listened to several people on TV talk shows who had gone down the blue tunnel to the Pearly Gates, and even beyond the Pearly Gates, or so they said, and then come back to life again. But I certainly wouldn't have set out on such a risky expedition on purpose, without first having survived one ...&lt;br /&gt;To go through the Pearly Gates, no matter how tempting the interviewee on the other side, as I myself discovered the hard way, is to run the risk that crotchety Saint Peter, depending on his mood, may never let you out again. Think of how heartbroken your friends and relatives would be if, by going through the Pearly Gates to talk to Napoleon, say, you in effect committed suicide.</quote><quote id="193" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"About belief or lack of belief in an afterlife: Some of you may know that I am neither Christian nor Jewish nor Buddhist, nor a conventionally religious person of any sort.&lt;br /&gt;I am a humanist, which mean, in part, that I have tried to behave decently without any expectation of rewards or punishments after I'm dead." My German-American ancestors, the earliest of whom settled in our Middle West about the time of our Civil War, called themselves "Freethinkers," which is the same sort of thing. My great grandfather Clemens Vonnegut wrote, for example," "If what Jesus said was good, what can it matter whether he was God or not?""&lt;br /&gt;I myself have written, "If it weren't for the message of mercy and pity in Jesus' Sermon on the Mount, I wouldn't want to be a human being. I would just as soon be a rattlesnake."</quote><quote id="194" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I am honorary president of the American Humanist Association, having succeeded the late, great, spectacularly prolific writer and scientist, Dr. Isaac Asimov in that essentially functionless capacity. At an A.H.A. memorial service for my predecessor I said, "Isaac is up in Heaven now." That was the funniest thing I could have said to an audience of humanists. It rolled them in the aisles. Mirth! Several minutes had to pass before something resembling solemnity could be restored.&lt;br /&gt;I made that joke, of course, before my first near-death experience — the accidental one.&lt;br /&gt;"So when my own time comes to join the choir invisible or whatever, God forbid, I hope someone will say, "He's up in Heaven now." Who really knows? I could have dreamed all this."&lt;br /&gt;My epitaph in any case? ""Everything was beautiful. Nothing hurt."" I will have gotten off so light, whatever the heck it is that was going on.</quote><quote id="195" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I wish one and all long and happy lives, no matter what may become of them afterwards. Use sunscreen! Don’t smoke cigarettes. Cigars, however, are good for you … Firearms are also good for you … Gunpowder has zero fat and zero cholesterol. That goes for dumdums, too.</quote><quote id="196" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Sigmund Freud|Freud said he didn’t know what women wanted. I know what women want. They want a whole lot of people to talk to.</quote><quote id="197" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">What do men want? They want a lot of pals, and they wish that people wouldn’t get so mad at them.</quote><quote id="198" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Ta ta and adios. Or, as Saint Peter said to me with a sly wink, when I told him I was on my last-round trip to Paradise: “See you later, Alligator.”</quote><quote id="199" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I asked this heroic pet lover how it felt to have died for a schnauzer named Teddy. Salvador Biagiani was philosophical. He said it sure beat dying for absolutely nothing in the Viet Nam War.</quote><quote id="200" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">His plan? To pass out weapons to slaves, so they could overthrow their masters. Suicide.</quote><quote id="201" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I was lucky enough on this trip to interview none other than the late Adolf Hitler. I was gratified to learn that he now feels remorse for any actions of his, however indirectly, which might have had anything to do with the violent deaths suffered by thirty-five million people during World War II. He and his mistress Eva Braun, of course were among those casualties, along with four million other Germans, six million Jews, eighteen million citizens of the Soviet Union and so on.&lt;br /&gt;“I paid my dues with everyone else,” he said.&lt;br /&gt;It is his hope that a modest monument, possibly a stone cross, since he was a Christian, will be erected somewhere in his memory, possibly on the grounds of the United Nations Headquarters in New York. It should be incised, he said, with his name and dates 1889-1945. Underneath should be a two-word sentence in German: “Entschuldigen Sie.”&lt;br /&gt;Roughly translated into English, this comes out, “I beg your pardon,” or “Excuse Me.”</quote><quote id="202" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">During my controlled near-death experiences, I’ve met Sir Darwin to come up with the theory of evolution, to Pasteur to come up with the germ theory, and to Albert Einstein to come up with relativity. “I must have been deaf, dumb, and blind not to have come up with those myself,” he said to me. “What could have been more obvious?”</quote><quote id="203" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">During my most recently controlled near-death experience, I got to interview William Shakespeare. We did not hit it off. He said the dialect I spoke was the ugliest English he had ever heard, “fit to split the ears of groundlings.” He asked if it had a name, and I said “Indianapolis.”</quote><quote id="204" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"Human beings are chimpanzees who get crazy drunk on power." By saying that our leaders are power-drunk chimpanzees, am I in danger of wrecking the morale of our soldiers fighting and dying in the Middle East? Their morale, like so many bodies, is already shot to pieces. "They are being treated, as I never was, like toys a rich kid got for Christmas."</quote><quote id="205" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">For some reason, the most vocal Christians among us never mention the Beatitudes. But, often with tears in their eyes, they demand that the Ten Commandments be posted in public buildings. And of course that’s Moses, not Jesus. "I haven’t heard one of them demand that the Sermon on the Mount, the Beatitudes, be posted anywhere.&lt;br /&gt;"Blessed are the merciful" in a courtroom? "Blessed are the peacemakers" in the Pentagon? Give me a break!"</quote><quote id="206" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">There is a tragic flaw in our precious Constitution, and I don’t know what can be done to fix it. This is it: "Only nut cases want to be president."</quote><quote id="207" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">What does “A.D.” signify? That commemorates an inmate of this lunatic asylum we call Earth who was nailed to a wooden cross by a bunch of other inmates. With him still conscious, they hammered spikes through his wrists and insteps, and into the wood. Then they set the cross upright, so he dangled up there where even the shortest person in the crowd could see him writhing this way and that. Can you imagine people doing such a thing to a person?</quote><quote id="208" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Listen. All great literature is about what a bummer it is to be a human being: "Moby Dick, Huckleberry Finn, The Red Badge of Courage", the "Iliad" and the "Odyssey", "The Charge of the Light Brigade."</quote><quote id="209" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"I have to say this in defense of humankind: No matter in what era in history, including the Garden of Eden, everybody just got there." And, except for the Garden of Eden, there were already all these crazy games going on, which could make you act crazy, even if you weren’t crazy to begin with. Some of the games that were already going on when you got here were love and hate, liberalism and conservatism, automobiles and credit cards, golf and girls’ basketball.&lt;br /&gt;"Even crazier than golf, though, is modern American politics, where, thanks to TV and for the convenience of TV, you can only be one of two kinds of human beings, either a liberal or a conservative."</quote><quote id="210" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">If you want to take my guns away from me, and you’re all for murdering fetuses, and love it when homosexuals marry each other, and want to give them kitchen appliances at their showers, and you’re for the poor, you’re a liberal. If you are against those perversions and for the rich, you’re a conservative. What could be simpler?</quote><quote id="211" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">So let’s give another big tax cut to the super-rich. That’ll teach bin Laden a lesson he won’t soon forget.</quote><quote id="212" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I am of course notoriously hooked on cigarettes. I keep hoping the things will kill me. A fire at one end and a fool at the other.</quote><quote id="213" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Here’s what I think the truth is: We are all addicts of fossil fuels in a state of denial, about to face cold turkey. And like so many addicts about to face cold turkey, our leaders are now committing violent crimes to get what little is left of what we’re hooked on.</quote><quote id="214" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">One of the few good things about modern times: If you die horribly on television, you will not have died in vain. You will have entertained us.</quote><quote id="215" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"In case you haven’t noticed, we are now almost as feared and hated all over the world as the Nazis were."</quote><quote id="216" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">In case you haven’t noticed, we…dehumanize our own soldiers, not because of their religion or race, but because of their low social class. Send ’em anywhere. Make ’em do anything. Piece of cake.</quote><quote id="217" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">"War is now a form of TV entertainment", and what made the First World War so particularly entertaining were two American inventions, barbed wire and the machine gun.</quote><quote id="218" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Shrapnel was invented by an Englishman of the same name. Don't you wish you could have something named after you?</quote><quote id="219" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">My last words? "Life is no way to treat an animal, not even a mouse."</quote><quote id="220" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Napalm came from Harvard. Veritas!</quote><quote id="221" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Our president is a Christian? So was Adolf Hitler.</quote><quote id="222" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">And now I want to tell you about my late Uncle Alex. He was my father’s kid brother, a childless graduate of Harvard who was an honest life insurance salesman in Indianapolis. He was well-read and wise. And his principal complaint about other human beings was that they so seldom noticed it when they were happy. So when we were drinking lemonade under an apple tree in the summer, say, and talking lazily about this and that, almost buzzing like honeybees, Uncle Alex would suddenly interrupt the agreeable blather to exclaim, "If this isn’t nice, I don’t know what is."  So I do the same now, and so do my kids and grandkids. And I urge you to please notice when you are happy, and exclaim or murmur or think at some point, "If this isn’t nice, I don’t  know what is."</quote><quote id="223" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Requiem:&lt;p&gt;The crucified planet Earth,&lt;br /&gt;should it find a voice&lt;br /&gt;and a sense of irony,&lt;br /&gt;might now well say&lt;br /&gt;of our abuse of it,&lt;br /&gt;"Forgive them, Father,&lt;br /&gt;They know not what they do."&lt;p&gt;The irony would be&lt;br /&gt;that we know what&lt;br /&gt;we are doing.&lt;p&gt;When the last living thing&lt;br /&gt;has died on account of us,&lt;br /&gt;how poetical it would be&lt;br /&gt;if Earth could say,&lt;br /&gt;in a voice floating up&lt;br /&gt;perhaps&lt;br /&gt;from the floor&lt;br /&gt;of the Grand Canyon,&lt;br /&gt;"It is done."&lt;br /&gt;People did not like it here.</quote><quote id="224" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">George W. Bush has gathered around him upper-crust C-students who know no history or geography.</quote><quote id="225" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Doesn't anything socialistic make you want to throw up? Like great public schools, or health insurance for all?</quote><quote id="226" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">During the Vietnam War, Abbie Hoffman announced that the new high was banana peels taken rectally. So then FBI scientists stuffed banana peels up their asses to find out if this was true or not.</quote><quote id="227" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">What is it, what can it possibly be about blowjobs and golf?</quote><quote id="228" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">If God were alive today, he would have to be an atheist, because the excrement has hit the air-conditioning big time, big time.</quote><quote id="229" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Is it possible that seemingly incredible geniuses like Bach and Shakespeare and Einstein were not in fact superhuman, but simply plagiarists, copying great stuff from the future?</quote><quote id="230" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Old Norwegian Proverb: Swedes have short dicks but long memories.</quote><quote id="231" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">My father said "When in doubt, castle."</quote><quote id="232" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">[Vietnam] only made billionaires out of millionaires. [Iraq] is making trillionaires out of billionaires. Now I call that progress.</quote><quote id="233" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Here is a lesson in creative writing. First rule: Do not use semicolons. They are transvestite hermaphrodites representing absolutely nothing. All they do is show you've been to college.</quote><quote id="234" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Humor is an almost physiological response to fear.</quote><quote id="235" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I think that novels that leave out technology misrepresent life as badly as Victorians misrepresented life by leaving out sex.</quote><quote id="236" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">There is a tragic flaw in our precious Constitution, and I don't' know what can be done to fix it. This is it: Only nut cases want to be president.</quote><quote id="237" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Socialism is no more an evil word than Christianity. Socialism no more prescribed Joseph Stalin and his secret police and shuttered churches than Christianity prescribed the Spanish Inquisition. Christianity and socialism alike, in fact, prescribe a society dedicated to the proposition that all men, women, and children are created equal and shall not starve.</quote><quote id="238" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Some of the loudest, most proudly ignorant guessing in the world is going on in Washington today. Our leaders are sick of all the solid information that has been dumped on humanity by research and scholarship and investigative reporting. They think that the whole country is sick of it, and they could be right. It isn't the gold standard that they want to put us back on. They want something even more basic. They want to put us back on the snake-oil standard.</quote><quote id="239" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">The highest treason in the USA is to say Americans are not loved, no matter where they are, no matter what they are doing there.</quote><quote id="240" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">If you actually are an educated, thinking person, you will not be welcome in Washington DC.</quote><quote id="241" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">We are about to be attacked by Al Qaeda. Wave flags if you have them. That always seems to scare them away. I'm kidding.</quote><quote id="242" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">[America's soldiers] are being treated ... like toys a rich kid got for Christmas.</quote><quote id="243" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">While we were being bombed in Dresden, sitting in a cellar with our arms over our heads in case the ceiling fell, one slider said as though he were a duchess in a mansion on a cold and rainy night, “I wonder what the poor people are doing tonight.” Nobody laughed, but we were still all glad he said it.</quote><quote id="244" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">We are here on Earth to fart around. Don't let anybody tell you any different.</quote><quote id="245" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">If I should ever die, God forbid, I hope you will say, “Kurt is up in heaven now.” That's my favorite joke.</quote><quote id="246" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">A joke is like building a mousetrap from scratch. You have to work pretty hard to make the thing snap when it is supposed to snap.</quote><quote id="247" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Humor is a way of holding off how awful life can be.</quote><quote id="248" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">I don't know about you, but I practice a disorganized religion. I belong to an unholy disorder. We call ourselves “Our Lady of Perpetual Astonishment.”</quote><quote id="249" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">There is no good reason good can't triumph over evil, if only angels will get organized along the lines of the mafia.</quote><quote id="250" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">You know, the truth can be really powerful stuff. You're not expecting it.</quote><quote id="251" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Evolution is so creative. That's how we got giraffes.</quote><quote id="252" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">Do you think Arabs are dumb? They gave us our numbers. Try doing long division with Roman numerals.</quote><quote id="253" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">It is almost always a mistake to mention Abraham Lincoln. He always steals the show.</quote><quote id="254" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">We've sure come a long way since then. Sometimes I wish we hadn't. I hate H-bombs and the Jerry Springer show.</quote><quote id="255" author="Kurt Vonnegut" cats="Absurdists|Authors|Novelists|Satirists|Short story writers" ref="">If you want to really hurt your parents, and you don't have the nerve to be gay, the least you can do is go into the arts. I'm not kidding. The arts are not a way to make a living. They are a very human way of making life more bearable. Practicing an art, no matter how well or badly, is a way to make your soul grow, for heaven's sake. Sing in the shower. Dance to the radio. Tell stories. Write a poem to a friend, even a lousy poem. Do it as well as you possibly can. You will get an enormous reward. You will have created something.</quote></quotes>