<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="ru|bg|pt|el|tr|it|hu|en"><quote id="0" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"I've seen these women all my life, I know how they walk, I know how they talk..."</quote><quote id="1" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Truth is, I've always been selling out. The difference is that in the past, I looked like I had integrity because there were no buyers.</quote><quote id="2" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">There's so much plastic in this culture that vinyl leopard skin is becoming an endangered synthetic.</quote><quote id="3" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">What if it's boring... or if it's not boring, it might be too revealing, or worse, it might be too revealing and still be boring.</quote><quote id="4" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"I have always felt that humor was a wonderful vehicle to let us become connected with each other and ourselves… I try to portray the similarities and polarities in men and women, so that we can acknowledge and embrace our collective consciousness."</quote><quote id="5" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">If you can't be direct, why be?</quote><quote id="6" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"I feel some part of me can wake up and be very existential and the next day wake up and be sort of in love with the universe."</quote><quote id="7" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">When you talk about yourself for 35 years, first of all, it gets repetitious. And then it seems a little bit excessive, at the least.</quote><quote id="8" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">People think there's some real subversive thing playing against whoever it is; a lot of it is just people who want to go along and get along. And they also want to make money. And the bottom line is, they're going to put out as much stuff as they can — stupid, banal stuff that makes money.</quote><quote id="9" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"The larger picture is really to swing people's awareness of what really is moral. ..." There are great clergy-people who absolutely do not agree with this. It's not whether God is on our side or whether we're doing God's will, it's being so narcissistic as to think that God is telling you what to do.</quote><quote id="10" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">We went to a Southern Baptist church. When I was a small child, until I was about 8 or 9 years old, I worried if I didn't go forward and get saved every Sunday — which I couldn't do, it was absolutely too humiliating to see these adults flailing and beating their breasts and sobbing, and I thought, Oh, my God, this is so ridiculous, so embarrassing — I could never bring myself to go forward. And I'd think, Oh, my God, if I don't go next Sunday, if the end of the world comes, I'll go to hell. And that's is a pretty hard thing for a 7- or 8-year-old to carry all the time </quote><quote id="11" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">The point I want to make is, the idea that people will say — out of the 170,000 people or however many were killed in the tsunami — they'll say, "God saved me." As if God particularly saved this person. There's a tremendous amount of narcissism in that belief, that God is speaking directly to you. I mean, it's unbelievable. ... All these disparate opinions and points of view that people say they're getting as direct divine guidance — I've been concerned for decades about presidents who claim to be born again. And knowing that everyone I knew in the fundamentalist church or in the evangelical Christian church — they wanted the rapture to come. ... We don't have to save the environment, because we're not going to be around.</quote><quote id="12" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">""9 to 5" made people aware of equal pay for equal work. It hasn't really happened, but it has come closer." We're aware of sexual harassment, and of course, there are very few companies that have daycare centers, which seems to me would be the most humane, positive thing to do for a worker. The worker would be more loyal, they'd be more productive. It's so crazy not to do the human thing. It seems to me to be much more profitable to do the human thing. It just makes a better society.</quote><quote id="13" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Jane took me to another level because she's truly a wonderful writer. I'd put things together in the past and struggled with them. And then I met Jane. ... I was doing my Edith Ann album in '71 — the album came out in '72. She'd done a thing on television called "J.T." — it was about a kid in Harlem — and she won a Peabody for it. I later learned it was the first thing she'd ever written. 
It was written as an "After School Special", but they played it in prime time — and they played it every year after that for about 25 years, or something. Anyway, I saw it and it was wonderful. It was poetic and sensitive and satiric and tender and funny and so many things compressed into this one hour. And I thought, "Oh, God, this is "exactly" what I want in a monologue." So I wrote Jane and asked her to help me do the "Edith Ann" album. I didn't hear from her for a while. Then, suddenly, about a week before I was supposed to go in and record, she sent me a lot of material. I persuaded her to come to California and help me produce it. Frankly, I was pretty taken with her as soon as I saw her. We just sort of clicked. We became a couple right away.</quote><quote id="14" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">I respect her talent and her brain and who she is as a person — and that kind of admiration and respect is a big factor in binding someone in a relationship. I know what a good heart she has, and how empathetic she is with all kinds of people and issues — she's so brilliant on top of it that she can voice these things. And she's as funny as she can possibly be. She makes me laugh.</quote><quote id="15" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Some journalists are just motivated by their own sense of what they want to say or what they feel comfortable saying or writing about. In '77, I was on the cover of "Time". The same week I had a big story in "Newsweek." In one of the magazines it says I live alone, and the other magazine said I live with Jane Wagner. Unless you were so really adamantly out, and had made some declaration at some press conference, people back then didn't write about your relationship.</quote><quote id="16" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"Listen, I have no judgment about anything. Some people will bring certain celebrities up to me who are presumably — or known to be — gay and ask "Why don't they come out?" But we don't know why they don't, and it's none of our business, really." In '75 I was making the "Modern Scream" album, and Jane and I were in the studio. My publicist called me and said ""Time" will give you the cover if you'll come out." I was more offended than anything that they thought we'd make a deal. But that was '75 — it would have been a hard thing to do at that time.</quote><quote id="17" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"It's a more ridiculing, divisive humor today", especially with the advent of political incorrectness, which is a license to be as ridiculing and awful about certain groups... There should be room for everybody, absolutely, and then the culture is going to decide the prevailing weight. We can't decide it individually. "Nobody is here without a reason. ... I always had a different sensibility. I like a huge range of comedy — from broad and farcical, the most sensitive, the most understated — but I always wanted my comedy to be more embracing of the species rather than debasing of it."</quote><quote id="18" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Don't be afraid of missing opportunities. Behind every failure is an opportunity somebody wishes they had missed.</quote><quote id="19" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">For fast acting relief, try slowing down.</quote><quote id="20" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">If love is the answer, could you please rephrase the question?</quote><quote id="21" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">If the formula for water is H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O, is the formula for an ice cube H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O squared?</quote><quote id="22" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">If truth is beauty, how come no one has their hair done in the library?</quote><quote id="23" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">If you read a lot of books, you're considered well-read. But if you watch a lot of TV, you're not considered well-viewed.</quote><quote id="24" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"Sometimes I worry about being a success in a mediocre world."</quote><quote id="25" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"The best mind-altering drug is truth."</quote><quote id="26" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"The trouble with the rat race is that even if you win, you're still a rat."</quote><quote id="27" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"Why is it when we talk to God we're said to be praying — but when God talks to us, we're said to be schizophrenic?"</quote><quote id="28" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"Interviewer": You once said you had a drug problem...
"Lily": Yeah, I still do. It's so hard to find good grass these days.</quote><quote id="29" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"I like a teacher who gives you something to take home to think about besides homework"</quote><quote id="30" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"Reality is nothing but a collective hunch."</quote><quote id="31" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Reality is the leading cause of stress amongst those in touch with it....</quote><quote id="32" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"Reality is a crutch for people who can't cope with drugs."</quote><quote id="33" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">When you're dancing the mystical dance of the molecules, you're not the one who's leading.</quote><quote id="34" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"It's my belief we developed language because of our deep inner need to complain."</quote><quote id="35" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"All my life, I've always wanted to be somebody, but I see now I should have been more specific."</quote><quote id="36" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">If I had known what it would be like to have it all... I might have been willing to settle for less.</quote><quote id="37" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"Sometimes I feel like a figment of my own imagination."</quote><quote id="38" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"No matter how cynical you become, it's never enough to keep up."</quote><quote id="39" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">I bet the worst part about dying is the part where your whole life passes before you.</quote><quote id="40" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Your problem is your role models were models.</quote><quote id="41" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">I swear people don't want sex so much as they want somebody who'll listen to 'em ... the first thing you learn after fellatio is how to listen.</quote><quote id="42" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"Remember we're all in this alone."</quote><quote id="43" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">If evolution was worth its salt, it should've evolved something better than 'survival of the fittest.' I think a better idea would be 'survival of the wittiest.' At least, that way, creatures that didn't survive could've died laughing.</quote><quote id="44" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Wouldn't it be great if we all grew up to be what we wanted to be? The world would be full of nurses, firemen, and ballerinas.</quote><quote id="45" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Why isn't there a special name for the tops of your feet?</quote><quote id="46" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">[http://www.lilytomlin.com Lily Tomlin's official website]</quote><quote id="47" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">[http://www.afterellen.com/People/2005/3/lilytomlin.html AfterEllen profile]</quote><quote id="48" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">{{imdb name|0005499|Lily Tomlin}}</quote><quote id="49" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">{{nndb name|661/000022595|Lily Tomlin}}</quote><quote id="50" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">[http://www.findarticles.com/p/articles/mi_m1589/is_2005_March_15/ai_n13629326 "Thoroughly modern Lily" in "The Advocate" (15 March 2005)]</quote><quote id="51" author="Lily Tomlin" cats="American actors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">[http://www.metroweekly.com/feature/?ak=2088 Metro Weekly interview (27 April 2006)]</quote></quotes>