<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="eo|bg|pt|de|tr|it|en|uk|cs|pl"><quote id="0" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"Well, maybe I'm a latent homosexual." He considered that for a moment. "Or maybe I'm a latent heterosexual. Anyway, I'm pretty latent. I don't know why. Of course, I've taken a number of stabs at it, but then I start thinking about the futility of it all and I give up. Maybe it's because you're expected to do something and after a certain point all I want to do is lie there and stare at the ceiling." </quote><quote id="1" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"The Eskimo has fifty-two names for snow because it is important to them; there ought to be as many for love."</quote><quote id="2" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"Variant: The Eskimos had 52 names for snow because it was important to them; there ought to be as many for love."</quote><quote id="3" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">A divorce is like an amputation; you survive, but there’s less of you.</quote><quote id="4" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"I would rather dance as a ballerina, though faultily, than as a flawless clown."</quote><quote id="5" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">He's just a contact of hers, which is not the same as a friend. While she was in the hospital she decided that most of her friends were really just contacts.</quote><quote id="6" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">He had that faint sick look in his eyes, as if he wanted to give her something, charity for instance.</quote><quote id="7" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">The policemen's faces glisten too, they're holding themselves back, they love this, it's a ceremony, they're implementing a policy</quote><quote id="8" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"Another belief of mine: that everyone else my age is an adult, whereas I am merely in disguise."</quote><quote id="9" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">Time is not a line but a dimension, like the dimensions of space.</quote><quote id="10" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">Roughing it builds a boy's character, but only certain kinds of roughing it.</quote><quote id="11" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"War is what happens when language fails."</quote><quote id="12" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">I am certain that a Sewing Machine would relieve as much human suffering as a hundred Lunatic Asylums, and possibly a good deal more.</quote><quote id="13" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">Ten days after the war ended, my sister Laura drove a car off a bridge. The bridge was being repaired: she went right through the Danger sign. The car fell a hundred feet into the ravine, smashing through the treetops feathery with new leaves, then burst into flames and rolled down into the shallow creek at the bottom. Chunks of the bridge fell on top of it. Nothing much was left but charred smithereens.</quote><quote id="14" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"All stories are about wolves. All worth repeating, that is. Anything else is sentimental drivel." …Think about it. There's escaping from the wolves, fighting the wolves, capturing the wolves, taming the wolves. Being thrown to the wolves, or throwing others to the wolves so the wolves will eat them instead of you. Running with the wolf pack. Turning into a wolf. Best of all, turning into the head wolf. No other decent stories exist.</quote><quote id="15" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">Adam named the living animals, MaddAddam names the dead ones.</quote><quote id="16" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">I'm working on my own life story. I don't mean I'm putting it together; no, I'm taking it apart.</quote><quote id="17" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">""Why do men feel threatened by women?"" I asked a male friend of mine. (I love that wonderful rhetorical device, "a male friend of mine." It's often used by female journalists when they want to say something particularly bitchy but don't want to be held responsible for it themselves. It also lets people know that you "do" have male friends, that you aren't one of those fire-breathing mythical monsters, The Radical Feminists, who walk around with little pairs of scissors and kick men in the shins if they open doors for you. "A male friend of mine" also gives--let us admit it--a certain weight to the opinions expressed.) So this male friend of mine, who does by the way exist, conveniently entered into the following dialogue. "I mean," I said, "men are bigger, most of the time, they can run faster, strangle better, and they have on the average a lot more money and power." ""They're afraid women will laugh at them,"" he said. "Undercut their world view." Then I asked some women students in a quickie poetry seminar I was giving, ""Why do women feel threatened by men?" "They're afraid of being killed,"" they said.</quote><quote id="18" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"The weapons
that were once outside
sharpening themselves on war
are now indoors
there, in the fortress,
fragile
in glass cases"; &lt;p&gt; Why is it
(I’m thinking
of the careful moulding
round the stonework archways)
that in this time, such
elaborate defences keep
things that are no longer
(much)
worth defending?</quote><quote id="19" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"Your righteous eyes, your laconic
trigger-fingers
people the streets with villains:
as you move, the air in front of you
blossoms with targets &lt;p&gt; and you leave behind you a heroic
trail of desolation":
beer bottles
slaughtered by the side
of the road, bird-
skulls bleaching in the sunset.</quote><quote id="20" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"I am the horizon
you ride towards, the thing you can never lasso" &lt;p&gt; I am also what surrounds you:
my brain
scattered with your
tincans, bones, empty shells,
the litter of your invasions. &lt;p&gt; I am the space you desecrate
as you pass through.</quote><quote id="21" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">When you hear me singing
you get the rifle down
and the flashlight, aiming for my brain,
but you always miss &lt;p&gt; and when you set out the poison
I piss on it
to warn the others.</quote><quote id="22" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">I am yours. If you feed me garbage,
I will sing a song of garbage.
This is a hymn.</quote><quote id="23" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"In view of the fading animals
the proliferation of sewers and fears
the sea clogging, the air
nearing extinction &lt;p&gt; we should be kind, we should
take warning, we should forgive each other &lt;p&gt; Instead we are opposite, we
touch as though attacking, &lt;p&gt; the gifts we bring
even in good faith maybe
warp in our hands to
implements, to manoeuvres"</quote><quote id="24" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">In restaurants we argue
over which of us will pay for your funeral &lt;p&gt; though the real question is
whether or not I will make you immortal.</quote><quote id="25" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">There is more than one kind of freedom, said Aunt Lydia. Freedom to and freedom from. In the days of anarchy, it was freedom to. Now you are being given freedom from. Don't underrate it.</quote><quote id="26" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">Tell, rather than write, because I have nothing to write with and writing is in any case forbidden. But if it’s a story, even in my head, I must be telling it to someone. You don’t tell a story only to yourself. There’s always someone else.
Even when there is no one.</quote><quote id="27" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"Nolite te bastardes carborundorum."</quote><quote id="28" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">Ignoring isn’t the same as ignorance, you have to work at it.</quote><quote id="29" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">You must cultivate poverty of spirit. Blessed are the meek. She didn’t go on to say anything about inheriting the earth.</quote><quote id="30" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">The sitting room is subdued, symmetrical; it’s one of the shapes money takes when it freezes.</quote><quote id="31" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"Blessed are they that mourn, for they shall be comforted."
Nobody said when.</quote><quote id="32" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">Sanity is a valuable possession; I hoard it the way people once hoarded money. I save it, so I will have enough, when the time comes.</quote><quote id="33" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">A man is just a woman’s strategy for making other women.</quote><quote id="34" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">You can think clearly only with your clothes on.</quote><quote id="35" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">I'll take care of it, Luke said. And because he said "it" instead of "her," I knew he meant "kill." That is what you have to do before you kill, I thought. You have to create an it, where none was before. You do that first, in your head, and then you make it real.</quote><quote id="36" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">(She is reciting the Lord’s prayer) Now we come to forgiveness. Don’t worry about forgiving me right now. There are more important things. For instance: keep the others safe, if they are safe. Don’t let them suffer too much. If they have to die, let it be fast. You might even provide a Heaven for them. We need You for that. Hell we can make for ourselves.</quote><quote id="37" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">You can’t make an omelette without breaking eggs, is what he says. We thought we could do better.
Better? I say, in a small voice. How can he think this is better?
Better never means better for everyone, he says. It always means worse, for some.</quote><quote id="38" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">Freedom, like everything else, is relative.</quote><quote id="39" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">A movie about the past is not the same as the past.</quote><quote id="40" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">By telling you anything at all I'm at least believing in you, I believe you're there, I believe you into being. Because I'm telling you this story I will your existence. I tell, therefore you are.</quote><quote id="41" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">As all historians know, the past is a great darkness, and filled with echoes. Voices may reach us from it; but what they say to us is imbued with the obscurity of the matrix out of which they come; and, try as we may, we cannot always decipher them precisely in the clearer light of our own day.</quote><quote id="42" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"She has been condemned to death by hanging. A man 
may escape this death by becoming the hangman, a 
woman by marrying the hangman. But at the present 
time there is no hangman; thus there is no escape. 
There is only a death, indefinitely postponed. This is 
not fantasy, it is history."</quote><quote id="43" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"To live in prison is to live without mirrors. To live 
without mirrors is to live without the self." She is 
living selflessly, she finds a hole in the stone wall and 
on the other side of the wall, a voice. The voice 
comes through darkness and has no face. This voice 
becomes her mirror. </quote><quote id="44" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">In order to avoid her death, her particular death, with 
wrung neck and swollen tongue, she must marry the 
hangman.</quote><quote id="45" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">She must 
transform his hands so they will be willing to twist 
the rope around throats that have been singled out 
as hers was, throats other than hers. She must marry 
the hangman or no one, but that is not so bad. Who 
else is there to marry? </quote><quote id="46" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"You wonder about her crime. She was condemned 
to death for stealing clothes from her employer, from 
the wife of her employer. She wished to make herself 
more beautiful. This desire in servants was not legal."</quote><quote id="47" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">He was not condemned to death, freedom awaited 
him. What was the temptation, the one that worked? 
Perhaps he wanted to live with a woman whose life 
he had saved, who had seen down into the earth but 
had nevertheless followed him back up to life. It was 
his only chance to be a hero, to one person at least, 
for if he became the hangman the others would 
despise him. He was in prison for wounding another 
man, on one finger of the right hand, with a sword. 
This too is history. </quote><quote id="48" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"My friends, who are both women, tell me their stories, 
which cannot be believed and which are true. They 
are horror stories and they have not happened to me, 
they have not yet happened to me, they have 
happened to me but we are detached, we watch our 
unbelief with horror."</quote><quote id="49" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">He wants only the simple things: a chair, 
someone to pull off his shoes, someone to watch him 
while he talks, with admiration and fear, gratitude if 
possible, someone in whom to plunge himself for rest 
and renewal. These things can best be had by marrying 
a woman who has been condemned to death by other 
men for wishing to be beautiful. There is a wide 
choice. </quote><quote id="50" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">Everyone said he was a fool. 
Everyone said she was a clever woman. 
They used the word "ensnare". </quote><quote id="51" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"The fact is there are no stories I can tell my friends 
that will make them feel better. History cannot be 
erased, although we can soothe ourselves by 
speculating about it."</quote><quote id="52" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">NOTES: Jean Cololère, a drummer in the colonial troops at Québec, was imprisoned for duelling in 1751. In the cell next to his was Françoise Laurent, who had been sentenced to hang for stealing. Except for letters of pardon, the only way at the time for someone under sentence of death to escape hanging was, for a man, to become a hangman, or, for a woman, to marry one. Françoise persuaded Cololère to apply for the vacant (and undesirable) post of executioner, and also to marry her.  
—Condensed from the "Dictionary of Canadian Biography", Volume III, 1741-1770</quote><quote id="53" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"There is so much silence between the words,
you say. You say, The sensed absence
of God and the sensed presence
amount to much the same thing,
only in reverse."
You say, I have too much white clothing.
You start to hum.
Several hundred years ago
this could have been mysticism
or heresy. It isn’t now.
Outside there are sirens.
Someone’s been run over.
The century grinds on.</quote><quote id="54" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"Confess: it’s my profession
that alarms you.
This is why few people ask me to dinner,
though Lord knows I don’t go out of my way to be scary."</quote><quote id="55" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">If I roll my eyes and mutter,
if I clutch at my heart and scream in horror
like a third-rate actress chewing up a mad scene,
I do it in private and nobody sees
but the bathroom mirror.</quote><quote id="56" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">In general I might agree with you:
women should not contemplate war,
should not weigh tactics impartially,
or evade the word "enemy",
or view both sides and denounce nothing.
Women should march for peace,
or hand out white feathers to arouse bravery,
spit themselves on bayonets
to protect their babies,
whose skulls will be split anyway,
or, having been raped repeatedly,
hang themselves with their own hair.
These are the functions that inspire general comfort.
That, and the knitting of socks for the troops
and a sort of moral cheerleading.
Also: mourning the dead.
Sons, lovers, and so forth.
All the killed children.</quote><quote id="57" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">Instead of this, I tell
what I hope will pass as truth.
A blunt thing, not lovely.
The truth is seldom welcome,
especially at dinner,
though I am good at what I do.
"My trade is courage and atrocities.
I look at them and do not condemn.
I write things down the way they happened,
as near as can be remembered.
I don’t ask "why", because it is mostly the same.
Wars happen because the ones who start them
think they can win."</quote><quote id="58" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"Despite the propaganda, there are no monsters,
or none that can be finally buried.
Finish one off, and circumstances
and the radio create another.
Believe me: whole armies have prayed fervently
to God all night and meant it,
and been slaughtered anyway."
Brutality wins frequently,
and large outcomes have turned on the invention
of a mechanical device, viz. radar.
True, valour sometimes counts for something,
as at Thermopylae. Sometimes being right —
though ultimate virtue, by agreed tradition,
is decided by the winner.
"Sometimes men throw themselves on grenades
and burst like paper bags of guts
to save their comrades.
I can admire that.
But rats and cholera have won many wars.
Those, and potatoes,
or the absence of them."</quote><quote id="59" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">In the interests of research
I have walked on many battlefields
that once were liquid with pulped
men’s bodies and spangled with exploded
shells and splayed bone.
All of them have been green again
by the time I got there.
Each has inspired a few good quotes in its day.
Sad marble angels brood like hens
over the grassy nests where nothing hatches.</quote><quote id="60" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">I’m just as human as you. &lt;p&gt; But it’s no use asking me for a final statement.
As I say, I deal in tactics.
Also statistics:
for every year of peace there have been four hundred
years of war.</quote><quote id="61" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"It's a feature of our age that if you write a work of fiction, everyone assumes that the people and events in it are disguised biography — but if you write your biography, it's equally assumed you're lying your head off." This last may be true, at any rate of poets: Plato said that poets should be excluded from the ideal republic because they are such liars. I am a poet, and I affirm that this is true. About no subject are poets tempted to lie so much as about their own lives; I know one of them who has floated at least five versions of his autobiography, none of them true. I of course — being also a novelist — am a much more truthful person than that. But since poets lie, how can you believe me?</quote><quote id="62" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"I became a poet at the age of sixteen. I did not intend to do it. It was not my fault."</quote><quote id="63" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">The day I became a poet was a sunny day of no particular ominousness. I was walking across the football field, not because I was sports-minded or had plans to smoke a cigarette behind the field house — the only other reason for going there — but because this was my normal way home from school. "I was scuttling along in my usual furtive way, suspecting no ill, when a large invisible thumb descended from the sky and pressed down on the top of my head. A poem formed." It was quite a gloomy poem: the poems of the young usually are. It was a gift, this poem — a gift from an anonymous donor, and, as such, both exciting and sinister at the same time. I suspect this is the way all poets begin writing poetry, only they don't want to admit it, so they make up more rational explanations. But this is the true explanation, and I defy anyone to disprove it.</quote><quote id="64" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">I did not know that the rules about these things were different if you were female. I did not know that "poetess" was an insult, and that I myself would some day be called one. I did not know that to be told I had transcended my gender would be considered a compliment. I didn't know — yet — that black was compulsory. All of that was in the future. "When I was sixteen, it was simple. Poetry existed; therefore it could be written; and nobody had told me — yet — the many, many reasons why it could not be written by me."</quote><quote id="65" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">As for my birth month, a detail of much interest to poets, obsessed as they are with symbolic systems of all kinds: I was not pleased, during my childhood, to have been born in November, as there wasn't much inspiration for birthday party motifs. February children got hearts, May ones flowers, but what was there for me? A cake surrounded by withered leaves? November was a drab, dark and wet month, lacking even snow; its only noteworthy festival was Remembrance Day. But in adult life I discovered that November was, astrologically speaking, the month of sex, death and regeneration, and that November First was the Day of the Dead. It still wouldn't have been much good for birthday parties, but it was just fine for poetry, which tends to revolve a good deal around sex and death, with regeneration optional.</quote><quote id="66" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">My English teacher from 1955, run to ground by some documentary crew trying to explain my life, said that in her class I had showed no particular promise. This was true. Until the descent of the giant thumb, I showed no particular promise. I also showed no particular promise for some time afterwards, but I did not know this. "A lot of being a poet consists of willed ignorance. If you woke up from your trance and realized the nature of the life-threatening and dignity-destroying precipice you were walking along, you would switch into actuarial sciences immediately." If I had not been ignorant in this particular way, I would not have announced to an assortment of my high school female friends, in the cafeteria one brown-bag lunchtime, that I was going to be a writer. "I said "writer," not "poet;" I did have some common sense." But my announcement was certainly a conversation-stopper. Sticks of celery were suspended in mid-crunch, peanut-butter sandwiches paused halfway between table and mouth; nobody said a word. One of those present reminded me of this incident recently — I had repressed it — and said she had been simply astounded. "Why?," I said. "Because I wanted to be a writer?" "No," she said. "Because you had the guts to say it out loud."</quote><quote id="67" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">The one good thing to be said about announcing yourself as a writer in the colonial Canadian fifties is that nobody told me I couldn't do it because I was a girl. They simply found the entire proposition ridiculous. Writers were dead and English, or else extremely elderly and American; they were not sixteen years old and Canadian. It would have been worse if I'd been a boy, though. Never mind the fact that all the really stirring poems I'd read at that time had been about slaughter, mayhem, sex and death — poetry was thought of as existing in the pastel female realm, along with embroidery and flower arranging. If I'd been male I would probably have had to roll around in the mud, in some boring skirmish over whether or not I was a sissy.</quote><quote id="68" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">I will pass over my flirtation with journalism as a way of making a living, an idea I dropped when I discovered that in the fifties — unlike now — female journalists always ended up writing the obituaries and the ladies' page. But how was I to make a living? There was not a roaring market in poetry, there, then. I thought of running away and being a waitress, which I later tried, but got very tired and thin; there's nothing like clearing away other people's mushed-up dinners to make you lose your appetite</quote><quote id="69" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"After a year or two of keeping my head down and trying to pass myself off as a normal person, I made contact with the five other people at my university who were interested in writing"; and through them, and some of my teachers, I discovered that there was a whole subterranean Wonderland of Canadian writing that was going on just out of general earshot and sight</quote><quote id="70" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">Like all twenty-one-year-old poets, I thought I would be dead by thirty, and Sylvia Plath had not set a helpful example. For a while there, you were made to feel that, if a poet and female, you could not really be serious about it unless you'd made a least one suicide attempt. So I felt I was running out of time.</quote><quote id="71" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">A lot of poets published their own work then; unlike novels, poetry was short, and therefore cheap to do. We had to print each poem separately, and then disassemble it, as there were not enough a's for the whole book; the cover was done with a lino-block. We printed 250 copies, and sold them through bookstores, for 50 cents each. They now go in the rare book trade for eighteen hundred dollars a pop. Wish I'd kept some.</quote><quote id="72" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">"I no longer feel I'll be dead by thirty; now it's sixty. I suppose these deadlines we set for ourselves are really a way of saying we appreciate time, and want to use all of it. I'm still writing, I'm still writing poetry, I still can't explain why, and I'm still running out of time." Wordsworth was sort of right when he said, "Poets in their youth begin in gladness/ But thereof comes in the end despondency and madness." Except that sometimes poets skip the gladness and go straight to the despondency. Why is that? Part of it is the conditions under which poets work — giving all, receiving little in return from an age that by and large ignores them — and part of it is cultural expectation — "The lunatic, the lover and the poet," says Shakespeare, and notice which comes first. My own theory is that poetry is composed with the melancholy side of the brain, and that if you do nothing but, you may find yourself going slowly down a long dark tunnel with no exit. I have avoided this by being ambidextrous: I write novels too. But when I find myself writing poetry again, it always has the surprise of that first unexpected and anonymous gift.</quote><quote id="73" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">It must be said at the outset that the field of mental illness has always been debatable ground. Who is sane, who isn't, and who is qualified to judge? Standards have fluctuated wildly, and abuses have been numerous. In the last century, in the United States, a wife could be committed to an asylum on the say-so of her husband and two easily-paid-off doctors alone, and there are cases on record of wives who were "put away" for holding theological opinions that differed from those of the husband, or for refusing to have as much sex as he would like.</quote><quote id="74" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">That old standby of melodrama, the rich uncle shoved into the bin so the greedy relatives could get their hands on his estate, had a sound basis in fact. The Victorians cleaned up the straw and the chains of the old Bedlam-like institutions of the eighteenth century, but they didn't always clean up the practices. Patients were drugged, starved, drained of vast quantities of blood, beaten up, swung from ropes, immersed in cold water and whirled around in the air upside-down, all in the belief that it would improve their mental states. Ask yourself whether this is likely to have been true.</quote><quote id="75" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">For every age there is a popular idea about what madness is, what causes it, and how a mad person should look and behave; and it's usually these popular ideas, rather than those of medical professionals, that turn up in songs and stories and plays and books. </quote><quote id="76" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">For a thousand years, the Bible was almost the only book people read, if they could read at all. The stories that were officially told and portrayed were Biblical and religious stories. That other fount of Western civilization as we know it today — the Greek classics — went largely unknown until the Renaissance. For our purposes, there's a noteworthy difference between these two literatures: in the Bible people are hardly ever said to be mad as such, whereas in Greek drama they go off their rockers with alarming frequency. It was the rediscovery of the classics that stimulated the long procession of literary madpeople of the past four hundred years.</quote><quote id="77" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">However, there are all sorts of behaviours in the Bible that might be called mad now, but aren't designated as insanity by the text itself. People see visions — of angels going up and down ladders, of fiery chariots — and, like Moses, who hears a bush talking, and Balaam the prophet who has a conversation with his donkey, they hear voices of those who cannot be said to be present in any usual sense of the word. They also speak in tongues, as the disciples do at Pentecost. Like madness, the visions, the voices and the speaking in tongues are due to external and usually divine agencies. In a world so permeated with supernatural powers, there are no accidents, and in one so riddled with prophets — who went into a frenzy while prophesying — many more kinds of behaviour were accepted as normal, at least for a prophet or an inspired person, than would be the case now. John the Baptist, dressed in animal skins and wandering around in the wilderness denouncing his social superiors, was not thought of as a de-institutionalized street person who's gone off his medications, but as a saint. And this was the pattern for mediaeval views of aberrant behaviour — if you were acting crazy it was a divine punishment, or else you were possessed, by powers either divine or demonic — perhaps aided, in the latter case, by witches.</quote><quote id="78" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">What Elizabethan playwrights learned from the Greek classics was not theories of insanity, but dramatic practice — that is, madness is a dandy theatrical element. It focuses the audience's attention and increases suspense, since you never know what a mad person may get up to next; and Shakespeare himself makes use of it in many forms. In King Lear, there's a scene in which one man pretending to be mad, another who has really gone mad, and a third who has probably always been a little addled, are brought together for purposes of comparison, irony, pathos, and tour de force acting. In Hamlet, there are two variations — Hamlet himself, who assumes madness, and Ophelia, who really does go winsomely bonkers. In MacBeth, it's Lady MacBeth who snaps.</quote><quote id="79" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">When women let their hair down, it means either sexiness or craziness or death, the three by Victorian times having become virtually synonymous.</quote><quote id="80" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">We tend to think of Freud as a great innovator, but the truth is that he himself rested, like a ship on an iceberg, on a huge body of theory and knowledge which had accumulated before his time. Even the famous Unconscious had made its appearance at least seven decades earlier. As for such supposedly modern phenomena as multiple personalities, the vogue for them began in the first half of the nineteenth century; and the first case in which the perpetrator of a murder pleaded amnesia, and got off, was in the eighteen eighties.</quote><quote id="81" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">As I was writing about Grace Marks, and about her interlude in the Asylum, I came to see her in context — the context of other people's opinions, both the popular images of madness and the scientific explanations for it available at the time. A lot of what was believed and said on the subject appears like sheer lunacy to us now. But we shouldn't be too arrogant — how many of our own theories will look silly when those who follow us have come up with something better? But whatever the scientists may come up with, writers and artists will continue to portray altered mental states, simply because few aspects of our nature fascinate people so much. The so-called mad person will always represent a possible future for every member of the audience — who knows when such a malady may strike? When "mad," at least in literature, you aren't yourself; you take on another self, a self that is either not you at all, or a truer, more elemental one than the person you're used to seeing in the mirror. You're in danger of becoming, in Shakespeare's works, a mere picture or beast, and in Susanna Moodie's words, a mere machine; or else you may become an inspired prophet, a truth-sayer, a shaman, one who oversteps the boundaries of the ordinarily visible and audible, and also, and especially, the ordinarily sayable. Portraying this process is deep power for the artist, partly because it's a little too close to the process of artistic creation itself, and partly because the prospect of losing our self and being taken over by another, unfamiliar self is one of our deepest human fears.</quote><quote id="82" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">I can tell you that once upon a time when I was doing public events people would ask me, "What do you think about the arts?, What do you think of the role of women?, What do you think of men?, What do you think of all of these things?", and now they ask one thing, and that one thing is this, "Is there hope?".</quote><quote id="83" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">My first problem was that there were already two Margaret Atwoods on Twitter, one of them with my picture. This grew; I gave commands; then all other Margaret Atwoods stopped together.</quote><quote id="84" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">And [Twitter users] really shone when, during the Olympics, I said that "Own the podium" was too brash to be Canadian, and suggested "A podium might be nice." Their own variations poured onto a feed tagged #cpodium: "A podium! For me?" "Rent the podium, see if we like it." "Mind if I squeeze by you to get onto that podium?" I was so proud of them! It was like having 33,000 precocious grandchildren!</quote><quote id="85" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">[http://www.owtoad.com/ Margaret Atwood's home page]</quote><quote id="86" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">[http://www.vformation.tv/Site/Margaret_Atwood.html Official website for the documentary about Margaret Atwood, Turning Pages]</quote><quote id="87" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">[http://books.guardian.co.uk/departments/generalfiction/story/0,6000,943485,00.html Profile] from "The Guardian"</quote><quote id="88" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">[http://www.cariboo.bc.ca/atwood/ The Margaret Atwood Society home page]</quote><quote id="89" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">[http://www.salon.com/jan97/interview970120.html January 1997 Interview] with Salon.com</quote><quote id="90" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">[http://www.unotchit.com/ Unotchit Inc. official website]</quote><quote id="91" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">[http://www.pittnews.com/vnews/display.v/ART/2005/01/26/41f7283f5343a Atwood invents, signs, backs up with facts]</quote><quote id="92" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">[http://www.neilgaiman.com/journal/2005/01/why-automatic-kissing-machines-are-bad.asp Commentary on Unotchit] from Neil Gaiman</quote><quote id="93" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">[http://nealpollack.com/archives/2005/01/index.html#a000211 Commentary on Unotchit] from Neal Pollack</quote><quote id="94" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">[http://wiredforbooks.org/margaretatwood/ 1986 Audio Interview with Margaret Atwood - RealAudio (30 min 14 s)]</quote><quote id="95" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">[http://books.guardian.co.uk/authors/author/0,5917,-11,00.html Guardian Books "Author Page"], with profile and links to further articles.</quote><quote id="96" author="Margaret Atwood" cats="Activists|Booker Prize winners|Canadian poets|Critics|Feminists|Living people|Novelists|Short story writers" ref="">[http://www.ilnarratore.com/show.php?type=author&amp;language=en&amp;aid=32&amp;tpl=/eng/autore.tpl.html ""Game after Supper"" - ""Take my Hand""] - on audio MP3 (in Canadian English)</quote></quotes>