<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="eo|en|zh|it|cs|ar|eu|et|az|id|es|ru|nl|pt|no|tr|lt|te|pl|ta|bg|hr|de|hu|bs|hy|he|ka|sr|sq|ko|sk|uk"><quote id="0" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Often I wonder what does really God get from me in this state — no faith, no love — not even in feelings. The other day I can't tell you how bad I felt. — There was a moment when I nearly refused to accept. — Deliberately I took the Rosary and very slowly and without even meditating or thinking – I said it slowly and calmly. The moment passed- but the darkness is so dark, and the pain is so painful. – "But I accept whatever He gives and I give whatever He takes". People say they are drawn closer to God- seeing my strong faith. – is this not deceiving people? Every time I have wanted to tell the truth – “that I have no faith” – the words just do not come – my mouth remains closed. – And yet I still keep on smiling at God and all. </quote><quote id="1" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"The hunger for love is much more difficult to remove than the hunger for bread."</quote><quote id="2" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Love is a fruit in season at all times, and within reach of every hand. Anyone may gather it and no limit is set. Everyone can reach this love through meditation, spirit of prayer, and sacrifice, by an intense inner life."</quote><quote id="3" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Holiness is not the luxury of the few; it is a simply duty", for you and for me, because Jesus has very clearly stated, "Be ye holy as my father in heaven is holy." So let us pray for each other that we grow in love for each other, and through this love become holy as Jesus wants us to be for he died out of love for us.
One day I met a lady who was dying of cancer in a most terrible condition. And I told her, I say, "You know, this terrible pain is only the kiss of Jesus — a sign that you have come so close to Jesus on the cross that he can kiss you." And she joined her hands together and said, "Mother Teresa, please tell Jesus to stop kissing me".</quote><quote id="4" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">But I feel that the greatest destroyer of peace today is abortion, because it is a war against the child, a direct killing of the innocent child, murder by the mother herself. And if we accept that a mother can kill even her own child, how can we tell other people not to kill one another? ... By abortion, the mother does not learn to love, but kills even her own child to solve her problems. And, by abortion, that father is told that he does not have to take any responsibility at all for the child he has brought into the world. The father is likely to put other women into the same trouble. So abortion just leads to more abortion. Any country that accepts abortion is not teaching its people to love, but to use any violence to get what they want. This is why the greatest destroyer of love and peace is abortion. </quote><quote id="5" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The biggest disease today is not leprosy or tuberculosis, but rather the feeling of being unwanted.</quote><quote id="6" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"If we have no peace, it is because we have forgotten that we belong to each other."</quote><quote id="7" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">We are misunderstood, we are misrepresented, we are misreported. We are not nurses, we are not doctors, we are not teachers, we are not social workers. We are religious, we are religious, we are religious.</quote><quote id="8" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">From now on you must pray for your people and yourself three times a day.</quote><quote id="9" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I don't know what to say since I don't know what is happening [in Albania]. I can say only one thing. My Albanian people are always in my heart. I pray very much to our Lord that His peace may come to our hearts, in our families and in all the world. I pray for Albania, that the Lord may help its leaders to see clearly because if they want to live in peace, they should love one another.</quote><quote id="10" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I've never seen the poor people being so familiar with their head of state as they were with her. It was a beautiful lesson for me.</quote><quote id="11" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I think it is very beautiful for the poor to accept their lot, to share it with the passion of Christ. I think the world is being much helped by the suffering of the poor people.</quote><quote id="12" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I do not know anything about Charles Keating's work or his business or the matters you are dealing with. I only know he has been kind and generous to God's poor, and always ready to help whenever there was a need... Whenever someone asks me to speak to a judge, I always tell them to pray, to look into [their] heart, and to do what Jesus would do in that circumstance. And this is what I am asking of you, your Honor.</quote><quote id="13" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Spread love everywhere you go"; first of all in your house. Give love to your children, to your wife or husband, to a next door neighbor. Let no one ever come to you without leaving better and happier. "Be the living expression of God's kindness; kindness in your face, kindness in your eyes, kindness in your smile."</quote><quote id="14" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"If I ever become a Saint — I surely be one of "darkness". I will continually be absent from Heaven — to light the light of those in darkness on earth."</quote><quote id="15" author="Mother Teresa" cats="1990s deaths|Albanians|Christian leaders|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Don't look for big things, just do small things with great love....The smaller the thing, the greater must be our love."</quote></quotes>