<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="ru|fr|bg|pt|is|de|ko|it|hu|sk|lt|en|pl|uk|sl|cs|az|ja|es|he"><quote id="0" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">"I believe in God, Mozart, and Beethoven."</quote><quote id="1" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">It is necessary for us to explain the "involuntary repugnance" we possess for the nature and personality of the Jews … The Jews have never produced a true poet. Heinrich Heine reached the point where he duped himself into a poet, and was rewarded by his versified lies being set to music by our own composers. He was the conscience of Judaism, just as Judaism is the evil conscience of our modern civilization.</quote><quote id="2" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">The error in the art-genre of Opera consists herein: a Means of expression (Music) has been made the end, while the End of expression (the Drama) has been made a means.</quote><quote id="3" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">"The oldest, truest, most beautiful organ of music, the origin to which alone our music owes its being, is the human voice."</quote><quote id="4" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">A political man is disgusting, but a political wife, horrible. </quote><quote id="5" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">From its first faint glimmerings, History shews Man's constant progress as a beast of prey. As such he conquers every land, subdues the fruit-fed races, founds mighty realms by subjugating other subjugators, forms states and sets up civilisations, to enjoy his prey at rest.</quote><quote id="6" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">Attack and defence, want and war, victory and defeat, lordship and thraldom, all sealed with the seal of blood: this from henceforth is the History of Man.</quote><quote id="7" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">I had translated the first twelve books of the "Odyssey". For a while I learnt English also, merely so as to gain an accurate knowledge of Shakespeare; and I made a metrical translation of Romeo's monologue. Though I soon left English on one side, yet Shakespeare remained my exemplar, and I projected a great tragedy which was almost nothing but a medley of "Hamlet" and "King Lear". The plan was gigantic in the extreme; two- and-forty human beings died in the course of this piece, and I saw myself compelled, in its working-out, to call the greater number back as ghosts, since otherwise I should have been short of characters for my last Acts. This play occupied my leisure for two whole years.</quote><quote id="8" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">"The July Revolution took place; with one bound I became a revolutionist, and acquired the conviction that every decently active being ought to occupy himself with politics exclusively." I was only happy in the company of political writers, and I commenced an Overture upon a political theme. Thus was I minded, when I left school and went to the university: not, indeed, to devote myself to studying for any profession — for my musical career was now resolved on — but to attend lectures on philosophy and aesthetics. By this opportunity of improving my mind I profited as good as nothing, but gave myself up to all the excesses of student life; and that with such reckless levity, that they very soon revolted me.</quote><quote id="9" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">Germany appeared in my eyes a very tiny portion of the earth. I had emerged from abstract Mysticism, and I learnt a love for Matter. Beauty of material and brilliancy of wit were lordly things to me: as regards my beloved music, I found them both among the Frenchmen and Italians. I forswore my model, Beethoven; "his last Symphony I deemed the keystone of a whole great epoch of art, beyond whose limits no man could hope to press, and within which no man could attain to independence."</quote><quote id="10" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">The utter childishness of our provincial public's verdict upon any art-manifestation that may chance to make its first appearance in their own theatre — for they are only accustomed to witness performances of works already judged and accredited by the greater world outside — brought me to the decision, at no price to produce for the first time a largish work at a minor theatre. When, therefore, I felt again the instinctive need of undertaking a major work, I renounced all idea of obtaining a speedy representation of it in my immediate neighbourhood: "I fixed my mind upon some theatre of first rank, that would some day produce it, and troubled myself but little as to where and when that theatre would be found."</quote><quote id="11" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">""Property" has acquired an almost greater sacredness in our social conscience than religion: for offence against the latter there is lenience, for damage to the former no forgiveness." Since Property is deemed the base of all stability, the more's the pity that not all are owners, that in fact the greater proportion of Society comes disinherited into the world. Society is manifestly thus reduced by its own principle to such a perilous inquietude, that it is compelled to reckon all its laws for an impossible adjustment of this conflict; and protection of property — for which in its widest international sense the weaponed host is specially maintained — can truly mean no else than a defence of the possessors against the non-possessors. Many as are the earnest and sagacious brains that have applied themselves to this problem, its solution, such as that at last suggested of an equal division of all possessions, has not as yet been found amenable; and it seems as if the State's disposal of the apparently so simple idea of Property had driven a beam into the body of mankind that dooms it to a lingering death of agony.</quote><quote id="12" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">Clever though be the many thoughts expressed by mouth or pen about the invention of "money" and its enormous value as a civiliser, against such praises should be set the curse to which it has always been doomed in song and legend. "If "gold" here figures as the demon strangling manhood's innocence, our greatest poet shews at last the goblin's game of "paper money". The Nibelung's fateful ring become a pocket-book, might well complete the eerie picture of the spectral world-controller." By the advocates of our Progressive Civilisation this rulership is indeed regarded as a spiritual, nay, a moral power; for vanished Faith is now replaced by "Credit," that fiction of our mutual honesty kept upright by the most elaborate safeguards against loss and trickery. What comes to pass beneath the benedictions of this Credit we now are witnessing, and seem inclined to lay all blame upon the Jews. They certainly are virtuosi in an art which we but bungle: only, the coinage of money out of nil was invented by our Civilisation itself; or if the Jews are blamable for that, it is because our entire civilisation is a barbaro-judaic medley, in nowise a Christian creation.</quote><quote id="13" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">This possibility, of always drawing from the pristine fount of our own nature, that makes us feel ourselves no more a race, no mere variety of man, but one of Manhood's primal branches, — 'tis this that ever has bestowed on us great men and spiritual heroes, as to whom we have no need to trouble whether fashioners of foreign fatherless civilisations are able to understand and prize them; whilst we again, inspired by the deeds and gifts of our forefathers, and gazing with unclouded eye, are able to rightly estimate those foreigners, and value them according to the spirit of pure Humanity indwelling in their work.</quote><quote id="14" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">What "Conservatives," "Liberals" and "Conservative-liberals," and finally "Democrats," "Socialists," or even "Social-democrats" etc., have lately uttered on the Jewish Question, must seem to us a trifle foolish; for none of these parties would think of testing that "Know thyself" upon themselves, not even the most indefinite and therefore the only one that styles itself in German, the "Progress"-party. "There we see nothing but a clash of interests, whose object is common to all the disputants, common and ignoble: plainly the side most strongly organised, i.e. the most unscrupulous, will bear away the prize." With all our comprehensive State- and National-Economy, it would seem that we are victims to a dream now flattering, now terrifying, and finally asphyxiating: all are panting to awake therefrom; but it is the dream's peculiarity that, so long as it enmeshes us, we take it for real life, and fight against our wakening as though we fought with death. "At last one crowning horror gives the tortured wretch the needful strength: he wakes, and what he held most real was but a figment of the dæmon of distraught mankind." 
We who belong to none of all those parties, but seek our welfare solely in man's wakening to his simple hallowed dignity; we who are excluded from these parties as useless persons, and yet are sympathetically troubled for them, — we can only stand and watch the spasms of the dreamer, since no cry of ours can pierce to him. "So let us save and tend and brace our best of forces, to bear a noble cordial to the sleeper when he wakes, as of himself he must at last."</quote><quote id="15" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">"This is Alberich's dream come true — Nibelheim, world dominion, activity, work, everywhere the oppressive feeling of steam and fog."</quote><quote id="16" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">"I am writing "Parsifal" only for my wife — if I had to depend on the German spirit, I should have nothing more to say."</quote><quote id="17" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">"Certain things in Mozart will and can never be excelled."</quote><quote id="18" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">Oh, I hate the thought of all those costumes and grease paint! When I think that characters like Kundry will now have to be dressed up, those dreadful artists' balls immediately spring into my mind. Having created the invisible orchestra, I now feel like inventing the invisible theatre!</quote><quote id="19" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">It should not be presumed that these people (the Jews), who are so separated from us by their religion, have any right to make our laws. But why blame the Jews? It is we who lack all feeling for our own identity, all sense of honour.</quote><quote id="20" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">"Music has taken a bad turn; these young people have no idea how to write a melody, they just give us shavings", which they dress up to look like a lion's mane and shake at us... "It's as if they avoid melodies, for fear of having perhaps stolen them from someone else."</quote><quote id="21" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">I can't listen to that much Wagner, ya know? I start to get the urge to conquer Poland.</quote><quote id="22" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">Heartless sterility, obliteration of all melody, all tonal charm, all music. This revelling in the destruction of all tonal essence, raging satanic fury in the orchestra, this demoniacal, lewd caterwauling, scandal-mongering, gun-toting music, with an orchestral accompaniment slapping you in the face. Hence, the secret fascination that makes it the darling of feeble-minded royalty, of the court monkeys covered with reptilian slime, and of the blasé hysterical female court parasites who need this galvanic stimulation by massive instrumental treatment to throw their pleasure-weary frog-legs into violent convulsion. The diabolical din of this pig-headed man, stuffed with brass and sawdust, inflated, in an insanely destructive self-aggrandizement, by Mephistopheles' mephitic and most venomous hellish miasma, into Beelzebub's Court Composer and General Director of Hell's Music - Wagner!</quote><quote id="23" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">Is Wagner a human being at all?  Is he not rather a disease?  He contaminates everything he touches - he has made music sick.</quote><quote id="24" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">"Monsieur Wagner a de beaux moments, mais de mauvais quart d'heures."</quote><quote id="25" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">After the last notes of "Gotterdammerung" I felt as though I had been let out of prison.</quote><quote id="26" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">I like Wagner’s music better than any other music. It is so loud that one can talk the whole time, without people hearing what one says.</quote><quote id="27" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://users.belgacom.net/wagnerlibrary/ The Wagner Library]</quote><quote id="28" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">{{gutenberg author| id=Richard+Wagner | name=Richard Wagner}}</quote><quote id="29" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">{{worldcat id|id=lccn-n79-89831}}</quote><quote id="30" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://www.wagneropera.net Richard Wagner Opera]</quote><quote id="31" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://www.wagneroperas.com Wagner Operas]</quote><quote id="32" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://www.rwagner.net/ RWagner.net]</quote><quote id="33" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://www.trell.org/wagner/ Wagner website]</quote><quote id="34" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://www.gutenberg.org/etext/27265 "The Wagnerian Romances" by Gertrude Hall]</quote><quote id="35" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://www.richard-wagner-postkarten.de/ The Richard Wagner Postcard-Gallery]</quote><quote id="36" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://gallica.bnf.fr/ gallica.bnf.fr] Pictures of [http://gallica.bnf.fr/scripts/ConsultationTout.exe?O=07722511 Richard Wagner] and his [http://gallica.bnf.fr/scripts/ConsultationTout.exe?O=07722510 family].</quote><quote id="37" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p00548gv Discussion of Wagner on Radio 4 programme "In our time" (BBC audio file)]</quote><quote id="38" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://www.bayreuther-festspiele.de/ Bayreuth Festival]</quote><quote id="39" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://www.wahnfried.de/_engl/archiv/index.html The National Archive of the Richard Wagner Foundation]</quote><quote id="40" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://www.faqs.org/faqs/music/wagner/general-faq/preamble.html The humanities.music.composers.wagner FAQ].</quote><quote id="41" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://www.richard-wagner-museum.ch/en/index/index.php Richard Wagner Museum]</quote><quote id="42" author="Richard Wagner" cats="1880s deaths|Composers|Germans" ref="">[http://www.wagner-tuba.com The Wagner Tuba]</quote></quotes>