<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="en"><quote id="0" author="Ricky Gervais" cats="Actors|Authors|Comedians|Directors|English people|Living people|Musicians|Producers|Radio personalities" ref="">The truth doesn’t hurt. Whatever it is, it doesn’t hurt. It’s better to know the truth.</quote><quote id="1" author="Ricky Gervais" cats="Actors|Authors|Comedians|Directors|English people|Living people|Musicians|Producers|Radio personalities" ref="">You have options. You can either continue to be miserable or you can just stop being angry at everyone and accept the way things are. Allow yourself to live.</quote><quote id="2" author="Ricky Gervais" cats="Actors|Authors|Comedians|Directors|English people|Living people|Musicians|Producers|Radio personalities" ref="">If there is a god, why did he make me an atheist? That was his first mistake. Well, the talking snake was his first mistake.</quote><quote id="3" author="Ricky Gervais" cats="Actors|Authors|Comedians|Directors|English people|Living people|Musicians|Producers|Radio personalities" ref="">Why don’t you believe in God? I get that question all the time. I always try to give a sensitive, reasoned answer. This is usually awkward, time consuming and pointless. People who believe in God don’t need proof of his existence, and they certainly don’t want evidence to the contrary. They are happy with their belief. They even say things like “it’s true to me” and “it’s faith.” I still give my logical answer because I feel that not being honest would be patronizing and impolite. It is ironic therefore that “I don’t believe in God because there is absolutely no scientific evidence for his existence and from what I’ve heard the very definition is a logical impossibility in this known universe,” comes across as both patronizing and impolite.</quote><quote id="4" author="Ricky Gervais" cats="Actors|Authors|Comedians|Directors|English people|Living people|Musicians|Producers|Radio personalities" ref="">Science seeks the truth. And it does not discriminate. For better or worse it finds things out. Science is humble. It knows what it knows and it knows what it doesn’t know. It bases its conclusions and beliefs on hard evidence -­- evidence that is constantly updated and upgraded. It doesn’t get offended when new facts come along. It embraces the body of knowledge. It doesn’t hold on to medieval practices because they are tradition. If it did, you wouldn’t get a shot of penicillin, you’d pop a leach down your trousers and pray.</quote></quotes>