<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="bg|pt|tr|sk|en|bs|cs"><quote id="0" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">We did long for the pitter-patter of little feet, so we decided to buy a dog. Cheaper, and… get more feet.</quote><quote id="1" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">I love being married, I do. It's so great to find that one special person that you want to annoy for the rest of your life.</quote><quote id="2" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Well, the old theory was "marry an older man because they're more mature". But the new theory is "men don't mature — marry a young one".</quote><quote id="3" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">To me, life is tough enough without having someone kick you from the inside.</quote><quote id="4" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"[One of my friends]" was in labor for 36 hours. (I don't even want to do anything that feels good for 36 hours.)</quote><quote id="5" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Envy the kangaroo. That pouch setup is extraordinary; the baby crawls out of the womb when it is about two inches long, gets into the pouch, and proceeds to mature. I'd have a baby if it would develop in my handbag.</quote><quote id="6" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">I don't even know how this word came into being: "aerobics". I guess gym instructors got together and said, "If we're going to charge ten dollars an hour, we can't call it 'jumping up and down'."</quote><quote id="7" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Nobody is really happy with what's on their head. People with straight hair want curly, people with curly want straight, and bald people want everyone to be blind.</quote><quote id="8" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Why are women wearing perfumes that smell like flowers to attract men? Men don't like flowers. I have a great idea for a scent that will attract men — how about "New Car Interior"?</quote><quote id="9" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">I had teeth that stuck out so far, I used to eat other kids' candy bars by accident.</quote><quote id="10" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">According to a new survey, women say they feel more comfortable undressing in front of men than they do undressing in front of other women. They say that women are too judgmental, where, of course, men are just grateful.</quote><quote id="11" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Before I met my husband, I'd never fallen in love...I'd stepped in it a few times. [HBO: "Born to be Mild"]</quote><quote id="12" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">I got kicked out of ballet class because I pulled a groin muscle. It wasn't mine.</quote><quote id="13" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">I think men who have a pierced ear are better prepared for marriage. They've experienced pain and bought jewelry.</quote><quote id="14" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">I was a vegetarian until I started leaning toward the sunlight.</quote><quote id="15" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">I was going to have cosmetic surgery until I noticed that the doctor's office was full of portraits by Picasso.</quote><quote id="16" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">I wonder if other dogs think poodles are members of a weird religious cult.</quote><quote id="17" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"[about her talk show]" I'm just like Dr. Phil, except I have hair and I don't help anybody.</quote><quote id="18" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">In Hollywood, a marriage is a success if it outlasts milk. [HBO: "Born to be Mild"]</quote><quote id="19" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Men reach their sexual peak at eighteen. Women reach theirs at thirty-five. Do you get the feeling that God is playing a practical joke?</quote><quote id="20" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Money is the root of all jewelry.</quote><quote id="21" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Most turkeys taste better the day after; my mother's tasted better the day before.</quote><quote id="22" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">My boyfriend and I broke up. He wanted to get married and I didn't want him to.</quote><quote id="23" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">My husband gave me a necklace. It's fake. I requested fake. Maybe I'm paranoid, but in this day and age, I don't want something around my neck that's worth more than my head. [HBO: "Born to be Mild"]</quote><quote id="24" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">My mother is such a lousy cook that Thanksgiving at her house is a time of sorrow.</quote><quote id="25" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Never play peekaboo with a child on a long plane trip. There's no end to the game. Finally I grabbed him by the bib and said, "Look, it's always gonna be me!"</quote><quote id="26" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">"[advice to a woman who can't decide between 2 men]" Remember, Casablanca"; Ronald Reagan was. So maybe if Ronnie had taken the part, Humprey Bogart could have been president. And maybe if you date this guy, you could be president too!</quote><quote id="27" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">Someday I want to be rich. Some people get so rich they lose all respect for humanity. That's how rich I want to be.</quote><quote id="28" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">When I eventually met Mr. Right I had no idea that his first name was Always.</quote><quote id="29" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">When I meet a man I ask myself, 'Is this the man I want my children to spend their weekends with?'</quote><quote id="30" author="Rita Rudner" cats="Americans|Authors|Comedians|Living people" ref="">When I was a kid I had two friends, and they were imaginary, and they would only play with each other. [HBO: "Born to be Mild"]</quote></quotes>