<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="el|eo|en|zh|it|cy|cs|et|gl|id|es|ru|az|nl|pt|no|tr|ro|pl|fr|bg|de|hu|fi|he|ka|sv|sk|uk"><quote id="0" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Freedom is never more than one generation away from extinction." We didn’t pass it on to our children in the bloodstream. It must be fought for, protected, and handed on for them to do the same, or one day we will spend our sunset years telling our children and our children's children what it was once like in the United States where men were free.</quote><quote id="1" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Back in 1927, an American socialist, Norman Thomas, six times candidate for President on the Socialist Party ticket, said that the American people would never vote for socialism but he said "under the name of liberalism the American people would adopt every fragment of the socialist program."</quote><quote id="2" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Shouldn't someone tag Mr. Kennedy's 'bold new imaginative program' with its proper age?" Reagan wondered. "Under the &lt;b&gt;tousled boyish haircut&lt;/b&gt; it is still old &lt;b&gt;Karl Marx&lt;/b&gt;—first launched a century ago. There is nothing new in the idea of a government being &lt;b&gt;Big Brother&lt;/b&gt; to us all. &lt;b&gt;Hitler&lt;/b&gt; called his state &lt;b&gt;'State Socialism'&lt;/b&gt;, and way before him it was relevant &lt;b&gt;'benevolant monarchy'&lt;/b&gt;."</quote><quote id="3" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">But at the moment I'd like to talk about another way because this threat is with us and at the moment is more imminent. "One of the traditional methods of imposing statism or socialism on a people has been by way of medicine. It's very easy to disguise a medical program as a humanitarian project." . . . Now, the American people, if you put it to them about socialized medicine and gave them a chance to choose, would unhesitatingly vote against it. We have an example of this. Under the Truman administration it was proposed that we have a compulsory health insurance program for all people in the United States, and, of course, the American people unhesitatingly rejected this.</quote><quote id="4" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">The doctor begins to lose freedom. . . . First you decide that the doctor can have so many patients. They are equally divided among the various doctors by the government. But then doctors aren’t equally divided geographically. So a doctor decides he wants to practice in one town and the government has to say to him, you can't live in that town. They already have enough doctors. You have to go someplace else. And from here it's only a short step to dictating where he will go. . . . All of us can see what happens once you establish the precedent that the government can determine a man's working place and his working methods, determine his employment. From here it's a short step to all the rest of socialism, to determining his pay. And pretty soon your son won't decide, when he's in school, where he will go or what he will do for a living. He will wait for the government to tell him where he will go to work and what he will do.</quote><quote id="5" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Every morning Nancy and I turn to see what he has to say about people of our respective birth signs.</quote><quote id="6" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">It's silly talking about how many years we will have to spend in the jungles of Vietnam when we could pave the whole country and put parking stripes on it and still be home by Christmas.</quote><quote id="7" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">We were told four years ago that 17 million people went to bed hungry every night.  Well, that was probably true.  They were all on a diet.</quote><quote id="8" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">I favor the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and it must be enforced at the point of a bayonet,  if necessary.</quote><quote id="9" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">I would have voted against the Civil Rights Act of 1964.</quote><quote id="10" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">A tree's a tree.  How many more do you need to look at?</quote><quote id="11" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Unemployment insurance is a pre-paid vacation for freeloaders.</quote><quote id="12" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Government is like a baby. An alimentary canal with a big appetite at one end and no responsibility at the other."</quote><quote id="13" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">I have a feeling that we are doing better in the war [in Vietnam] than the people have been told.</quote><quote id="14" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">We must reject the idea that every time a law's broken, society is guilty rather than the lawbreaker. It is time to restore the American precept that each individual is accountable for his actions.</quote><quote id="15" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Welfare's purpose should be to eliminate, as far as possible, the need for its own existence."</quote><quote id="16" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">If it's to be a bloodbath, let it be now. Appeasement is not the answer.</quote><quote id="17" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"One legislator accused me of having a nineteenth-century attitude on law and order. That is a totally false charge. I have an eighteenth-century attitude. That is when the Founding Fathers made it clear that the safety of law-abiding citizens should be one of the government's primary concerns."</quote><quote id="18" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">If you analyze it I believe "the very heart and soul of conservatism is libertarianism". I think conservatism is really a misnomer just as liberalism is a misnomer for the liberals — if we were back in the days of the Revolution, so-called conservatives today would be the Liberals and the liberals would be the Tories. The basis of conservatism is a desire for less government interference or less centralized authority or more individual freedom and this is a pretty general description also of what libertarianism is. Now, I can’t say that I will agree with all the things that the present group who call themselves Libertarians in the sense of a party say, because I think that like in any political movement there are shades, and there are libertarians who are almost over at the point of wanting no government at all or anarchy.  I believe there are legitimate government functions. There is a legitimate need in an orderly society for some government to maintain freedom or we will have tyranny by individuals. The strongest man on the block will run the neighborhood. We have government to ensure that we don’t each one of us have to carry a club to defend ourselves. But again, I stand on my statement that I think that libertarianism and conservatism are traveling the same path.</quote><quote id="19" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Right now our main effort is directed toward oxides of nitrogen which comes out of automobile tail pipe and cause the photochemical reactions which color the air a muddy brown. There is no question they are a problem in areas like L.A. where we have a more or less constant temperature inversion trapping the air. But Dr. [John] McKetta lists the findings in his field as his no. 3 shock &amp; surprise. "Nature it seems also produces oxides of nitrogen. As a matter of fact nature produces 97% of them."</quote><quote id="20" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">There are those in America today who have come to depend absolutely on government for their security. And when government fails they seek to rectify that failure in the form of granting government more power. So, as government has failed to control crime and violence with the means given it by the Constitution, they seek to give it more power at the expense of the Constitution. But in doing so, in their willingness to give up their arms in the name of safety, they are really giving up their protection from what has always been the chief source of despotism — government. Lord Acton said power corrupts. Surely then, if this is true, the more power we give the government the more corrupt it will become. And if we give it the power to confiscate our arms we also give up the ultimate means to combat that corrupt power. In doing so we can only assure that we will eventually be totally subject to it. When dictators come to power, the first thing they do is take away the people's weapons. It makes it so much easier for the secret police to operate, it makes it so much easier to force the will of the ruler upon the ruled.</quote><quote id="21" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">w:Fascism|Fascism was really the basis for the New Deal. It was Benito Mussolini|Mussolini's success in Italy, with his government-directed economy, that led the early New Dealers to say "But Mussolini keeps the trains running on time."</quote><quote id="22" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"I'm convinced that today the majority of Americans want what those first Americans wanted: A better life for themselves and their children; a minimum of government authority." Very simply, they want to be left alone in peace and safety to take care of the family by earning an honest dollar and putting away some savings. This may not sound too exciting, but there is something magnificent about it. On the farm, on the street corner, in the factory and in the kitchen, millions of us ask nothing more, but certainly nothing less than to live our own lives according to our values — at peace with ourselves, our neighbors and the world.</quote><quote id="23" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Let it show on the record that when the American people cried out for economic help, Jimmy Carter took refuge behind a dictionary. Well, if it's a definition he wants, I'll give him one. A recession is when your neighbor loses his job. A depression is when you lose yours. And recovery is when Jimmy Carter loses his.</quote><quote id="24" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Politics is supposed to be the second oldest profession. I have come to realize that it bears a very close resemblance to the first."</quote><quote id="25" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"The smoke from burning marijuana contains many more cancer-causing substances than tobacco." And if that isn’t enough it leads to bronchitis and emphysema. "If adults want to take such chances that is their business. But surely the communications media ... should let four million youngsters know what they are risking."</quote><quote id="26" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">They tell us we must learn to live with less, and teach our children that their lives will be less full and prosperous than ours have been; that the America of the coming years will be a place where &amp;mdash; because of our past excesses &amp;mdash; it will be impossible to dream and make those dreams come true. I don't believe that. And, I don't believe you do either. That is why I am seeking the presidency. I cannot and will not stand by and see this great country destroy itself. Our leaders attempt to blame their failures on circumstances beyond their control, on false estimates by unknown, unidentifiable experts who rewrite modern history in an attempt to convince us our high standard of living, the result of thrift and hard work, is somehow selfish extravagance which we must renounce as we join in sharing scarcity. I don't agree that our nation must resign itself to inevitable decline, yielding its proud position to other hands. I am totally unwilling to see this country fail in its obligation to itself and to the other free peoples of the world.</quote><quote id="27" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"A troubled and afflicted mankind looks to us, pleading for us to keep our rendezvous with destiny; that we will uphold the principles of self-reliance, self-discipline, morality, and, above all, responsible liberty for every individual that we will become that shining city on a hill."</quote><quote id="28" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">All the waste in a year from a nuclear power plant can be stored under a desk.</quote><quote id="29" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"I am paying for this microphone!"</quote><quote id="30" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"And I have to point out that government doesn't tax to get the money it needs, government always needs the money it gets." </quote><quote id="31" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Government exists to protect us from each other. Where government has gone beyond its limits is in deciding to protect us from ourselves.</quote><quote id="32" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"[Evolution] has in recent years been challenged in the world of science and is not yet believed in the scientific community to be as infallible as it once was believed. But if it was going to be taught in the schools, then I think that also the biblical theory of creation, which is not a theory but the biblical story of creation, should also be taught." </quote><quote id="33" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Approximately 80 percent of our air pollution stems from hydrocarbons released by vegetation.  So let's not go overboard in setting and enforcing tough emission standards for man-made sources.</quote><quote id="34" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">With regard to the freedom of the individual for choice with regard to abortion, there's one individual who's not being considered at all. That's the one who is being aborted. And I've noticed that everybody that is for abortion has already been born.</quote><quote id="35" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">I have flown twice over Mount St. Helens. I'm not a scientist and I don't know the figures, but I have a suspicion that one little mountain out there, in these last several months, has probably released more sulfur dioxide into the atmosphere than has been released in the last ten years of automobile driving or things of that kind.</quote><quote id="36" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"There you go again." When I opposed Medicare, there was another piece of legislation meeting the same problem before the Congress. I happened to favor the other piece of legislation and thought that it would be better for the senior citizens to provide better care than the one that was finally passed.</quote><quote id="37" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Next Tuesday all of you will go to the polls, will stand there in the polling place and make a decision. I think when you make that decision, it might be well if you would ask yourself, are you better off than you were four years ago?</quote><quote id="38" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"I believe with all my heart that our first priority must be world peace, and that use of force is always and only a last resort, when everything else has failed, and then only with regard to our national security."</quote><quote id="39" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"I have spent most of my life as a Democrat. I recently have seen fit to follow another course. I believe that the issues confronting us cross party lines."</quote><quote id="40" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">As for the peace that we would preserve, I wonder who among us would like to approach the wife or mother whose husband or son has died in South Vietnam and ask them if they think this is a peace that should be maintained indefinitely. Do they mean peace, or do they mean we just want to be left in peace? There can be no real peace while one American is dying some place in the world for the rest of us. "We're at war with the most dangerous enemy that has ever faced mankind in his long climb from the swamp to the stars, and it's been said if we lose that war, and in so doing lose this way of freedom of ours, history will record with the greatest astonishment that those who had the most to lose did the least to prevent its happening." Well I think it's time we ask ourselves if we still know the freedoms that were intended for us by the Founding Fathers. </quote><quote id="41" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"If we lose freedom here, there is no place to escape to. This is the last stand on Earth." And this idea that government is beholden to the people, that it has no other source of power except to sovereign people, is still the newest and most unique idea in all the long history of man's relation to man. This is the issue of this election. Whether we believe in our capacity for self-government or whether we abandon the American revolution and confess that a little intellectual elite in a far-distant capital can plan our lives for us better than we can plan them ourselves.</quote><quote id="42" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">The trouble with our liberal friends is not that they are ignorant, but that they know so much that isn't so. </quote><quote id="43" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"You and I are told increasingly that we have to choose between a left or right, but I would like to suggest that there is no such thing as a left or right. There is only an up or down" &amp;mdash; up to a man's age-old dream; the ultimate in individual freedom consistent with law and order &amp;mdash; or down to the ant heap of totalitarianism, and regardless of their sincerity, their humanitarian motives, those who would trade our freedom for security have embarked on this downward course.</quote><quote id="44" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Those who would trade our freedom for the soup kitchen of the welfare state have told us that they have a utopian solution of peace without victory. They call their policy "accommodation." And they say if we only avoid any direct confrontation with the enemy, he will forget his evil ways and learn to love us. All who oppose them are indicted as warmongers.</quote><quote id="45" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"They say we offer simple answers to complex problems. Well, perhaps there is a simple answer &amp;mdash; not an easy answer &amp;mdash; but simple."</quote><quote id="46" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Alexander Hamilton said, "A nation which can prefer disgrace to danger is prepared for a master, and deserves one." Let's set the record straight. There is no argument over the choice between peace and war, but there is only one guaranteed way you can have peace — and you can have it in the next second — surrender.</quote><quote id="47" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Admittedly there is a risk in any course we follow other than this [surrender], but every lesson in history tells us that the greater risk lies in appeasement, and this is the specter our well-meaning liberal friends refuse to face &amp;mdash; that their policy of accommodation is appeasement, and it gives no choice between peace and war, only between fight and surrender. If we continue to accommodate, continue to back and retreat, eventually we have to face the final demand &amp;mdash; the ultimatum. And what then? When Nikita Khrushchev has told his people he knows what our answer will be? He has told them that we are retreating under the pressure of the Cold War, and someday when the time comes to deliver the ultimatum, our surrender will be voluntary because by that time we will have weakened from within spiritually, morally, and economically. He believes this because from our side he has heard voices pleading for "peace at any price" or "better Red than dead," or as one commentator put it, he would rather "live on his knees than die on his feet." And therein lies the road to war, because those voices don't speak for the rest of us. You and I know and do not believe that life is so dear and peace so sweet as to be purchased at the price of chains and slavery. If nothing in life is worth dying for, when did this begin &amp;mdash; just in the face of this enemy?</quote><quote id="48" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"The martyrs of history were not fools, and our honored dead who gave their lives to stop the advance of the Nazis didn't die in vain." Where, then, is the road to peace? Well, it's a simple answer after all. You and I have the courage to say to our enemies, "There is a price we will not pay." There is a point beyond which they must not advance. This is the meaning in the phrase of Barry Goldwater's "peace through strength." Winston Churchill said that "the destiny of man is not measured by material computation. When great forces are on the move in the world, we learn we are spirits &amp;mdash; not animals." And he said, "There is something going on in time and space, and beyond time and space, which, whether we like it or not, spells duty."</quote><quote id="49" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"You and I have a rendezvous with destiny. We will preserve for our children this, the last best hope of man on Earth, or we will sentence them to take the last step into a thousand years of darkness." We will keep in mind and remember that Barry Goldwater has faith in us. He has faith that you and I have the ability and the dignity and the right to make our own decisions and determine our own destiny.</quote><quote id="50" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Thomas Jefferson made a comment about the Presidency and age. He said that one should not worry about one's exact chronological age in reference to his ability to perform one's task. And ever since he told me that, I stopped worrying. </quote><quote id="51" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Intelligence reports say he &amp;mdash; Castro &amp;mdash; is very worried about me. I'm very worried that we can't come up with something to justify his worrying.</quote><quote id="52" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Government's first duty is to protect the people, not run their lives."</quote><quote id="53" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Honey, I forgot to duck."</quote><quote id="54" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"I hope you're all Republican." </quote><quote id="55" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"This is not the time for political fun and games. This is the time for a new beginning." I ask you now to put aside any feelings of frustration or helplessness about our political institutions and join me in this dramatic but responsible plan to reduce the enormous burden of Federal taxation on you and your family.</quote><quote id="56" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">The size of the Federal budget is not an appropriate barometer of social conscience or charitable concern.</quote><quote id="57" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">I never knew anything above Cs.</quote><quote id="58" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Every country and every people has a stake in the Afghan resistance, for the freedom fighters of Afghanistan are defending principles of independence and freedom that form the basis of global security and stability."</quote><quote id="59" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">From Stettin on the Baltic to Varna on the Black Sea, the regimes planted by totalitarianism have had more than thirty years to establish their legitimacy. But none &amp;mdash; not one regime &amp;mdash; has yet been able to risk free elections. Regimes planted by bayonets do not take root....If history teaches anything, it teaches self-delusion in the face of unpleasant facts is folly....Our military strength is a prerequisite to peace, but let it be clear we maintain this strength in the hope it will never be used, for the ultimate determinant in the struggle that's now going on in the world will not be bombs and rockets but a test of wills and ideas, a trial of spiritual resolve, the values we hold, the beliefs we cherish, the ideals to which we are dedicated.</quote><quote id="60" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">When the chips are down and the decisions are made as to who the candidates will be, then the 11th commandment prevails and everybody goes to work, and that is: Thou shalt not speak ill of another Republican. </quote><quote id="61" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Yes, because for many years I was a Democrat.</quote><quote id="62" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">By outlawing Solidarity, a free trade organization to which an overwhelming majority of Polish workers and farmers belong, they have made it clear that they never had any intention of restoring one of the most elemental human rights—the right to belong to a free trade union.</quote><quote id="63" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Well, I learned a lot. ... You'd be surprised. They're all individual countries.</quote><quote id="64" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Dr. King freed the white man. How did he accomplish this tremendous feat? Where others &amp;mdash; white and black &amp;mdash; preached hatred, he taught the principles of love and nonviolence." We can be so thankful that Dr. King raised his mighty eloquence for love and hope rather than for hostility and bitterness. He took the tension he found in our nation, a tension of injustice, and channeled it for the good of America and all her people.</quote><quote id="65" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Let us be aware that while they [the Soviet leadership] preach the supremacy of the state, declare its omnipotence over individual man, and predict its eventual domination of all peoples on the earth, they are the focus of evil in the modern world.</quote><quote id="66" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">So, in your discussions of the nuclear freeze proposals, I urge you to beware the temptation of pride, the temptation of blithely declaring yourselves above it all and label both sides equally at fault, to ignore the facts of history and the aggressive impulses of an evil empire, to simply call the arms race a giant misunderstanding and thereby remove yourself from the struggle between right and wrong and good and evil.</quote><quote id="67" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">What if free people could live secure in the knowledge that their security did not rest upon the threat of instant U.S. retaliation to deter a Soviet attack, that we could intercept and destroy strategic ballistic missiles before they reached our own soil or that of our allies? I know this is a formidable, technical task, one that may not be accomplished before the end of this century. Yet, current technology has attained a level of sophistication where it's reasonable for us to begin this effort. It will take years, probably decades of effort on many fronts. There will be failures and setbacks, just as there will be successes and breakthroughs. And as we proceed, we must remain constant in preserving the nuclear deterrent and maintaining a solid capability for flexible response. But isn't it worth every investment necessary to free the world from the threat of nuclear war? We know it is. </quote><quote id="68" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"The defense policy of the United States is based on a simple premise: The United States does not start fights. We will never be an aggressor." We maintain our strength in order to deter and defend against aggression &amp;mdash; to preserve freedom and peace.</quote><quote id="69" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Small business is the gateway to opportunity for those who want a piece of the American dream. [...] Well, wouldn't it be nice to hear a little more about the forgotten heroes of America-those who create most of our new jobs, like the owners of stores down the street; the faithfuls who support our churches, synagogues, schools, and communities; the brave men and women everywhere who produce our goods, feed a hungry world, and keep our families warm while they invest in the future to build a better America? That's where miracles are made, not in Washington, D.C.  </quote><quote id="70" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Some people work an entire lifetime and wonder if they ever made a difference to the world. But the Marines don't have that problem.</quote><quote id="71" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">One hundred nations in the UN have not agreed with us on just about everything that's come before them, where we're involved, and it didn't upset my breakfast at all. </quote><quote id="72" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">This country now possesses the strongest credit in the world. The full consequences of a default or even the serious prospect of default by the United States are impossible to predict and awesome to contemplate. Denigration of the full faith and credit of the United States would have substantial effects on the domestic financial markets and on the value of the dollar in exchange markets. The Nation can ill afford to allow such a result. The risks, the cost, the disruptions, and the incalculable damage lead me to but one conclusion: the Senate must pass this legislation before the Congress adjourns.</quote><quote id="73" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"The only way there could be war is if they start it; we're not going to start a war."</quote><quote id="74" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Not to the extent of throwing up my hands and saying, "Well, it's all over." No. I think whichever generation and at whatever time, when the time comes, the generation that is there, I think will have to go on doing what they believe is right.</quote><quote id="75" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Until now has there ever been a time in which so many of the prophecies are coming together? There have been times in the past when people thought the end of the world was coming, and so forth, but never anything like this.</quote><quote id="76" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">I have left orders to be awakened at any time in case of national emergency, even if I'm in a cabinet meeting.</quote><quote id="77" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"History teaches that wars begin when governments believe the price of aggression is cheap."</quote><quote id="78" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">What we have found in this country, and maybe we're more aware of it now, is one problem that we've had, even in the best of times, and that is the people who are sleeping on the grates, the homeless who are homeless, you might say, by choice.</quote><quote id="79" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"I am not worried about the deficit. It is big enough to take care of itself."</quote><quote id="80" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">You'd be surprised how much being a good actor pays off.</quote><quote id="81" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">These are the boys of Pointe du Hoc. These are the men who took the cliffs. These are the champions who helped free a continent. These are the heroes who helped end a war.</quote><quote id="82" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"We will always remember. We will always be proud. We will always be prepared, so we may always be free."</quote><quote id="83" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"My fellow Americans, I'm pleased to tell you today that I've signed legislation that will outlaw Russia forever. We begin bombing in five minutes."</quote><quote id="84" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Recognizing the equality of all men and women, we are willing and able to lift the weak, cradle those who hurt, and nurture the bonds that tie us together as one nation under God."</quote><quote id="85" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"America's future rests in a thousand dreams inside your hearts. It rests in the message of hope in songs of a man so many young Americans admire -- New Jersey's own, Bruce Springsteen."</quote><quote id="86" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"I want you to know that also I will not make age an issue of this campaign. I am not going to exploit, for political purposes, my opponent's youth and inexperience."</quote><quote id="87" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">If you read the letter, you will find there is nothing wrong with it. </quote><quote id="88" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">We in the United States, above all, must remember that lesson [of the Holocaust], for we were founded as a nation of openness to people of all beliefs. And so we must remain. Our very unity has been strengthened by our pluralism. We establish no religion in this country, we command no worship, we mandate no belief, nor will we ever. Church and state are, and must remain, separate. All are free to believe or not believe, all are free to practice a faith or not, and those who believe are free, and should be free, to speak of and act on their belief.</quote><quote id="89" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"To a few of us here today this is a solemn and most momentous occasion, and yet in the history of our nation it is a commonplace occurrence." The orderly transfer of authority as called for in the Constitution routinely takes place, as it has for almost two centuries, and few of us stop to think how unique we really are. "In the eyes of many in the world, this every-four-year ceremony we accept as normal is nothing less than a miracle."</quote><quote id="90" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">If we look to the answer as to why for so many years we achieved so much, prospered as no other people on earth, it was because here in this land we unleashed the energy and individual genius of man to a greater extent than has ever been done before. "Freedom and the dignity of the individual have been more available and assured here than in any other place on earth. The price for this freedom at times has been high, but we have never been unwilling to pay the price."</quote><quote id="91" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"It is time for us to realize that we're too great a nation to limit ourselves to small dreams." We're not, as some would have us believe, doomed to an inevitable decline. "I do not believe in a fate that will fall on us no matter what we do. I do believe in a fate that will fall on us if we do nothing." So, with all the creative energy at our command, let us begin an era of national renewal. Let us renew our determination, our courage, and our strength. And let us renew our faith and our hope. "We have every right to dream heroic dreams. Those who say that we're in a time when there are no heroes, they just don't know where to look."</quote><quote id="92" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Above all, we must realize that no arsenal or no weapon in the arsenals of the world is so formidable as the will and moral courage of free men and women." It is a weapon our adversaries in today's world do not have. It is a weapon that we as Americans do have. Let that be understood by those who practice terrorism and prey upon their neighbors.</quote><quote id="93" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">In this present crisis, "government is not the solution to our problem; government is the problem". From time to time we've been tempted to believe that society has become too complex to be managed by self-rule, that government by an elite group is superior to government for, by, and of the people. Well, if no one among us is capable of governing himself, then who among us has the capacity to govern someone else? All of us together, in and out of government, must bear the burden.</quote><quote id="94" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Directly in front of me, the monument to a monumental man, George Washington, father of our country. A man of humility who came to greatness reluctantly. He led Americans out of revolutionary victory into infant nationhood. Off to one side, the stately memorial to Thomas Jefferson. The Declaration of Independence flames with his eloquence. And then, beyond the Reflecting Pool, the dignified columns of the Lincoln Memorial. Whoever would understand in his heart the meaning of America will find it in the life of Abraham Lincoln. 
Beyond those monuments to heroism is the Potomac River, and on the far shore the sloping hills of Arlington National Cemetery, with its row upon row of simple white markers bearing crosses of Stars of David. They add up to only a tiny fraction of the price that has been paid for our freedom. Each one of those markers is a monument to the kind of hero I spoke of earlier. Their lives ended in places called Belleau Wood, the Argonne, Omaha Beach, Salerno, and halfway around the world on Guadalcanal, Tarawa, Pork Chop Hill, the Chosin Reservoir, and in a hundred rice paddies and jungles of a place called Vietnam. 
Under one such marker lies a young man, Martin Treptow, who left his job in a small town barber shop in 1917 to go to France with the famed Rainbow Division. There, on the western front, he was killed trying to carry a message between battalions under heavy artillery fire. 
We are told that on his body was found a diary. On the flyleaf under the heading, "My Pledge," he had written these words: "America must win this war. Therefore, I will work, I will save, I will sacrifice, I will endure, I will fight cheerfully and do my utmost, as if the issue of the whole struggle depended on me alone." 
The crisis we are facing today does not require of us the kind of sacrifice that Martin Treptow and so many thousands of others were called upon to make. "It does require, however, our best effort and our willingness to believe in ourselves and to believe in our capacity to perform great deeds, to believe that together with God's help we can and will resolve the problems which now confront us. And after all, why shouldn't we believe that? We are Americans.</quote><quote id="95" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">You and I, as individuals, can, by borrowing, live beyond our means, but for only a limited period of time. Why, then, should we think that collectively, as a nation, we're not bound by that same limitation? "We must act today in order to preserve tomorrow."</quote><quote id="96" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Make no mistake, abortion-on-demand is not a right granted by the Constitution. No serious scholar, including one disposed to agree with the Court's result, has argued that the framers of the Constitution intended to create such a right.</quote><quote id="97" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">The decision by the seven-man majority in Roe v. Wade has so far been made to stick. But the Court's decision has by no means settled the debate. Instead, Roe v. Wade has become a continuing prod to the conscience of the nation.</quote><quote id="98" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">We cannot diminish the value of one category of human life &amp;mdash; the unborn &amp;mdash; without diminishing the value of all human life.</quote><quote id="99" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">If you don't know whether a body is alive or dead, you would never bury it. I think this consideration itself should be enough for all of us to insist on protecting the unborn.</quote><quote id="100" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">The real question today is not when human life begins, but, What is the value of human life?</quote><quote id="101" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">The abortionist who reassembles the arms and legs of a tiny baby to make sure all its parts have been torn from its mother's body can hardly doubt whether it is a human being. </quote><quote id="102" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Regrettably, we live at a time when some persons do not value all human life. They want to pick and choose which individuals have value. </quote><quote id="103" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">As a nation, we must choose between the sanctity of life ethic and the "quality of life" ethic. I have no trouble identifying the answer our nation has always given to this basic question, and the answer that I hope and pray it will give in the future. </quote><quote id="104" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">As a nation today, we have not rejected the sanctity of human life. The American people have not had an opportunity to express their view on the sanctity of human life in the unborn. I am convinced that Americans do not want to play God with the value of human life. It is not for us to decide who is worthy to live and who is not. Even the Supreme Court's opinion in Roe v. Wade did not explicitly reject the traditional American idea of intrinsic worth and value in all human life; it simply dodged this issue.</quote><quote id="105" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">We must all educate ourselves to the reality of the horrors taking place. Doctors today know that unborn children can feel a touch within the womb and that they respond to pain. </quote><quote id="106" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Late-term abortions, especially when the baby survives, but is then killed by starvation, neglect, or suffocation, show once again the link between abortion and infanticide. The time to stop both is now. </quote><quote id="107" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">It is possible that the Supreme Court itself may overturn its abortion rulings. We need only recall that in Brown v. Board of Education the court reversed its own earlier "separate-but-equal" decision. </quote><quote id="108" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">As we continue to work to overturn Roe v. Wade, we must also continue to lay the groundwork for a society in which abortion is not the accepted answer to unwanted pregnancy. Pro-life people have already taken heroic steps, often at great personal sacrifice, to provide for unwed mothers.</quote><quote id="109" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">We will never recognize the true value of our own lives until we affirm the value in the life of others.</quote><quote id="110" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">We cannot survive as a free nation when some men decide that others are not fit to live and should be abandoned to abortion or infanticide. My Administration is dedicated to the preservation of America as a free land, and there is no cause more important for preserving that freedom than affirming the transcendent right to life of all human beings, the right without which no other rights have any meaning.</quote><quote id="111" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">I've spoken recently of the freedom fighters of Nicaragua. You know the truth about them. You know who they're fighting and why. They are the moral equal of our Founding Fathers and the brave men and women of the French Resistance. We cannot turn away from them, for the struggle here is not right versus left; it is right versus wrong.</quote><quote id="112" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"I have only one thing to say to the tax increasers: Go ahead, make my day."</quote><quote id="113" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">I intend to go right on appointing highly qualified individuals of the highest personal integrity to the bench, individuals who understand the danger of short-circuiting the electoral process and disenfranchising the people through judicial activism.</quote><quote id="114" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"The future doesn't belong to the fainthearted, it belongs to the brave."</quote><quote id="115" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">We will never forget them, nor the last time we saw them &amp;mdash; this morning, as they prepared for their journey, and waved good-bye, and "slipped the surly bonds of earth" to "touch the face of God." </quote><quote id="116" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Today we have done what we had to do. If necessary, we shall do it again. It gives me no pleasure to say that, and I wish it were otherwise... When our citizens are abused or attacked anywhere in the world on the direct orders of a hostile regime, we will respond so long as I'm in this Oval Office. Self-defense is not only our right; it is our duty. ... Despite our repeated warnings, Qadhafi continued his reckless policy of intimidation, his relentless pursuit of terror. He counted on America to be passive. He counted wrong.</quote><quote id="117" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"I have never given a litmus test to anyone that I have appointed to the bench.... I feel very strongly about those social issues, but I also place my confidence in the fact that the one thing that I do seek are judges that will interpret the law and not write the law." We've had too many examples in recent years of courts and judges legislating. They're not interpreting what the law says and whether someone has violated it or not. In too many instances, they have been actually legislating by legal decree what they think the law should be, and that I don't go for. And I think that the two men that we're just talking about here, Rehnquist and Scalia, are interpreters of the Constitution and the law.</quote><quote id="118" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Too much SALT isn’t good for you. </quote><quote id="119" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Government's view of the economy could be summed up in a few short phrases: If it moves, tax it. If it keeps moving, regulate it. And if it stops moving, subsidize it.</quote><quote id="120" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">The other day, someone told me the difference between a democracy and a people's democracy. It's the same difference between a jacket and a straitjacket. </quote><quote id="121" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">The charge has been made that the United States has shipped weapons to Iran as ransom payment for the release of American hostages in Lebanon, that the United States undercut its allies and secretly violated American policy against trafficking with terrorists....  Those charges are utterly false....  We did not — repeat — did not trade weapons or anything else for hostages, nor will we.</quote><quote id="122" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">The simple truth is, 'I don't remember — period.'</quote><quote id="123" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"A few months ago I told the American people I did not trade arms for hostages. My heart and my best intentions still tell me that's true, but the facts and the evidence tell me it is not."</quote><quote id="124" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">General Secretary Gorbachev, if you seek peace, if you seek prosperity for the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe, if you seek liberalization: Come here to this gate! Mr. Gorbachev, open this gate! "Mr. Gorbachev, tear down this wall!"</quote><quote id="125" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">It's reported that John Adams' last words were, "Thomas Jefferson survives." History tells us, however, that Jefferson had died shortly before John Adams passed away. But Adams was right. All of us stand in tribute to the truth of those words. We proclaim it again and again with our dedication to keeping this a land of liberty and justice for all, and through our deeds and actions, to ensure that this country remains a bastion of freedom, the last best hope for mankind. "As long as a love of liberty is emblazoned on our hearts, Jefferson lives."</quote><quote id="126" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"If a tax hike makes it to my desk, I'll veto it in less time than it takes Vanna White to turn the letters V-E-T-O!"</quote><quote id="127" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Cannot swords be turned to plowshares? Can we and all nations not live in peace? In our obsession with antagonisms of the moment, we often forget how much unites all the members of humanity." Perhaps we need some outside, universal threat to make us recognize this common bond. I occasionally think how quickly our differences worldwide would vanish if we were facing an alien threat from outside this world. And yet, "I ask you, is not an alien force already among us? What could be more alien to the universal aspirations of our peoples than war and the threat of war?"</quote><quote id="128" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Diplomacy, of course, is a subtle and nuanced craft", so much so that it's said that when the most wily diplomat of the nineteenth-century passed away, other diplomats asked, on reports of his death, "What do you suppose the old fox meant by that?"</quote><quote id="129" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">How do you tell a Communist? Well, it's someone who reads Marx and Lenin. And how do you tell an anti-Communist? It's someone who "understands" Marx and Lenin.</quote><quote id="130" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Freedom is the right to question and change the established way of doing things." It is the continuous revolution of the marketplace. It is the understanding that allows to recognize shortcomings and seek solutions.</quote><quote id="131" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"The nine most terrifying words in the English language are "I'm from the government, and I'm here to help.""</quote><quote id="132" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"The ten most dangerous words in the English language are "Hi,I'm from the government, and I'm here to help.""</quote><quote id="133" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Blood that has soaked into the sands of a beach is all of one color. America stands unique in the world: the only country not founded on race but on a way, an ideal. "Not in spite of but because of our polyglot background, we have had all the strength in the world. That is the American way."</quote><quote id="134" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Facts are stupid things &amp;mdash; "stubborn" things, I should say." [Laughter]</quote><quote id="135" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Americans "[…]Are not going to tolerate intimidation, terror and outright acts of war against this nation and its people. "And we are especially not going to tolerate these attacks from outlaw states run by the strangest collection of misfits, Looney Tunes and squalid criminals since the advent of the Third Reich" […] There can be no place on earth where it is safe for these monsters to rest,or train or practice their cruel and deadly. We must act together – or unilateraly, if necessary – to ensue that these terrorists have no sanctuary, anywhere."</quote><quote id="136" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"I hope we once again have reminded people that man is not free unless government is limited." There's a clear cause and effect here that is as neat and predictable as a law of physics: As government expands, liberty contracts.</quote><quote id="137" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">I won a nickname, "The Great Communicator." But I never thought it was my style or the words I used that made a difference: It was the content. I wasn't a great communicator, but I communicated great things, and they didn't spring full bloom from my brow, they came from the heart of a great nation — from our experience, our wisdom, and our belief in principles that have guided us for two centuries. They called it the Reagan revolution. Well, I'll accept that, but for me it always seemed more like the great rediscovery, a rediscovery of our values and our common sense.</quote><quote id="138" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">The lesson of all this was, of course, that because we're a great nation, our challenges seem complex. It will always be this way. But as long as we remember our first principles and believe in ourselves, the future will always be ours. And something else we learned: "Once you begin a great movement, there's no telling where it will end. We meant to change a nation, and instead, we changed a world."</quote><quote id="139" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">""We the people" tell the government what to do, it doesn't tell us." "We the people" are the driver, the government is the car. And we decide where it should go, and by what route, and how fast. Almost all the world's constitutions are documents in which governments tell the people what their privileges are. Our Constitution is a document in which "We the people" tell the government what it is allowed to do. "We the people" are free.</quote><quote id="140" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">I've spoken of the shining city all my political life, but I don't know if I ever quite communicated what I saw when I said it. But in my mind it was a tall proud city built on rocks stronger than oceans, wind-swept, God-blessed, and teeming with people of all kinds living in harmony and peace, a city with free ports that hummed with commerce and creativity, and if there had to be city walls, the walls had doors and the doors were open to anyone with the will and the heart to get here. That's how I saw it and see it still.</quote><quote id="141" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Whatever else history may say about me when I’m gone, I hope it will record that I appealed to your best hopes, not your worst fears; to your confidence rather than your doubts." My dream is that you will travel the road ahead with liberty’s lamp guiding your steps and opportunity’s arm steadying your way.</quote><quote id="142" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">We've done our part. And as I walk off into the city streets, a final word to the men and women of the Reagan revolution, the men and women across America who for eight years did the work that brought America back. My friends: We did it. We weren't just marking time. We made a difference. We made the city stronger. We made the city freer, and we left her in good hands. All in all, not bad, not bad at all. And so, good-bye, God bless you, and God bless the United States of America.</quote><quote id="143" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Information is the oxygen of the modern age. It seeps through the walls topped by barbed wire, it wafts across the electrified borders. ... The Goliath of totalitarianism will be brought down by the David of the microchip."</quote><quote id="144" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">We have found, in our country, that when people have the right to make decisions as close to home as possible, they usually make the right decisions.</quote><quote id="145" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Although I held public office for a total of sixteen years, I also thought of myself as a citizen-politician, not a career one." Every now and then when I was in government, I would remind my associates that "When we start thinking of government as 'us' instead of 'them,' we've been here too long." By that I mean that elected officeholders need to retain a certain skepticism about the perfectibility of government.</quote><quote id="146" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"I know in my heart that man is good. That what is right will always eventually triumph. And there's purpose and worth to each and every life."</quote><quote id="147" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">When you see all that rhetorical smoke billowing up from the Democrats, well ladies and gentleman, I'd follow the example of their nominee; don't inhale. </quote><quote id="148" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"Well I've said it before and I'll say it again &amp;mdash; America's best days are yet to come. Our proudest moments are yet to be. Our most glorious achievements are just ahead."</quote><quote id="149" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">This fellow they've nominated claims he's the new Thomas Jefferson. Well let me tell you something; I knew Thomas Jefferson. He was a friend of mine and Governor... You're no Thomas Jefferson!" </quote><quote id="150" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">However, our task is far from over. Our friends in the other party will never forgive us for our success, and are doing everything in their power to rewrite history. Listening to the liberals, you'd think that the 1980's were the worst period since the Great Depression, filled with suffering and despair. I don't know about you, but I'm getting awfully tired of the whining voices from the White House these days. They're claiming there was a decade of greed and neglect, but you and I know better than that. We were there.</quote><quote id="151" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">In closing, let me thank you, the American people, for giving me the great honor of allowing me to serve as your president. When the Lord calls me home, whenever that day may be, I will leave with the greatest love for this country of ours and eternal optimism for its future. "I now begin the journey that will lead me into the sunset of my life. I know that for America there will always be a bright dawn ahead. Thank you, my friends. May God always bless you."</quote><quote id="152" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">It's true hard work never killed anyone, but I figure, why take the chance?</quote><quote id="153" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">I'm not smart enough to lie.</quote><quote id="154" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">Liberals fought poverty and poverty won.</quote><quote id="155" author="Ronald Reagan" cats="2000s deaths|American actors|American politicians|Californians|Political leaders|United States Presidents" ref="">"The person who agrees with you 80 percent of the time is a friend and an ally — "not" a 20 percent traitor."</quote></quotes>