<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="el|en|nl|pt|ru|de|tr|it|sk|eu|pl|uk|sl|cs|es"><quote id="0" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">"Both are torn halves of an integral freedom, to which however they do not add up."</quote><quote id="1" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">Fear and destructiveness are the major emotional sources of fascism, "eros" belongs mainly to democracy.</quote><quote id="2" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">"Writing poetry after Auschwitz is barbaric."</quote><quote id="3" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">"When I made my theoretical model, I could not have guessed that people would try to realise it with Molotov cocktails."</quote><quote id="4" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">In general they are intoxicated by the fame of mass culture, a fame which the latter knows how to manipulate; they could just as well get together in clubs for worshipping film stars or for collecting autographs. What is important to them is the sense of belonging as such, identification, without paying particular attention to its content. As girls, they have trained themselves to faint upon hearing the voice of a 'crooner'. Their applause, cued in by a light-signal, is transmitted directly on the popular radio programmes they are permitted to attend. They call themselves 'jitter-bugs', bugs which carry out reflex movements, performers of their own ecstasy. Merely to be carried away by anything at all, to have something of their own, compensates for their impoverished and barren existence. The gesture of adolescence, which raves for this or that on one day with the ever-present possibility of damning it as idiocy on the next, is now socialized.</quote><quote id="5" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">Jazz is the false liquidation of art — instead of utopia becoming reality it disappears from the picture.</quote><quote id="6" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">The aim of jazz is the mechanical reproduction of a regressive moment, a castration symbolism. 'Give up your masculinity, let yourself be castrated,' the eunuchlike sound of the jazz band both mocks and proclaims, 'and you will be rewarded, accepted into a fraternity which shares the mystery of impotence with you, a mystery revealed at the moment of the initiation rite.</quote><quote id="7" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">If one is to take Lulu's twelve-tone chord as the integral totality of complementary harmony, then Berg's allegorical genius proves itself within a historical perspective which makes the brain reel: just as Lulu in the world of total illusion longs for nothing but her murderer and finally finds him in that sound, so does all harmony of unrequited happiness long for its fatal chord as the cipher of fulfillment — twelve-tone music is not to be separated from dissonance. Fatal: because all dynamics come to a standstill within it wihout finding release. The law of complementary harmony already implies the end of the musical experience of time, as this was heralded in the dissociation of time according to Expressionistic extremes.</quote><quote id="8" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">Advancing bourgeois society liquidates memory, time, recollection as irrational leftovers of the past.</quote><quote id="9" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">Immer von Beckett ist eine technische Reduktion bis zum äußersten. ... Aber diese Reduktion ist ja wirklich das was die Welt aus uns macht ... das heißt die Welt aus uns gemacht diese Stümpfe von Menschen also diese Menschen die eigentlich ihr ich ihr verloren haben die sind wirklich die Produkte der Welt in der wir leben.</quote><quote id="10" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">"Bourgeois society is ruled by equivalence. It makes the dissimilar comparable by reducing it to abstract quantities. To the enlightenment, that which does not reduce to numbers, and ultimately to the one, becomes illusion."</quote><quote id="11" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">"The blessing that the market does not ask about birth is paid for in the exchange society by the fact that the possibilities conferred by birth are molded to fit the production of goods that can be bought on the market."</quote><quote id="12" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">The metaphysical apologia at least betrayed the injustice of the established order through the incongruence of concept and reality. The impartiality of scientific language deprived what was powerless of the strength to make itself heard and merely provided the existing order with a neutral sign for itself. Such neutrality is more metaphysical than metaphysics."</quote><quote id="13" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">Furchtbares hat die Menschheit sich antun müssen, bis das Selbst, der identische, zweckgerichtete, männliche Charakter des Menschen geschaffen war, und etwas davon wird noch in jeder Kindheit wiederholt.</quote><quote id="14" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">Die traurige Wissenschaft, aus der ich meinem Freunde einiges darbiete, bezieht sich auf einen Bereich, der für undenkliche Zeiten als der eigentliche der Philosophie galt, seit deren Verwandlung in Methode aber der intellektuellen Nichtachtung, der sententiösen Willkür und am Ende der Vergessenheit verfiel: die Lehre vom richtigen Leben. Was einmal den Philosophen Leben hieß, ist zur Sphäre des Privaten und dann bloß noch des Konsums geworden, die als Anhang des materiellen Produktionsprozesses, ohne Autonomie und ohne eigene Substanz, mit geschleift wird.</quote><quote id="15" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">Für Marcel Proust.—Der Sohn wohlhabender Eltern, der, gleichgültig ob aus Talent oder Schwäche, einen sogenannten intellektuellen Beruf, als Künstler oder Gelehrter, ergreift, hat es unter denen, die den degoutanten Namen des Kollegen tragen, besonders schwer. Nicht bloß, daß ihm die Unabhängigkeit geneidet wird, daß man dem Ernst seiner Absicht mißtraut und in ihm einen heimlichen Abgesandten der etablierten Mächte vermutet. Solches Mißtrauen zeugt zwar von Ressentiment, würde aber meist seine Bestätigung finden. Jedoch die eigentlichen Widerstände liegen anderswo. Die Beschäftigung mit geistigen Dingen ist mittlerweile selber »praktisch«, zu einem Geschäft mit strenger Arbeitsteilung, mit Branchen und numerus clausus geworden. Der materiell Unabhängige, der sie aus Widerwillen gegen die Schmach des Geldverdienens wählt, wird nicht geneigt sein, das anzuerkennen. Dafür wird er bestraft. Er ist kein »professional«, rangiert in der Hierarchie der Konkurrenten als Dilettant, gleichgültig wieviel er sachlich versteht, und muß, wenn er Karriere machen will, den stursten Fachmann an entschlossener Borniertheit womöglich noch übertrumpfen. Die Suspension der Arbeitsteilung, zu der es ihn treibt, und die in einigen Grenzen seine ökonomische Lage zu verwirklichen ihn befähigt, gilt als besonders anrüchig: sie verrät die Abneigung, den von der Gesellschaft anbefohlenen Betrieb zu sanktionieren, und die auftrumpfende Kompetenz läßt solche Idiosynkrasien nicht zu. Die Departementalisierung des Geistes ist ein Mittel, diesen dort abzuschaffen, wo er nicht ex officio, im Auftrag betrieben wird. Es tut seine Dienste um so zuverlässiger, als stets derjenige, der die Arbeitsteilung kündigt—wäre es auch nur, indem seine Arbeit ihm Lust bereitet —, nach deren eigenem Maß Blößen sich gibt, die von den Momenten seiner Überlegenheit untrennbar sind. So ist für die Ordnung gesorgt: die einen müssen mitmachen, weil sie sonst nicht leben können, und die sonst leben könnten, werden draußen gehalten, weil sie nicht mitmachen wollen. Es ist, als rächte sich die Klasse, von der die unabhängigen Intellektuellen desertiert sind, indem zwangshaft ihre Forderungen dort sich durchsetzen, wo der Deserteur Zuflucht sucht.</quote><quote id="16" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">The bourgeois ... is tolerant. His love for people as they are stems from his hatred of what they might be.</quote><quote id="17" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">Die Glorifizierung der prächtigen underdogs läuft auf die des prächtigen Systems heraus, das sie dazu macht.</quote><quote id="18" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">Das Zentrum der geistigen Selbstdisziplin als solcher ist in Zersetzung begriffen. Die Tabus, die den geistigen Rang eines Menschen ausmachen, oftmals sedimentierte Erfahrungen und unartikulierte Erkenntnisse, richten sich stets gegen eigene Regungen, die er verdammen lernte, die aber so stark sind, daß nur eine fraglose und unbefragte Instanz ihnen Einhalt gebieten kann. Was fürs Triebleben gilt, gilt fürs geistige nicht minder: der Maler und Komponist, der diese und jene Farbenzusammenstellung oder Akkordverbindung als kitschig sich untersagt, der Schriftsteller, dem sprachliche Konfigurationen als banal oder pedantisch auf die Nerven gehen, reagiert so heftig gegen sie, weil in ihm selber Schichten sind, die es dorthin lockt. Die Absage ans herrschende Unwesen der Kultur setzt voraus, daß man an diesem selber genug teilhat, um es gleichsam in den eigenen Fingern zucken zu fühlen, daß man aber zugleich aus dieser Teilhabe Kräfte zog, sie zu kündigen. Diese Kräfte, die als solche des individuellen Widerstands in Erscheinung treten, sind darum doch keineswegs selber bloß individueller Art. Das intellektuelle Gewissen, in dem sie sich zusammenfassen, hat ein gesellschaftliches Moment so gut wie das moralische Überich. Es bildet sich an einer Vorstellung von der richtigen Gesellschaft und deren Bürgern. Läßt einmal diese Vorstellung nach—und wer könnte noch blind vertrauend ihr sich überlassen—, so verliert der intellektuelle Drang nach unten seine Hemmung, und aller Unrat, den die barbarische Kultur im Individuum zurückgelassen hat, Halbbildung, sich Gehenlassen, plumpe Vertraulichkeit, Ungeschliffenheit, kommt zum Vorschein. Meist rationalisiert es sich auch noch als Humanität, als den Willen, anderen Menschen sich verständlich zu machen, als welterfahrene Verantwortlichkeit. Aber das Opfer der intellektuellen Selbstdisziplin fällt dem, der es auf sich nimmt, viel zu leicht, als daß man ihm glauben dürfte, daß es eines ist.</quote><quote id="19" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">Marriage as a community of interests unfailingly means the degradation of the interested parties, and it is the perfidy of the world's arrangements that no one, even if aware of it, can escape such degradation. The idea might therefore be entertained that marriage without ignominy is a possibility reserved for those spared the pursuit of interests, for the rich. But the possibility is purely formal, for the privileged are precisely those in whom the pursuit of interests has become second-nature—they would not otherwise uphold privilege.</quote><quote id="20" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">"Wrong life cannot be lived rightly."</quote><quote id="21" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">"Tenderness between people is nothing other than awareness of the possibility of relations without purpose."</quote><quote id="22" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">The straight line is regarded as the shortest distance between two people, as if they were points.</quote><quote id="23" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">The almost insoluble task is to let neither the power of others, nor our own powerlessness, stupefy us.</quote><quote id="24" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">All the world's not a stage.</quote><quote id="25" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">Art is magic delivered from the lie of being truth.</quote><quote id="26" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">The importance of the culture industry in the spiritual constitution of the masses is no dispensation for reflection on its objective legitimation, its essential being, least of all by a science which thinks itself pragmatic.</quote><quote id="27" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">The phrase, the world wants to be deceived, has become truer than had ever been intended.  People are not only, as the saying goes, falling for the swindle; if it guarantees them even the most fleeting gratification they desire a deception which is nonetheless transparent to them.  They force their eyes shut and voice approval, in a kind of self-loathing, for what is meted out to them, knowing fully the purpose for which it is manufactured. "Without admitting it they sense that their lives would be completely intolerable as soon as they no longer clung to satisfactions which are none at all."</quote><quote id="28" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">"The power of the culture industry's ideology is such that conformity has replaced consciousness." The order that springs from it is never confronted with what it claims to be or with the real interests of human beings. "Order, however, is not good in itself." It would be so only as a good order. The fact that the culture industry is oblivious to this and extols order "in abstracto", bears witness to the impotence and untruth of the messages it conveys. While it claims to lead the perplexed, it deludes them with false conflicts which they are to exchange for their own. It solves conflicts for them only in appearance, in a way that they can hardly be solved in their real lives.</quote><quote id="29" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">In the products of the culture industry human beings get into trouble only so that they can be rescued unharmed, usually by representatives of a benevolent collective; and then, in illusory harmony, they are reconciled with the general interest whose demands they had initially experienced as irreconcilable with their own.</quote><quote id="30" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">[http://www.gseis.ucla.edu/faculty/kellner/illumina%20Folder/ador.htm Illuminations - The Critical Theory Project]</quote><quote id="31" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">[http://popcultures.com/Theorists/9/theodor-adorno: Theodor Adorno profile at popcultures.com]</quote><quote id="32" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">[http://www.othervoices.org/cubowman/siren.html "Odysseus and the Siren Call of Reason : The Frankfurt School Critique of Enlightenment" in "Other Voices", n.1 v.1, (1997)]</quote><quote id="33" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">[http://www.logosjournal.com/habermas.htm "Adorno during the 1950s" by Juergen Habermas]</quote><quote id="34" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">[http://www.mahlerarchives.net/archives/goldsmithadorno.pdf "Context, Theme, and Tone in Adorno’s Writings about Mahler and His Music," in "Naturlaut", by Melissa Ursula Dawn Goldsmith]</quote><quote id="35" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">[http://www.marxists.org/reference/archive/adorno/index.htm The Adorno Reference Archive at Marxists.org]</quote><quote id="36" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">[http://www.efn.org/~dredmond/ndtrans.html "Negative Dialectics" at efn.org]</quote><quote id="37" author="Theodor Adorno" cats="1960s deaths|Critical theory|Germans|Philosophers|Socialists" ref="">[http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=7948579 Gravesite]</quote></quotes>