<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="en|it"><quote id="0" author="William Wallace" cats="14th century deaths|Military leaders|Scots" ref="">""Pro Libertate""</quote><quote id="1" author="William Wallace" cats="14th century deaths|Military leaders|Scots" ref="">"We come here with no peaceful intent, but ready for battle, determined to avenge our wrongs and set our country free." Let your masters come and attack us: we are ready to meet them beard to beard.</quote><quote id="2" author="William Wallace" cats="14th century deaths|Military leaders|Scots" ref="">I have brought you to the ring, now dance if you can.</quote><quote id="3" author="William Wallace" cats="14th century deaths|Military leaders|Scots" ref="">"I can not be a traitor, for I owe him no allegiance. He is not my Sovereign; he never received my homage; and whilst life is in this persecuted body, he never shall receive it." To the other points whereof I am accused, I freely confess them all. As Governor of my country I have been an enemy to its enemies; I have slain the English; I have mortally opposed the English King; I have stormed and taken the towns and castles which he unjustly claimed as his own. "If I or my soldiers have plundered or done injury to the houses or ministers of religion, I repent me of my sin; but it is not of Edward of England I shall ask pardon."</quote><quote id="4" author="William Wallace" cats="14th century deaths|Military leaders|Scots" ref="">"Dico Tibi Verum, Libertas Optima Rerum: Nunquam Servili Sub Nexu Vivito, Fili"</quote><quote id="5" author="William Wallace" cats="14th century deaths|Military leaders|Scots" ref="">"For sooth, ere he decease, 
Shall many thousands in the field make end." 
From Scotland he shall forth the Southron send, 
And Scotland thrice he shall bring to peace. 
So good of hand again shall ne'er be kenned.</quote><quote id="6" author="William Wallace" cats="14th century deaths|Military leaders|Scots" ref="">First, here I honour, in particular,
Sir William Wallace, much renown'd in war,
Whose bold progenitors have long time stood,
Of honourable and true Scottish blood.</quote><quote id="7" author="William Wallace" cats="14th century deaths|Military leaders|Scots" ref="">"The whole followers of the nobility had attached themselves to him"; and that although the persons of their lords were with the King of England, their heart was with Wallace, who found his army reinforced by so immense a multitude of the Scots, that the community of the land obeyed him as their leader and their prince.</quote><quote id="8" author="William Wallace" cats="14th century deaths|Military leaders|Scots" ref="">Every man dies. Not every man really lives.</quote><quote id="9" author="William Wallace" cats="14th century deaths|Military leaders|Scots" ref="">[http://www.bbc.co.uk/history/scottishhistory/independence/features_independence_wallace2.shtml Brief biography at BBC]</quote><quote id="10" author="William Wallace" cats="14th century deaths|Military leaders|Scots" ref="">[http://members.tripod.com/bob_newcumnock/wallace_home/wallace1297.html The Wallace Years 1297-1305]</quote></quotes>