<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><quotes languages="el|en|zh|af|ca|it|cs|ar|eu|et|gl|id|es|ru|az|nl|nn|no|tr|lt|th|ro|is|pl|be|fr|bg|uk|hr|de|da|fa|br|bs|fi|hy|hu|ja|he|ka|te|pt|sr|ko|sv|sk|ku|sl"><quote id="0" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Every influence, every motive, that provokes the spirit of murder among men, impels these mountaineers to deeds of treachery and violence. The strong aboriginal propensity to kill, inherent in all human beings, has in these valleys been preserved in unexampled strength and vigour. That religion, which above all others was founded and propagated by the sword — the tenets and principles of which are instinct with incentives to slaughter and which in three continents has produced fighting breeds of men — stimulates a wild and merciless fanaticism. The love of plunder, always a characteristic of hill tribes, is fostered by the spectacle of opulence and luxury which, to their eyes, the cities and plains of the south display. A code of honour not less punctilious than that of old Spain, is supported by vendettas as implacable as those of Corsica.</quote><quote id="1" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"I pass with relief from the tossing sea of Cause and Theory to the firm ground of Result and Fact."</quote><quote id="2" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">It is better to be making the news than taking it; to be an actor rather than a critic.</quote><quote id="3" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Nothing in life is so exhilarating as to be shot at without result."</quote><quote id="4" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">How dreadful are the curses which Mohammedanism lays on its votaries! Besides the fanatical frenzy, which is as dangerous in a man as hydrophobia in a dog, there is this fearful fatalistic apathy. The effects are apparent in many countries. Improvident habits, slovenly systems of agriculture, sluggish methods of commerce, and insecurity of property exist wherever the followers of the Prophet rule or live. A degraded sensualism deprives this life of its grace and refinement; the next of its dignity and sanctity. The fact that in Mohammedan law every woman must belong to some man as his absolute property, either as a child, a wife, or a concubine, must delay the final extinction of slavery until the faith of Islam has ceased to be a great power among men.&lt;br /&gt;Individual Moslems may show splendid qualities. Thousands become the brave and loyal soldiers of the Queen; all know how to die; but the influence of the religion paralyses the social development of those who follow it. No stronger retrograde force exists in the world. Far from being moribund, Mohammedanism is a militant and proselytizing faith. It has already spread throughout Central Africa, raising fearless warriors at every step; "and were it not that Christianity is sheltered in the strong arms of science, the science against which it had vainly struggled, the civilisation of modern Europe might fall, as fell the civilisation of ancient Rome."</quote><quote id="5" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">It is the habit of the boa constrictor to besmear the body of his victim with a foul slime before he devours it; and there are many people in England, and perhaps elsewhere, who seem to be unable to contemplate military operations for clear political objects, unless they can cajole themselves into the belief that their enemy are utterly and hopelessly vile. To this end the Dervishes, from the Mahdi and the Khalifa downwards, have been loaded with every variety of abuse and charged with all conceivable crimes. This may be very comforting to philanthropic persons at home; but when an army in the field becomes imbued with the idea that the enemy are vermin who cumber the earth, instances of barbarity may easily be the outcome. This unmeasured condemnation is moreover as unjust as it is dangerous and unnecessary.</quote><quote id="6" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">What is the true and original root of Dutch aversion to British rule? It is the abiding fear and hatred of the movement that seeks to place the native on a level with the white man ... the Kaffir is to be declared the brother of the European, to be constituted his legal equal, to be armed with political rights.</quote><quote id="7" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">In former days, when wars arose from individual causes, from the policy of a Minister or the passion of a King, when they were fought by small regular armies of professional soldiers, and when their course was retarded by the difficulties of communication and supply, and often suspended by the winter season, it was possible to limit the liabilities of the combatants. But now, when mighty populations are impelled on each other, each individual severally embittered and inflamed—when the resources of science and civilisation sweep away everything that might mitigate their fury, a European war can only end in the ruin of the vanquished and the scarcely less fatal commercial dislocation and exhaustion of the conquerors. Democracy is more vindictive than Cabinets. "The wars of peoples will be more terrible than those of kings."</quote><quote id="8" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The ability to foretell what is going to happen tomorrow, next week, next month, and next year – and to have the ability afterwards to explain why it didn’t happen.</quote><quote id="9" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Will the shutting out of foreign goods increase the total amount of wealth in this country? Can foreign nations grow rich at our expense by selling us goods under cost price? Can a people tax themselves into prosperity? Can a man stand in a bucket and lift himself up by the handle?</quote><quote id="10" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Politics are almost as exciting as war, and – quite as dangerous ... [I]n war, you can only be killed once. But in politics many times.</quote><quote id="11" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">For my own part I have always felt that a politician is to be judged by the animosities which he excites among his opponents. I have always set myself not merely to relish but to deserve thoroughly their censure. </quote><quote id="12" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The conditions of the Transvaal ordinance under which Chinese Labour is now being carried on do not, in my opinion, constitute a state of slavery. A labour contract into which men enter voluntarily for a limited and for a brief period, under which they are paid wages which they consider adequate, under which they are not bought or sold and from which they can obtain relief on payment of seventeen pounds ten shillings, the cost of their passage, may not be a healthy or proper contract, but it cannot in the opinion of His Majesty's Government be classified as slavery in the extreme acceptance of the word without some risk of terminological inexactitude.</quote><quote id="13" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"The Times" is speechless, and takes three columns to express its speechlessness.</quote><quote id="14" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"What is the use of living, if it be not to strive for noble causes and to make this muddled world a better place for those who will live in it after we are gone?" How else can we put ourselves in harmonious relation with the great verities and consolations of the infinite and the eternal? And I avow my faith that we are marching towards better days. Humanity will not be cast down. "We are going on swinging bravely forward along the grand high road and already behind the distant mountains is the promise of the sun."</quote><quote id="15" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The unnatural and increasingly rapid growth of the feeble-minded and insane classes, coupled as it is with steady restriction among all the thrifty, energetic and superior stocks constitutes a national and race danger which is impossible to exaggerate. I feel that the source from which the stream of madness is fed should be cut off and sealed before another year has passed.</quote><quote id="16" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">'I propose that 100,000 degenerate Britons should be forcibly sterilized and others put in labour camps to halt the decline of the British race.'</quote><quote id="17" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Everything tends towards catastrophe and collapse. I am interested, geared up and happy. Is it not horrible to be made like this?</quote><quote id="18" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Like chasing a quinine pill around a cow pasture.</quote><quote id="19" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I am finished.</quote><quote id="20" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">[The] "truth is incontrovertible. Panic may resent it, ignorance may deride it, malice may distort it, but there it is."</quote><quote id="21" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I think a curse should rest on me — because I love this war. I know it's smashing and shattering the lives of thousands every moment — and yet — I can't help it — I enjoy every second of it.</quote><quote id="22" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">No compromise on the main purpose; no peace till victory; no pact with unrepentant wrong -- that is the Declaration of July 4th, 1918. </quote><quote id="23" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The Great War differed from all ancient wars in the immense power of the combatants and their fearful agencies of destruction, and from all modern wars in the utter ruthlessness with which it was fought. ... Europe and large parts of Asia and Africa became one vast battlefield on which after years of struggle not armies but nations broke and ran. When all was over, Torture and Cannibalism were the only two expedients that the civilized, scientific, Christian States had been able to deny themselves: and they were of doubtful utility.</quote><quote id="24" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I do not understand this squeamishness about the use of gas. We have definitely adopted the position at the Peace Conference of arguing in favour of the retention of gas as a permanent method of warfare. "It is sheer affectation to lacerate a man with the poisonous fragment of a bursting shell and to boggle at making his eyes water by means of lachrymatory gas. I am strongly in favour of using poisoned gas against uncivilised tribes." The moral effect should be so good that the loss of life should be reduced to a minimum. It is not necessary to use only the most deadly gases: gases can be used which cause great inconvenience and would spread a lively terror and yet would leave no serious permanent effects on most of those affected" ... We cannot, in any circumstances acquiesce to the non-utilisation of any weapons which are available to procure a speedy termination of the disorder which prevails on the frontier.</quote><quote id="25" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">: Many argue that quotes from this passage are often taken out of context, because Churchill is distinguishing between non-lethal agents and the deadly gasses used in World War I and emphasizing the use of non-lethal weapons; however Churchill is not clearly ruling out the use of lethal gases, simply stating that "it is not necessary to use only the most deadly". It is sometimes claimed that gas killed many young and elderly Kurds and Arabs when the RAF bombed rebelling villages in Iraq in 1920 during the British occupation. For more information on this matter, see Gas in Mesopotamia.</quote><quote id="26" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Lenin was sent into Russia by the Germans in the same way that you might send a phial containing a culture of typhoid or cholera to be poured into the water supply of a great city, and it worked with amazing accuracy."</quote><quote id="27" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">First there are the Jews who, dwelling in every country throughout the world, identify themselves with that country, enter into its national life and, while adhering faithfully to their own religion, regard themselves as citizens in the fullest sense of the State which has received them. Such a Jew living in England would say, 'I am an English man practising the Jewish faith.' This is a worthy conception, and useful in the highest degree. We in Great Britain well know that during the great struggle the influence of what may be called the 'National Jews' in many lands was cast preponderatingly on the side of the Allies; and in our own Army Jewish soldiers have played a most distinguished part, some rising to the command of armies, others winning the Victoria Cross for valour.&lt;p&gt;There is no need to exaggerate the part played in the creation of Bolshevism and in the actual bringing about of the Russian Revolution, by these international and for the most part atheistical Jews, it is certainly a very great one; it probably outweighs all others. With the notable exception of Lenin, the majority of the leading figures are Jews. Moreover, the principal inspiration and driving power comes from the Jewish leaders. Thus Tchitcherin, a pure Russian, is eclipsed by his nominal subordinate Litvinoff, and the influence of Russians like Bukharin or Lunacharski cannot be compared with the power of Trotsky, or of Zinovieff, the Dictator of the Red Citadel (Petrograd) or of Krassin or Radek -- all Jews. In the Soviet institutions the predominance of Jews is even more astonishing. And the prominent, if not indeed the principal, part in the system of terrorism applied by the Extraordinary Commissions for Combating Counter-Revolution has been taken by Jews, and in some notable cases by Jewesses. The same evil prominence was obtained by Jews in the brief period of terror during which Bela Kun ruled in Hungary. The same phenomenon has been presented in Germany (especially in Bavaria), so far as this madness has been allowed to prey upon the temporary prostration of the German people. Although in all these countries there are many non-Jews every whit as bad as the worst of the Jewish revolutionaries, the part played by the latter in proportion to their numbers in the population is astonishing.</quote><quote id="28" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">: (A note: Churchill viewed Bolshevism as a heavily Jewish phenomenon.  He contrasted the Jewish role in the creation of Bolshevism with a more positive view of the role that Jews had played in England.){{citation needed}}</quote><quote id="29" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">However we may dwell upon the difficulties of General Dyer during the Amritsar riots, upon the anxious and critical situation in the Punjab, upon the danger to Europeans throughout that province, ... one tremendous fact stands out – I mean the slaughter of nearly 400 persons and the wounding of probably three to four times as many, at the Jallian Wallah Bagh on 13th April. That is an episode which appears to me to be without precedent or parallel in the modern history of the British Empire. ... "It is an extraordinary event, a monstrous event, an event which stands in singular and sinister isolation."</quote><quote id="30" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I yield to no one in my detestation of Bolshevism, and of the revolutionary violence which precedes it. ... But my hatred of Bolshevism and Bolsheviks is not founded on their silly system of economics, or their absurd doctrine of an impossible equality. It arises from the bloody and devastating terrorism which they practice in every land into which they have broken, and by which alone their criminal regime can be maintained. ... Governments who have seized upon power by violence and by usurpation have often resorted to terrorism in their desperate efforts to keep what they have stolen, but the august and venerable structure of the British Empire ... does not need such aid. Such ideas are absolutely foreign to the British way of doing things.</quote><quote id="31" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Let me marshal the facts. "The crowd was unarmed, except with bludgeons. It was not attacking anybody or anything. It was holding a seditious meeting. When fire had been opened upon it to disperse it, it tried to run away. Pinned up in a narrow place considerably smaller than Trafalgar Square, with hardly any exits, and packed together so that one bullet would drive through three or four bodies, the people ran madly this way and the other. When the fire was directed upon the centre, they ran to the sides. The fire was then directed to the sides. Many threw themselves down on the ground, and the fire was then directed on the ground. This was continued for 8 or 10 minutes ..." [i]f the road had not been so narrow, the machine guns and the armoured cars would have joined in. Finally, when the ammunition had reached the point that only enough remained to allow for the safe return of the troops, and after 379 persons ... had been killed, and when most certainly 1,200 or more had been wounded, the troops, at whom not even a stone had been thrown, swung round and marched away. ... We have to make it absolutely clear ... that this is not the British way of doing business. ... Our reign, in India or anywhere else, has never stood on the basis of physical force alone, and it would be fatal to the British Empire if we were to try to base ourselves only upon it.</quote><quote id="32" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I cannot pretend to feel impartial about the colours. I rejoice with the brilliant ones, and am genuinely sorry for the poor browns.</quote><quote id="33" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Every day you may make progress. Every step may be fruitful. Yet there will stretch out before you an ever-lengthening, ever-ascending, ever-improving path. You know you will never get to the end of the journey. But this, so far from discouraging, only adds to the joy and the glory of the climb.</quote><quote id="34" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I am most anxious that in dealing with matters which every Member knows are extremely delicate matters, I should not use any phrase or expression which would cause offence to our friends and Allies on the Continent or across the Atlantic Ocean.</quote><quote id="35" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The choice was clearly open: crush them with vain and unstinted force, or try to give them what they want. These were the only alternatives, and though each had ardent advocates, most people were unprepared for either. Here indeed was the Irish spectre – horrid and inexorcisable. </quote><quote id="36" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">No hour of life is lost that is spent in the saddle.</quote><quote id="37" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Too often the strong, silent man is silent only because he does not know what to say, and is reputed strong only because he has remained silent.</quote><quote id="38" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I decline utterly to be impartial as between the fire brigade and the fire.</quote><quote id="39" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Make your minds perfectly clear that if ever you let loose upon us again a general strike, we will loose upon you &amp;ndash; another "British Gazette."</quote><quote id="40" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">If I had been an Italian, I am sure I would have been entirely with you from the beginning to the end of your victorious struggle against the bestial appetites and passions of Leninism.</quote><quote id="41" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">A sheep in sheep's clothing.</quote><quote id="42" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">To improve is to change, so to be perfect is to have changed often.</quote><quote id="43" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">She shone for me like the Evening Star. I loved her dearly — but at a distance.</quote><quote id="44" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Where my reason, imagination or interest were not engaged, I would not or I could not learn.</quote><quote id="45" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Thus I got into my bones the essential structure of the ordinary British sentence, which is a noble thing.</quote><quote id="46" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Headmasters have powers at their disposal with which Prime Ministers have never yet been invested.</quote><quote id="47" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I then had one of the three or four long intimate conversations with him which are all I can boast.</quote><quote id="48" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">In retrospect these years form not only the least agreeable, but the only barren and unhappy period of my life. I was happy as a child with my toys in my nursery. I have been happier every year since I became a man. But this interlude of school makes a sombre grey patch upon the chart of my journey. It was an unending spell of worries that did not then seem petty, of toil uncheered by fruition; a time of discomfort, restriction and purposeless monotony. This train of thought must not lead me to exaggerate the character of my school days ... Harrow was a very good school ... Most of the boys were very happy ... I can only record the fact that, no doubt through my own shortcomings, I was an exception. ... I was on the whole considerably discouraged ... All my contemporaries and even younger boys seemed in every way better adapted to the conditions of our little world. They were far better both at the games and at the lessons. It is not pleasant to feel oneself so completely outclassed and left behind at the very beginning of the race. </quote><quote id="49" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Certainly the prolonged education indispensable to the progress of Society is not natural to mankind. It cuts against the grain. A boy would like to follow his father in pursuit of food or prey. He would like to be doing serviceable things so far as his utmost strength allowed. He would like to be earning wages however small to help to keep up the home. He would like to have some leisure of his own to use or misuse as he pleased. He would ask little more than the right to work or starve. And then perhaps in the evenings a real love of learning would come to those who are worthy – and why try to stuff in those who are not? – and knowledge and thought would open the ‘magic casements’ of the mind.</quote><quote id="50" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I had a feeling once about Mathematics, that I saw it all—Depth beyond depth was revealed to me—the Byss and the Abyss. I saw, as one might see the transit of Venus—or even the Lord Mayor's Show, a quantity passing through infinity and changing its sign from plus to minus. I saw exactly how it happened and why the tergiversation was inevitable: and how the one step involved all the others. It was like politics. But it was after dinner and I let it go! </quote><quote id="51" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Although always prepared for martyrdom, I preferred that it should be postponed.</quote><quote id="52" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">You will make all kinds of mistakes; but as long as you are generous and true, and also fierce, you cannot hurt the world or even seriously distress her.</quote><quote id="53" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I wonder whether any other generation has seen such astounding revolutions of data and values as those through which we have lived. Scarcely anything material or established which I was brought up to believe was permanent and vital, has lasted. Everything I was sure or taught to be sure was impossible, has happened.</quote><quote id="54" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I have no doubt that the Romans planned the time-table of their days far better than we do. They rose before the sun at all seasons. Except in wartime we never see the dawn. Sometimes we see sunset. The message of sunset is sadness; the message of dawn is hope. The rest and the spell of sleep in the middle of the day refresh the human frame far more than a long night. We were not made by Nature to work, or even play, from eight o’clock in the morning till midnight. We throw a strain upon our system which is unfair and improvident. For every purpose of business or pleasure, mental or physical, we ought to break our days and our marches into two.</quote><quote id="55" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I do think unpunctuality is a vile habit, and all my life I have tried to break myself of it.</quote><quote id="56" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I now began for the first time to envy those young cubs at the university who had fine scholars to tell them what was what; professors who had devoted their lives to mastering and focusing ideas in every branch of learning; who were eager to distribute the treasures they had gathered before they were overtaken by the night. But now I pity undergraduates, when I see what frivolous lives many of them lead in the midst of precious fleeting opportunity. After all, a man’s Life must be nailed to a cross either of Thought or Action. Without work there is no play. </quote><quote id="57" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I accumulated in those years so fine a surplus in the Book of Observance that I have been drawing confidently upon it ever since.</quote><quote id="58" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"It is a good thing for an uneducated man to read books of quotations. Bartlett's Familiar Quotations is an admirable work, and I studied it intently. The quotations when engraved upon the memory give you good thoughts. They also make you anxious to read the authors and look for more."</quote><quote id="59" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I had been brought up and trained to have the utmost contempt for people who got drunk – and I would have liked to have the boozing scholars of the Universities wheeled into line and properly chastised for their squalid misuse of what I must ever regard as a gift of the gods. </quote><quote id="60" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Never, never, never believe any war will be smooth and easy, or that anyone who embarks on the strange voyage can measure the tides and hurricanes he will encounter. The statesman who yields to war fever must realise that once the signal is given, he is no longer the master of policy but the slave of unforeseeable and uncontrollable events." Antiquated War Offices, weak, incompetent, or arrogant Commanders, untrustworthy allies, hostile neutrals, malignant Fortune, ugly surprises, awful miscalculations — all take their seats at the Council Board on the morrow of a declaration of war. Always remember, however sure you are that you could easily win, that there would not be a war if the other man did not think he also had a chance.</quote><quote id="61" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I remember, when I was a child, being taken to the celebrated Barnum's circus, which contained an exhibition of freaks and monstrosities. But the exhibit on the programme which I most desired to see was the one described as "The Boneless Wonder." My parents judged that that spectacle would be too revolting and demoralising for my youthful eyes, and I have waited 50 years to see the boneless wonder sitting on the Treasury Bench.</quote><quote id="62" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">India is a geographical term.  It is no more a united nation than the equator.</quote><quote id="63" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">It is alarming and also nauseating to see Mr. Gandhi, a seditious Middle Temple lawyer of the type well-known in the East, now posing as a fakir, striding half naked up the steps of the Viceregal palace to parley on equal terms with the representative of the King-Emperor. </quote><quote id="64" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"We shall escape the absurdity of growing a whole chicken in order to eat the breast or wing, by growing these parts separately under a suitable medium."</quote><quote id="65" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">We are stripped bare by the curse of plenty. </quote><quote id="66" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">We know that he has, more than any other man, the gift of compressing the largest number of words into the into the smallest amount of thought.</quote><quote id="67" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">One may dislike Hitler's system and yet admire his patriotic achievement. If our country were defeated, I hope we should find a champion as indomitable to restore our courage and lead us back to our place among the nations.</quote><quote id="68" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">We cannot tell whether Hitler will be the man who will once again let loose upon the world another war in which civilisation will irretrievably succumb, or whether he will go down in history as the man who restored honour and peace of mind to the Great Germanic nation.</quote><quote id="69" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Mr. Gandhi has gone very high in my esteem since he stood up for the untouchables" ... I do not care whether you are more or less loyal to Great Britain ... Tell Mr. Gandhi to use the powers that are offered and make the thing a success. </quote><quote id="70" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"The world looks with some awe upon a man who appears unconcernedly indifferent to home, money, comfort, rank, or even power and fame. The world feels not without a certain apprehension, that here is some one outside its jurisdiction; someone before whom its allurements may be spread in vain; some one strangely enfranchised, untamed, untrammelled by convention, moving independent of the ordinary currents of human action."</quote><quote id="71" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Occasionally he stumbled over the truth, but hastily picked himself up and hurried on as if nothing had happened.</quote><quote id="72" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Anyone can see what the position is. The Government simply cannot make up their mind, or they cannot get the Prime Minister to make up his mind. "So they go on in strange paradox, decided only to be undecided, resolved to be irresolute, adamant for drift, solid for fluidity, all powerful to be impotent." So we go on preparing more months and years – precious, perhaps vital to the greatness of Britian – for the locusts to eat.</quote><quote id="73" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"The era of procrastination, of half-measures, of soothing and baffling expedients, of delays, is coming to its close. In its place we are entering a period of consequences."</quote><quote id="74" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Courage is rightly esteemed the first of human qualities, because, as has been said, 'it is the quality which guarantees all others.'</quote><quote id="75" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The essence and foundation of House of Commons debating is formal conversation. The set speech, the harangue addressed to constituents, or to the wider public out of doors, has never succeeded much in our small wisely-built chamber. To do any good you have got to get down to grips with the subject and in human touch with the audience.</quote><quote id="76" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"I do not agree that the dog in a manger has the final right to the manger even though he may have lain there for a very long time. I do not admit that right." I do not admit for instance, that a great wrong has been done to the Red Indians of America or the black people of Australia. I do not admit that a wrong has been done to these people by the fact that a stronger race, a higher-grade race, a more worldly wise race to put it that way, has come in and taken their place.</quote><quote id="77" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Dictators ride to and fro on tigers from which they dare not dismount. And the tigers are getting hungry."</quote><quote id="78" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">For five years I have talked to the House on these matters – not with very great success. I have watched this famous island descending incontinently, fecklessly, the stairway which leads to a dark gulf. It is a fine broad stairway at the beginning, but after a bit the carpet ends. A little farther on there are only flagstones, and a little farther on still these break beneath your feet. [ ... ] Look back upon the last five years – since, that is to say, Germany began to rearm in earnest and openly to seek revenge ... historians a thousand years hence will still be baffled by the mystery of our affairs. They will never understand how it was that a victorious nation, with everything in hand, suffered themselves to be brought low, and to cast away all that they had gained by measureless sacrifice and absolute victory – gone with the wind! Now the victors are the vanquished, and those who threw down their arms in the field and sued for an armistice are striding on to world mastery. That is the position – that is the terrible transformation that has taken place bit by bit.</quote><quote id="79" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">[O]ur loyal, brave people ... should know the truth. ... they should know that we have sustained a defeat without a war, ... and that the terrible words have for the time being been pronounced against the Western democracies; ‘Thou art weighed in the balance and found wanting.’ And do not suppose that this is the end. This is only the beginning of the reckoning. This is only the first sip, the first foretaste of a bitter cup which will be proferred to us year by year unless by a supreme recovery of moral health and martial vigour, we arise again and take our stand for freedom as in the olden time.</quote><quote id="80" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"The stations of uncensored expression are closing down; the lights are going out; but there is still time for those to whom freedom and parliamentary government mean something, to consult together. Let me, then, speak in truth and earnestness while time remains."</quote><quote id="81" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"People say we ought not to allow ourselves to be drawn into a theoretical antagonism between Nazidom and democracy; but the antagonism is here now." It is this very conflict of spiritual and moral ideas which gives the free countries a great part of their strength. "You see these dictators on their pedestals, surrounded by the bayonets of their soldiers and the truncheons of their police." On all sides they are guarded by masses of armed men, cannons, aeroplanes, fortifications, and the like — they boast and vaunt themselves before the world, yet in their hearts there is unspoken fear. "They are afraid of words and thoughts; words spoken abroad, thoughts stirring at home — all the more powerful because forbidden — terrify them. A little mouse of thought appears in the room, and even the mightiest potentates are thrown into panic. They make frantic efforts to bar our thoughts and words; they are afraid of the workings of the human mind." Cannons, airplanes, they can manufacture in large quantities; but how are they to quell the natural promptings of human nature, which after all these centuries of trial and progress has inherited a whole armoury of potent and indestructible knowledge?</quote><quote id="82" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I have always said that if Great Britain were defeated in war I hoped we should find a Hitler to lead us back to our rightful position among the nations. I am sorry, however, that he has not been mellowed by the great success that has attended him. The whole world would rejoice to see the Hitler of peace and tolerance, and nothing would adorn his name in world history so much as acts of magnanimity and of mercy and of pity to the forlorn and friendless, to the weak and poor. ... Let this great man search his own heart and conscience before he accuses anyone of being a warmonger.</quote><quote id="83" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Britain and France had to choose between war and dishonour. They chose dishonour. They will have war." </quote><quote id="84" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"I cannot forecast to you the action of Russia. It is a riddle wrapped in a mystery inside an enigma": but perhaps there is a key. That key is Russian national interest.</quote><quote id="85" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"First, Poland has been again overrun by two of the great powers which held her in bondage for 150 years but were unable to quench the spirit of the Polish nation. The heroic defense of Warsaw shows that the soul of Poland is indestructible, and that she will rise again like a rock which may for a spell be submerged by a tidal wave but which remains a rock."</quote><quote id="86" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I would say to the House, as I said to those who have joined this Government:" 'I have nothing to offer but blood, toil, tears, and sweat.' "We have before us an ordeal of the most grievous kind. We have before us many, many long months of struggle and of suffering. "You ask, what is our policy? I will say: It is to wage war, by sea, land and air, with all our might and with all the strength that God can give us: to wage war against a monstrous tyranny, never surpassed in the dark, lamentable catalogue of human crime. That is our policy. You ask, what is our aim? I can answer in one word: It is victory, victory at all costs, victory in spite of all terror, victory, however long and hard the road may be; for without victory, there is no survival."</quote><quote id="87" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Side by side ... the British and French peoples have advanced  to rescue ... mankind from the foulest and most soul-destroying tyranny which has ever darkened and stained the pages of history. Behind them ... gather a group of shattered States and bludgeoned races: the Czechs, the Poles, the Norwegians, the Danes, the Dutch, the Belgians -- upon all of whom the long night of barbarism will descend, unbroken even by a star of hope, "unless we conquer, as conquer we must; as conquer we shall."</quote><quote id="88" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Every morn brought forth a noble chance, and every chance brought forth a noble knight. </quote><quote id="89" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"We shall not flag or fail. We shall go on to the end, we shall fight in France, we shall fight on the seas and oceans, we shall fight with growing confidence and growing strength in the air, "we shall defend our Island, whatever the cost may be, we shall fight on the beaches, we shall fight on the landing grounds, we shall fight in the fields and in the streets, we shall fight in the hills; we shall never surrender", and even if, which I do not for a moment believe, this Island or a large part of it were subjugated and starving, then our Empire beyond the seas, armed and guarded by the British Fleet, would carry on the struggle, until, in God's good time, the New World, with all its power and might, steps forth to the rescue and the liberation of the Old."</quote><quote id="90" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Bearing ourselves humbly before God ... we await undismayed the impending assault ... "be the ordeal sharp or long, or both, we shall seek no terms, we shall tolerate no parlay; we may show mercy – we shall ask for none."</quote><quote id="91" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Of this I am quite sure, that "if we open a quarrel between the past and the present, we shall find that we have lost the future."</quote><quote id="92" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Upon this battle depends the survival of Christian civilisation. Upon it depends our own British life and the long continuity of our institutions and our Empire. The whole fury and might of the enemy must very soon be turned on us now. Hitler knows that he will have to break us in this island or lose the war. If we can stand up to him, all Europe may be free and the life of the world may move forward into broad, sunlit uplands. But if we fail, then the whole world, including the United States, including all that we have known and cared for, will sink into the abyss of a new Dark Age, made more sinister, and perhaps more protracted, by the lights of perverted science. "Let us therefore brace ourselves to our duties, and so bear ourselves that, if the British Empire and its Commonwealth last for a thousand years, men will still say, 'This was their finest hour.' "</quote><quote id="93" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The gratitude of every home in our Island, in our Empire, and indeed throughout the world, except in the abodes of the guilty, goes out to the British airmen who, undaunted by odds, unwearied in their constant challenge and mortal danger, are turning the tide of the World War by their prowess and by their devotion. "Never in the field of human conflict was so much owed by so many to so few." All hearts go out to the fighter pilots, whose brilliant actions we see with our own eyes day after day; but we must never forget that all the time, night after night, month after month, our bomber squadrons travel far into Germany, find their targets in the darkness by the highest navigational skill, aim their attacks, often under the heaviest fire, often with serious loss, with deliberate careful discrimination, and inflict shattering blows upon the whole of the technical and war-making structure of the Nazi power.</quote><quote id="94" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"We are waiting for the long-promised invasion. So are the fishes."</quote><quote id="95" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Goodnight then: sleep to gather strength for the morning. For the morning will come. Brightly will it shine on the brave and true, kindly upon all who suffer for the cause, glorious upon the tombs of heroes. Thus will shine the dawn. Vive la France! Long live also the forward march of the common people in all the lands towards their just and true inheritance, and towards the broader and fuller age.</quote><quote id="96" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">These cruel, wanton, indiscriminate bombings of London are, of course, a part of Hitler’s invasion plans. He hopes, by killing large numbers of civilians, and women and children, that he will terrorise and cow the people of this mighty imperial city ... Little does he know the spirit of the British nation, or the tough fibre of the Londoners.</quote><quote id="97" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The hour has come; kill the Hun.</quote><quote id="98" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Here is the answer which I will give to President Roosevelt: Put your confidence in us. ... "We shall not fail or falter; we shall not weaken or tire. Neither the sudden shock of battle, nor the long-drawn trials of vigilance and exertion will wear us down. Give us the tools and we will finish the job."</quote><quote id="99" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I must point out ... that "the British nation is unique in this respect. They are the only people who like to be told how bad things are, who like to be told the worst, " and like to be told that they are very likely to get much worse in the future and must prepare themselves for further reverses.</quote><quote id="100" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"If Hitler invaded Hell, I would make at least a favourable reference to the devil in the House of Commons."</quote><quote id="101" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Hitler is a monster of wickedness, insatiable in his lust for blood and plunder. Not content with having all Europe under his heel, or else terrorised into various forms of abject submission, he must now carry his work of butchery and desolation among the vast multitudes of Russia and of Asia. The terrible military machine - which we and the rest of the civilised world so foolishly, so supinely, so insensately allowed the Nazi gangsters to build up year by year from almost nothing - cannot stand idle lest it rust or fall to pieces. ... So now this bloodthirsty guttersnipe must launch his mechanized armies upon new fields of slaughter, pillage and devastation.</quote><quote id="102" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">We ask no favours of the enemy. We seek from them no compunction. On the contrary, if tonight the people of London were asked to cast their votes as to whether a convention should be entered into to stop the bombing of all cities, an overwhelming majority would cry, "No, we will mete out to the Germans the measure, and more than the measure, they have meted out to us." {applause} The people of London with one voice would say to Hitler: "You have committed every crime under the sun. Where you have been the least resisted there you have been the most brutal. It was you who began the indiscriminate bombing. We remember Warsaw! In the first few days of the war. We remember Rotterdam. We have been newly reminded of your habits by the hideous massacre in Belgrade. We know too well the bestial assaults you're making upon the Russian people, to whom our hearts go out in their valiant struggle! {cheers}  We will have no truce or parley with you, or the grisly gang who work your wicked will! You do your worst! - and we will do our best! {sustained cheering} Perhaps it may be our turn soon. Perhaps it may be our turn now."</quote><quote id="103" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Never give in — never, never, never, never, in nothing great or small, large or petty, never give in except to convictions of honour and good sense." Never yield to force; never yield to the apparently overwhelming might of the enemy.</quote><quote id="104" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">We have not journeyed all this way across the centuries, across the oceans, across the mountains, across the prairies, because we are made of sugar candy.</quote><quote id="105" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">It is not given to us to peer into the mysteries of the future. Still, I avow my hope and faith, sure and inviolate, that in the days to come the British and American peoples will for their own safety and for the good of all walk together side by side in majesty, in justice, and in peace.</quote><quote id="106" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">When I warned them that Britain would fight on alone whatever they did, their generals told their Prime Minister and his divided Cabinet, "In three weeks England will have her neck wrung like a chicken."" Some chicken! Some neck!"</quote><quote id="107" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"The most dangerous moment of the War, and the one which caused me the greatest alarm", was when the Japanese Fleet was heading for Ceylon and the naval base there. The capture of Ceylon, the consequent control of the Indian Ocean, and the possibility at the same time of a German conquest of Egypt would have closed the ring and the future would have been black.</quote><quote id="108" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">It was an experience of great interest to me to meet Premier Stalin ... It is very fortunate for Russia in her agony to have this great rugged war chief at her head. He is a man of massive outstanding personality, suited to the sombre and stormy times in which his life has been cast; a man of inexhaustible courage and will-power and a man direct and even blunt in speech, which, having been brought up in the House of Commons, I do not mind at all, especially when I have something to say of my own. Above all, he is a man with that saving sense of humour which is of high importance to all men and all nations, but particularly to great men and great nations. Stalin also left upon me the impression of a deep, cool wisdom and a complete absence of illusions of any kind. I believe I made him feel that we were good and faithful comrades in this war – but that, after all, is a matter which deeds not words will prove.  </quote><quote id="109" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"I hate Indians. They are a beastly people with a beastly religion".</quote><quote id="110" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Now this is not the end. It is not even the beginning of the end. But it is, perhaps, the end of the beginning."</quote><quote id="111" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The problems of victory are more agreeable than those of defeat, but they are no less difficult.</quote><quote id="112" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I have not become the King’s First Minister in order to preside over the liquidation of the British Empire.</quote><quote id="113" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Before Alamein we never had a victory. After Alamein, we never had a defeat.</quote><quote id="114" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The maxim "‘Nothing avails but perfection’" may be spelt shorter: "‘Paralysis.’"</quote><quote id="115" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I am sure it would be sensible to restrict as much as possible the work of these gentlemen, who are capable of doing an immense amount of harm with what may very easily degenerate into charlatanry. The tightest hand should be kept over them, and they should not be allowed to quarter themselves in large numbers among Fighting Services at the public expense.</quote><quote id="116" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">There is no finer investment for any community than putting milk into babies.</quote><quote id="117" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">By its sudden collapse, ... the proud German army has once again proved the truth of the saying, 'The Hun is always either at your throat or at your feet'.</quote><quote id="118" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"The empires of the future are the empires of the mind."</quote><quote id="119" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I have nothing to add to the reply which has already been sent.</quote><quote id="120" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I hate nobody except Hitler — and that is professional.</quote><quote id="121" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"We shape our buildings, and afterwards our buildings shape us."</quote><quote id="122" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The essence of good House of Commons speaking is the conversational style, the facility for quick, informal interruptions and interchanges. Harangues from a rostrum would be a bad substitute for the conversational style in which so much of our business is done. But the conversational style requires a fairly small space, and there should be on great occasions a sense of crowd and urgency. There should be a sense of the importance of much that is said and a sense that great matters are being decided, there and then, by the House. ... It has a collective personality which enjoys the regard of the public, and which imposes itself upon the conduct not only of  individual Members but of parties.</quote><quote id="123" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The House of Commons has lifted our affairs above the mechanical sphere into the human sphere. It thrives on criticism, it is perfectly impervious to newspaper abuse or taunts from any quarter, and it is capable of digesting almost anything or almost any body of gentlemen, whatever be the views with which they arrive. There is no situation to which it cannot address itself with vigour and ingenuity. It is the citadel of British liberty; it is the foundation of our laws; its traditions and its privileges are as lively today it broke the arbitrary power of the Crown and substituted that Constitutional Monarchy under which we have enjoyed so many blessings.</quote><quote id="124" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">You might however consider whether you should not unfold as a background the great privilege of "habeas corpus" and trial by jury, which are the supreme protection invented by the English people for ordinary individuals against the state. "The power of the Executive to cast a man in prison without formulating any charge known to the law, and particularly to deny him the judgment of his peers is in the highest degree odious and is the foundation of all totalitarian government, whether Nazi or Communist."</quote><quote id="125" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The object of presenting medals, stars, and ribbons is to give pride and pleasure to those who have deserved them. At the same time a distinction is something which everybody does not possess. If all have it it is of less value ... A medal glitters, but it also casts a shadow.  </quote><quote id="126" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I have left the obvious, essential fact to this point, namely, that "it is the Russian Armies who have done the main work in tearing the guts out of the German army." In the air and on the oceans we could maintain our place, but there was no force in the world which could have been called into being, except after several more years, that would have been able to maul and break the German army unless it had been subjected to the terrible slaughter and manhandling that has fallen to it through the strength of the Russian Soviet Armies.</quote><quote id="127" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">A love of tradition has never weakened a nation, indeed it has strengthened nations in their hour of peril; but the new view must come, the world must roll forward ... Let us have no fear of the future.</quote><quote id="128" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"It seems to me that the moment has come when the question of bombing of German cities simply for the sake of increasing the terror, though under other pretexts, should be reviewed."</quote><quote id="129" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">It is a mistake to look too far ahead. Only one link in the chain of destiny can be handled at a time.</quote><quote id="130" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"To achieve the extirpation of Nazi tyranny there are no lengths of violence to which we will not go."</quote><quote id="131" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"The Russians will sweep through your country and your people will be liquidated. You are on the verge of annihiliation."</quote><quote id="132" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"The inherent vice of capitalism is the unequal sharing of blessings. The inherent virtue of Socialism is the equal sharing of miseries."</quote><quote id="133" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Meeting Roosevelt was like uncorking your first bottle of champagne." </quote><quote id="134" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The very first thing the President did was to show me the new Presidential Seal, which he had just redesigned. He explained, 'The seal has to go everywhere the President goes. It must be displayed upon the lectern when he speaks. The eagle used to face the arrows but I have re-designed it so that it now faces the olive branches ... what do you think?' I said, 'Mr. President, with the greatest respect, I would prefer the American eagle's neck to be on a swivel so that it could face the olive branches or the arrows, as the occasion might demand.'</quote><quote id="135" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">When I was a young subaltern in the South African War, the water was not fit to drink. To make it palatable we had to put a bit of whiskey in it. By diligent effort I learned to like it.</quote><quote id="136" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">A shadow has fallen upon the scenes so lately lighted by the Allied victory…. "From Stettin in the Baltic to Trieste in the Adriatic an iron curtain has descended across the Continent."</quote><quote id="137" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"We must build a kind of United States of Europe."</quote><quote id="138" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"We must all turn our backs upon the horrors of the past. We must look to the future. We cannot afford to drag forward cross the years that are to come the hatreds and revenges which have sprung from the injuries of the past. "</quote><quote id="139" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Is there any need for further floods of agony? Is the only lesson of history to be that mankind is unteachable? Let there be justice, mercy and freedom. The people have only to will it, and all will achieve their hearts' desire.</quote><quote id="140" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"The salvation of the common people of every race and of every land from war or servitude" must be established on solid foundations and "must be guarded by the readiness of all men and women to die rather than submit to tyranny."</quote><quote id="141" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">There is less there than meets the eye.</quote><quote id="142" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I gather, young man, that you wish to be a Member of Parliament. "The first lesson that you must learn is that, when I call for statistics about the rate of infant mortality, what I want is proof that fewer babies died when I was Prime Minister than when anyone else was Prime Minister. That is a political statistic. "</quote><quote id="143" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">When I am abroad I always make it a rule never to criticize or attack the Government of my country. I make up for lost time when I am at home.</quote><quote id="144" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"When I was younger I made it a rule never to take strong drink before lunch. It is now my rule never to do so before breakfast."</quote><quote id="145" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">All the greatest things are simple, and many can be expressed in a single word: Freedom; Justice; Honour; Duty; Mercy; Hope.</quote><quote id="146" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Many forms of Government have been tried and will be tried in this world of sin and woe. No one pretends that democracy is perfect or all-wise. Indeed, it has been said that democracy is the worst form of government except all those other forms that have been tried from time to time."</quote><quote id="147" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Socialism is the philosophy of failure, the creed of ignorance and the gospel of envy."</quote><quote id="148" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">For my part, I consider that it will be found much better by all Parties to leave the past to history, especially as I propose to write that history.</quote><quote id="149" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"In War: Resolution. In Defeat: Defiance. In Victory: Magnanimity. In Peace: Good Will."</quote><quote id="150" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">One day President Roosevelt told me that he was asking publicly for suggestions about what the war should be called. I said at once 'The Unnecessary War'.</quote><quote id="151" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Their horse cavalry, of which they had twelve brigades, charged valiantly against the swarming tanks and armoured cars but could not harm them with their swords and lances.</quote><quote id="152" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I felt as if I were walking with destiny, and that all my past life had been but a preparation for this hour and for this trial.</quote><quote id="153" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Those who are prone, by temperament and character, to seek sharp and clear-cut solutions of difficult and obscure problems, who are ready to fight whenever some challenge comes from a foreign power, have not always been right. On the other hand, those whose inclination is to bow their heads, to seek patiently and faithfully for peaceful compromise, are not always wrong. On the contrary, in the majority of instances they may be right, not only morally, but from a practical standpoint. "How many wars have been averted by patience and persisting good will!" Religion and virtue alike lend their sanctions to meekness and humility, not only between men but between nations. "How many wars have been precipitated by firebrands! How many misunderstandings which led to wars could have been removed by temporizing! How often have countries fought cruel wars and then after a few years found themselves not only friends but allies!"</quote><quote id="154" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Still, if you will not fight for the right when you can easily win without bloodshed; if you will not fight when your victory will be sure and not too costly; you may come to the moment when you will have to fight with all the odds against you and only a precarious chance of survival. There may even be a worse case. You may have to fight when there is no hope of victory, because it is better to perish than to live as slaves.</quote><quote id="155" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Baldwin, Stanley ... confesses putting party before country, 169-70; ...</quote><quote id="156" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"Broadly speaking, short words are best, and the old words, when short, are best of all." </quote><quote id="157" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The reason for having diplomatic relations is not to confer a compliment, but to secure a convenience. </quote><quote id="158" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">When I look back on all these worries I remember the story of the old man who said on his deathbed that he had had a lot of trouble in his life, most of which had never happened.</quote><quote id="159" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">War is mainly a catalogue of blunders.</quote><quote id="160" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">No American will think it wrong of me if I proclaim that to have the United States at our side was to me the greatest joy. I could not foretell the course of events. I do not pretend to have measured accurately the martial might of Japan, but now at this very moment I knew the United States was in the war, up to the neck and in to the death. So we had won after all! ... Hitler's fate was sealed. Mussolini's fate was sealed. As for the Japanese, they would be ground to powder.</quote><quote id="161" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Some people did not like this ceremonious style. But after all "when you have to kill a man it costs nothing to be polite."</quote><quote id="162" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">It excites world wonder in the Parliamentary countries that we should build a Chamber, starting afresh, which can only seat two-thirds of its Members. It is difficult to explain this to those who do not know our ways. They cannot easily be made to understand why we consider that the intensity, passion, intimacy, informality and spontaneity of our Debates constitute the personality of the House of Commons and endow it at once with its focus and its strength.</quote><quote id="163" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I am reminded of the professor who, in his declining hours, was asked by his devoted pupils for his final counsel. He replied, "Verify your quotations."</quote><quote id="164" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Let me have the best solution worked out. Don’t argue the matter. The difficulties will argue for themselves.</quote><quote id="165" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">There are two main characteristics of the House of Commons which will command the approval and the support of reflective and experienced Members. The first is that its shape should be oblong and not semicircular. Here is a very potent factor in our political life. The semicircular assembly, which appeals to political theorists, enables every individual or every group to move round the centre, adopting various shades of pink according as the weather changes. I am a convinced supporter of the party system in preference to the group system. I have seen many earnest and ardent Parliaments destroyed by the group system. The party system is much favoured by the oblong form of chamber. "It is easy for an individual to move through those insensible gradations from left to right, but the act of crossing the Floor is one which requires serious attention. I am well informed on this matter for I have accomplished that difficult process, not only once, but twice."</quote><quote id="166" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Of course, when you are winning a war almost everything that happens can be claimed to be right and wise.</quote><quote id="167" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">‘In war-time,’ I said, ‘truth is so precious she should always be attended by a bodyguard of lies.’</quote><quote id="168" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">A number of social problems arose. I had been told that neither smoking nor alcoholic beverages were allowed in the [Saudi] Royal Presence. As I was the host at luncheon I raised the matter at once, and said to the interpreter that if it was the religion of His Majesty [Ibn Saud] to deprive himself of smoking and alcohol I must point out that my rule of life prescribed as an absolutely sacred rite smoking cigars and also the drinking of alcohol before, after, and if need be during all meals and in the intervals between them. The King graciously accepted the position. His own cup-bearer from Mecca offered me a glass of water from its sacred well, the most delicious I had ever tasted.</quote><quote id="169" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">By noon it was clear that the Socialists would have a majority. At luncheon my wife said to me, 'It may well be a blessing in disguise.' I replied, 'At the moment it seems quite effectively disguised.'</quote><quote id="170" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The Chinese said of themselves several thousand years ago: “China is a sea that salts all the waters that flow into it.” There’s another Chinese saying about their country which is much more modern—it dates only from the fourth century. This is the saying: “The tail of China is large and will not be wagged.” I like that one. The British democracy approves the principles of movable party heads and unwaggable national tails. It is due to the working of these important forces that I have the honour to be addressing you at this moment.</quote><quote id="171" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The object of Parliament is to substitute argument for fisticuffs.</quote><quote id="172" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">But now let me return to my theme of the many changes that have taken place since I was last here. There is a jocular saying: "‘To improve is to change; to be perfect is to have changed often.’" I had to use that once or twice in my long career.</quote><quote id="173" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Dogs look up to you, cats look down on you. Give me a pig! He looks you in the eye and treats you as an equal.</quote><quote id="174" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Without tradition, art is a flock of sheep without a shepherd. Without innovation, it is a corpse.</quote><quote id="175" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"To jaw-jaw is always better than to war-war."</quote><quote id="176" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"For myself, I am an optimist — it does not seem to be much use being anything else."</quote><quote id="177" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"An appeaser is one who feeds a crocodile — hoping it will eat him last."</quote><quote id="178" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I have taken more out of alcohol than alcohol has taken out of me.</quote><quote id="179" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">It’s not enough that we do our best; sometimes we have to do what’s required.</quote><quote id="180" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I am a sporting man. I always give them a fair chance to get away.</quote><quote id="181" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">""Keep England White" is a good slogan."</quote><quote id="182" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">This Treasury paper, by its very length, defends itself against the risk of being read.</quote><quote id="183" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I want no criticism of America at my table. The Americans criticize themselves more than enough.</quote><quote id="184" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">We have surmounted all the perils and endured all the agonies of the past. We shall provide against and thus prevail over the dangers and problems of the future, withhold no sacrifice, grudge no toil, seek no sordid gain, fear no foe. All will be well. We have, I believe, within us the life-strength and guiding light by which the tormented world around us may find the harbour of safety, after a storm-beaten voyage.</quote><quote id="185" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"The day may dawn when fair play, love for one's fellow men, respect for justice and freedom, will enable tormented generations to march forth triumphant from the hideous epoch in which we have to dwell. Meanwhile, never flinch, never weary, never despair."</quote><quote id="186" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I think it is the most important subject facing this country, but I cannot get any of my ministers to take any notice.</quote><quote id="187" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">I am ready to meet my Maker. Whether my Maker is prepared for the great ordeal of meeting me is another matter.</quote><quote id="188" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"We are all worms. But I do believe I am a glow-worm."</quote><quote id="189" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Thus ended the great American Civil War, which upon the whole must be considered the noblest and least avoidable of all the great mass conflicts of which till then there was record.</quote><quote id="190" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">No one can understand history without continually relating the long periods which are constantly mentioned to the experiences of our own short lives.  Five years is a lot.  Twenty years is the horizon to most people.  Fifty years is antiquity.  To understand how the impact of destiny fell upon any generation of men one must first imagine their position and then apply the time-scale of our own lives.</quote><quote id="191" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">At this point the march of invention brought a new factor upon the scene.  Iron was dug and forged.  Men armed with iron entered Britain from the Continent and killed the men of bronze.  At this point we can plainly recognise across the vanished millenniums a fellow-being.  A biped capable of slaying another with iron is evidently to modern eyes a man and a brother. </quote><quote id="192" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">We see the crude and corrupt beginnings of a higher civilisation blotted out by the ferocious uprising of the native tribes.  Still, it is the primary right of men to die and kill for the land they live in, and to punish with exceptional severity all members of their own race who have warmed their hands at the invaders' hearth.</quote><quote id="193" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Apparently, as in so many ancient battles, the beaten side were the victims of misunderstanding and the fate of the day was decided against them before the bulk of the forces realised that a serious engagement had begun.  Reserves descended from the hills too late to achieve victory, but in good time to be massacred in the rout.</quote><quote id="194" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Like other systems in decay, the Roman Empire continued to function for several generations after its vitality was sapped.  For nearly a hundred years our Island was one of the scenes of conflict between a dying civilisation and lusty, famishing barbarism.</quote><quote id="195" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">And wherever men are fighting against barbarism, tyranny, and massacre, for freedom, law, and honour, let them remember that the fame of their deeds, even though they themselves be exterminated, may perhaps be celebrated as long as the world rolls round.  Let us then declare that King Arthur and his noble knights, guarding the Sacred Flame of Christianity and the theme of a world order, sustained by valour, physical strength, and good horses and armour, slaughtered innumerable hosts of foul barbarians and set decent folk an example for all time.</quote><quote id="196" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The picture rises  before us vivid and bright: the finely carved, dragon-shaped prow; the high, curving stern; the long row of shields, black and yellow alternately, ranged along the sides; the gleam of steel; the scent of murder.</quote><quote id="197" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">When we reflect upon the brutal vices of these salt-water bandits, pirates as shameful as any whom the sea has borne, or recoil from their villainous destruction and cruel deeds, we must also remember the discipline, the fortitude, the comradeship and martial virtues which made them at this period beyond all challenge the most formidable and daring race in the world.</quote><quote id="198" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">When the next year the raiders returned and landed near Jarrow they were stoutly attacked while harassed by bad weather.  Many were killed.  Their "king" was captured and put to a cruel death, and the fugitives carried so grim a tale back to Denmark that for forty years the English coasts were unravaged.</quote><quote id="199" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">"872, Ivar, King of the Northmen of all Ireland and Britain, ended his life."  He had conquered Mercia and East Anglia. He had captured the major stronghold of the kingdom of Strathclyde, Dumbarton.  Laden with loot and seemingly invincible, he settled in Dublin and died there peacefully two years later.  The pious chroniclers report that he "slept in Christ."  Thus it may be that he had the best of both worlds.</quote><quote id="200" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">A group of pagan ruffians and pirates had gained possession of an effective military and naval machine, but they faced a mass of formidable veterans whom they had to feed and manage, and for whom they must provide killings.  Such men make plans, and certainly their descent upon England was one of the most carefully considered and elaborately prepared villainies of that dark time.</quote><quote id="201" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Without any coherent national organisation to repel from the land on which they had settled the ever-unknowable descents from the seas, the Saxons, now for four centuries entitled to be deemed the owners of the soil, very nearly succumbed completely to the Danish inroads. That they did not was due--as almost every critical turn of historic fortune has been due--to the sudden apparition in an era of confusion and decay of one of the great figures of history.</quote><quote id="202" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">It was Twelfth Night, and the Saxons, who in these days of torment refreshed and fortified themselves by celebrating the feasts of the Church, were off their guard, engaged in pious exercises, or perhaps even drunk.  Down swept the ravaging foe.  The whole army of Wessex, sole guarantee of England south of the Thames, was dashed into confusion.  Many were killed.</quote><quote id="203" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Civilisation had been restored to the Island.  But now the political fabric which nurtured it was about to be overthrown.  Hitherto strong men armed had kept the house. Now a child, a weakling, a vacillator, a faithless, feckless creature, succeeded to the warriour throne. </quote><quote id="204" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">We have seen that Alfred in his day had never hesitated to use money as well as arms.  Ethelred used money instead of arms.  He used it in ever-increasing quantities, with ever-diminishing returns ... There is the record of a final payment to the Vikings in 1012.  This time forty-eight thousand pounds' weight of silver was extracted, and the oppressors enforce the collection by the sack of Canterbury, holding Archbishop Alphege to ransom, and finally killing him at Greenwich because he refused to coerce his flock to raise the money.  The Chronicle states:  "All these calamities fell upon us through evil counsel, because tribute was not offered to them at the right time, nor yet were they resisted; but, when they had done the most evil, then was peace made with them.  And notwithstanding all this peace and tribute they went everywhere in companies, harried our wretched people, and slew them"</quote><quote id="205" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">It is vain to recount further the catalogue of miseries.  In earlier ages such horrors remain unknown because unrecorded.  Just enough flickering light plays upon this infernal scene to give us the sense of its utter desolation and hopeless wretchedness and cruelty.</quote><quote id="206" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">The lights of Saxon England were going out, and in the gathering darkness a gentle, grey-beard prophet foretold the end.  When on his death-bed Edward spoke of a time of evil that was coming upon the land his inspired mutterings struck terror into the hearers.</quote><quote id="207" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">On September 28 the fleet hove in sight, and all came safely to anchor in Pevensey Bay.  There was no opposition to the landing.  The local "fyrd" had been called out this year four times already to watch the coast, and having, in true English style, come to the conclusion that the danger was past because it had not yet arrived had gone back to their homes.</quote><quote id="208" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">w:William I of England|William now directed his archers to shoot high into the air, so that the arrows would fall behind the shield-wall, and one of these pierced w:Harold Godwinson|Harold in the right-eye, inflicting a mortal wound.  He fell at the foot of the royal standard, unconquerable except by death, which does not count in honour.  The hard-fought battle was now decided.</quote><quote id="209" author="Winston Churchill" cats="1960s deaths|British Prime Ministers|English people|Nobel Prize winners" ref="">Joan was a being so uplifted from the ordinary run of mankind that she finds no equal in a thousand years. She embodied the natural goodness and valour of the human race in unexampled perfection. Unconquerable courage, infinite compassion, the virtue of the simple, the wisdom of the just, shone forth in her. She glorifies as she freed the soil from which she sprang.</quote></quotes>